today I'm going to review my makes from twenty nineteen if you like this video and
have an already please don't forget to life and subscribe in case I'm going to cover
three rough sections firstly I'm going to go through my project categories so just I'm key
highlights of mix I've made this year I'm then going to move on to how well
I did on my make nine projects and finally I'm just gonna mention some other key
achievements and lessons learned from the year so instead of mentioning every single project I've made
firstly I haven't kept the very good locks that I can't remember everything I've made I
haven't logged everything online via the blog block or my Instagram feed so which is a
role shame because it means I remember some of the stuff I have made but it's
just all that wiped out this year however I thought I'd mentioned the main highlights and
that stand out for me so I've got with its five categories for this year and
I'll go through those out so the first category is the most challenging make so I've
chosen my main big knitting project for the year it was one of my make line
of just rabbit it is this cardigan that the cop be holding an hour my color
anyway said this is from the listing pattern that my mom's had in her such for
years and she made from one to Dover she's made on the sheer as well she's
made a blue version and yeah it's got this nobly
pattern on it so it's quite fun to make well they we have learned that the
different sizes
depending which sides you need to make it's harder so my mom made a different slides
to me and in the end she probably gonna think the same size she's realized but
anyway so she did a different size but it turns out the increase in decrease it's
a lot harder in that sizing
so yeah but the size that I don't we make is nice to follow it fortunately
and it has taken me pretty much most a year to make a I think the
garment when I finished that it's at some point
in the autumn so I started it in January so it was a very long make
for the I've had the wall for
a number of years but yeah so I'm kind of happy with it it's it's one
of those makes where when you finally finished it and you're just not too sure about
sense which is folly put it like do you have to other cardigan's so I made
a yellow version of this cardigan and quite a few years ago is my first rule
make sail down in that respect it's
it's not a real challenge to me because I have followed the pattern before however it
was a challenge just its black and it's quite hard to see when your listing after
work you know it's it's dark outside seagull reliant on artificial I've taken enter you know
I did have to unravel let quite a number of times I do get a bit
impatient as well so that's why it's probably my greatest challenge this year as well so
to have the patience to keep finishing it throughout all of those months I'm for the
big achievement for me see you I think this is something I don't think I've written
a blog about I haven't blocked about it and I don't think I put the final
bowed again on Instagram that might change that thank you so over I'm happy with it
I love the pockets of work with this and my main ambition is just to make
one in a range of different colors so I could just open and a water open
to see that all lined up together but we'll see because they do take a while
to make the second project category is most fun make and that was an easy one
to select it's the beach towel poncho I really enjoyed making this and it was a
weekend that my mom came down to visit and I knew that she wanted to her
and beach tell been so yeah we just put head together and created us so I'm
as you could to see I'm if you've seen watch the video already we did make
it up as we went along so we started off you know trying to make shift
the herds we ended up tracing around another hood that I'm we had offer and the
day I had lying around but yeah really happy with the under as though I really
want to make myself one now as well on to most useful make the most useful
make is definitely my Debbie short of this bag so I made this I think in
September and it's really even useful already I haven't put it was my most useful make
but actually the office bag was part of the south so I made a little dipper
pouch to go with the office bag which I put them because I have a name
budget work and if they got keys for work so I keep all of my useful
office
have no year and that as though it just means that when I get to work
I'm not like rummaging around in my bag tines of you know find the keys to
let myself him I can just you know straight away find them in there because it's
enlisted about and of course I made to the water water can courier as well which
I use quite a lot both at work and outside of work so yeah the whole
steps being really useful they were a gift made and was a bit of a tricky
one I've decided to go with the last main gift I made for Christmas this year
and it fills bear themed pajamas at and what's going to choose the oven mitts I
made for my sister and her family because that had an interesting sort of should whory
design on it and I did remission quoting on it which to quite a lot of
time and I also made the bias binding from scraps of Roman fabric that I used
to make their aprons last year however what I really liked about films their pajamas is
that I have the confidence to create a little hand embroidered that on the PJ top
I don't of why but I've always been put off at using a plicae or hand
embroidering onto pajama top just because it's made out of the net fabric I'm always worried
that it will somehow distort the fabric or be a lot harder to attach or it
might stretch out of we might get a stretch and look a bit strange and but
obviously because the pajama top is loose fit by design I realized that this was a
bit of a ford argument so what I did was by roughly with my joke pen
sketched out a design which I thought liked roughly like one of the bears on the
printing fabric for the trousers
and then I use chain stitch to stitch all the way around and did a French
not for the I want to my favorite make I do like a lot of the
gifts I made and I got a lot of satisfaction out of making it for other
people but I'm going to choose this year the clear what cycle I made what I
really like about this make is that I made out of two pairs of jeans they
weren't exact matches the the dice and the designs of the two sets of jeans I
think
I've managed to make them work well together the best thing about this make is although
it took absolutely ages to unpick there seems of the genes is probably one of my
most one makes from this year the genes fabric the denim is so substantial it feels
really nice to where I just felt so comfortable in it and yeah it's just nice
to just check it on same leaving on to my many lines from this year so
I chose nine projects I'm according to the make nine challenge and which you can find
more information about on Instagram so out of my nine projects I managed to make four
of them this year which is too bad I think it's
one or two less than I may last year to the ones I did manage to
make where the Molly dress which I enjoy wearing I managed to make the Bibi pitiful
which another one I'm really happy with to the reason that one did get made quite
quickly is because
that was my fabric that I accident me cut out for the wrong project so I
think to make myself feel better about it if you stopped the rest of that fabric
making the baby privacy that Copley called again I showed earlier was one of my make
lines and obviously the one that took the longest time a bit like the Croatia thrown
made last year's for me was the most time and senses and finally I made the
kinda card again which is another one and I really like the design although I guess
the fabric I got for that I'm not as happy with and but still wearing it
so it's so the ones I didn't get round to you I'm included making a to
can teacher so gone old's chief swim see with a nice calamari sequin to come on
it and for some reason I'm help and so on turning it into a t-shirt I
still really want to do this has kind of been the project this been in my
in the back of my head the whole year and by the time I could have
got the guts to start creating it because my main concern and commit kind goes back
to the I'm embroidering the bear on the pajamas I just worry about the I'm stretch
of the net fabric having the two kimono which it's ridiculous I know which is why
do you want to now get on with it so it didn't manage to make that
so it'll probably roll over onto my twenty Fenty make nine because I get for me
want to make it so okay so I also said that I'd make a bag for
other swimming or you get the reason I haven't is because the new the classes I
was going to ended up getting canceled they kind of did restart again but but as
the habit of going to them and with swimming we have a real look at issue
but we go don't always use the look of these things so essentially I wanted to
make a backlot fit really well into the lockers that are provided that I'm a bit
suspicious on whether they might just reconfigure the whole locker space areas I'm not sure I'm
going to get on you cells that however you could say because I did make the
office back I have technically made a similar right in this year and one I knew
I definitely knew said another bag or dimanche make list of vinyl back so this was
actually for a gift and I were going to too much detail now but again I
probably will attempt to make it in twenty twenty instead I had included the art finishing
the throat because I did get the whole set for the asked unknitting although I can't
find a few issues so going to have to make up some of the swells I
did not get around to this because I just spent so much time on the cock
accordion I just think it around to its again I might possibly added to the twenty
twenty list or I might leave it until a future here I would like to get
it done one day the final on it didn't get around to with the same house
seven rich hundred I just yet didn't have time to make it and I don't really
feel an urgent need for us they find me just a brief roundup of other cheapens
and less and black land in twenty nineteen so the best major one is that I
can definitely live off my fabric stash I've avoided fine fabric Fisher just so I could
free up a bit space in my class it hasn't us so we worked out that
way I guess now I tried to feel a bit more comfortable with my fabric stash
this time last year I felt really stressed about it I just felt like it was
a big overwhelming presence and love lets you know we don't have a huge amount of
space in and it just felt like I was overpowering the flat with my crafts however
now I'm kind of a bit more appreciative of it because I've been able to make
so many lovely makes and gets for other people yeah I guess I'm a bit more
at peace with my fabric sash so I'm not as stressed about it now because I've
really benefited from it and Christine work you from my such as you know helped a
bit financially as well because I spent an awful got on my crafts the air and
just on small have a datary items another key achievement has been that I've consistently put
out some videos on YouTube ever since I mused the clear up psyching video area I
think since then I've been consistently posting video so I think I've had at least twenty
videos in a row by now might slightly more that's been a real achievement obviously it's
it's a lot habit for him making sure that you post out regularly on YouTube and
so like have got into a bit of the stories that that which I'm really happy
with another thing that I've learned this year is a list of passing custom so I
went to a couple of local persons on doing a better of passing casting one of
them fakest or creating your own block from scratch and the other one was about adapting
a block to fit in measurements both were really interesting and it's definitely shaped how I
look at dress-making I would actually say I think that's why my productivity went down with
it it was spring summer just because and then felt a bit over one's white how
much I needed to think about when adjusting a person now the lesson I've learned this
year is how to adjust my craft making to how I'm feeling so because of my
chronic ownness I do have what I call crashes and when these happen it's really difficult
to dress make in particular because I don't know it just seems to take a lot
more efforts doing things like letting my hands pressuring and even had embroidery the probably only
one that you know I found really beneficial or even the handsewing bits interest makings you
know feel showing up at him by hands which I quite enjoy I find that these
have been really useful
so I can still feel productive but I'm giving my body time to heal you to
stop attacking itself and then I can't get back on stress making but you know it's
handy to have some other craft that skin you know take the place of dress making
when
my body call cope with up the final point I want to make is that I've
learned I really need a better method of tracking my makes I have not got a
compressive list of what I made this year I know I have made some great things
and I just can't think them in fact I've just remembered that I made and avoid
a tablecloth for my grandparents which was
he is a key make that the fissure siya this is exactly why I need some
sort of method of tracking what I'm making so that's it for my review for this
week the next time I'm going to go through my plans for twenty twenty and also
how I'm going to track those unthankful watching