hello today I'm going to go through my plans for twenty Fenty if you like this
video and have authority please don't forget to life unsubscribe okay so I didn't think this
will be a very long video and but basically I'm going to go through my proposed
make mine list so I'm going to do wind from January through to the end of
December although you can do the challenge at any time you like during the yet I'm
going to go to do some other aims I have to see it and finally I'm
going to explain how I'm going to track my makes the ship if you say to
begin with I think I'll go through my make mine list so I've got a couple
that have carried over from twenty nineteen so the two that have carried over from twenty
nineteen is of course but you can teach at that dimensions in my twenty nineteen review
which was my last video and I've also carried over the argentin through which again is
something I'd really like to get done the main problem may have with the young based
projector's I'm quite a slow Mr and crocheter so I tend to only get one project
done it that I think I've always thought one project on I never I always seem
to put to the on-base project down every year but make line and I only ever
seem to achieve one of them just because I think by the time I finished the
first project I get my start to get to the point more inland making them stuff
for Christmas and then I just never got around to it and I was a seemed
to be quite ambitious and to quite big projects well I say that in twenty eighteen
I put making and its animal Irena's time and I never managed to make that will
they say that I think it's just because you have to do a loop stitch on
it which was the main issue with that project so I needed to really concentrate to
get into that
I needed to really concentrate to work out that stitch and then I kept putting it
down and I'm forgetting where I was so I just need to really sit down and
just make it one thing so other project of got on that I've got a dressing
gown to make this year I'm really want the fabric for it I'm so we did
have to purchase the fabric for this one actually
and yeah that's all ready to be cut up it's all prewashed so I'll probably make
that soonish probably in the next month fingers crossed the other fabric I purchased recently is
for the dungarees I want to make so I'm I think I'm going to use the
Mila dungarees pattern which I got as a Christmas gift or the birthday gift anyway I
got it is a gift last year or about a year ago so I'd like to
make that up at some point and again I'm you need stretched them for that so
I bought it specifically for this project my other young based projects I mentioned that but
the optimising through which have carried over from our sticks I just really want to get
it done and it all saving someone some possit completers I can essentially clear out one
of these acute some McCulloch's but I mean so and I'll have more storage a any
way like I was saying my other your place project is I'm going to make a
short this year and for this one I'm actually quite optimistic and might get both of
my own base projects on the sheer because and have already sorted the shore which is
a very promising sign but we will see I'd really like to make a man's shed
this year mainly because my partner fell he really would like a shop and I've never
made him one before but I'm actually doing a level to award is the city good
qualification and I'm making a woman's share in that at the moment I'm I'll show you
the progress so feretory so please excuse I'm all the creases in a I keep shoving
it about to go to this class but yes so the fabrics from many of across
well the last flight Africans I got some matching yellow poplin cotton fabric for the contrast
on the yoke on the inside the cuffs
the packet on the sleeve opening on this project I've been able to learn quite lock
techniques are in you know I've got there are a couple of Tuck's on here
obviously I'm having to attach a cuff this one's partially don't I still need to finish
off the cups and by the time I finished that all of made a color and
added the Boston band on the front step yeah it's been really interesting making this of
really enjoyed that can wait for it to be finished actually as well that's I compare
it so yeah the safari hopefully be the first project I finished good Leonie's finish it
for the course I'm doing anyway so I'll give me extra motivation so I don't added
this to my make time because I'm this is obviously how barbut with the in twenty
nineteen but I would like to make a man's shirt there you'll probably make one fulfilled
possibly my that I'm not sure but yeah the shots Stephanie in the cards can I
think I have the confidence after making this one for the show I'm hoping on my
and she had some fabric at home to use I was quite like to make a
Christmas deem shirt at some point but I would have to buy a fabric to make
a festive unless I embroidered something in it but I don't really have any claims fabric
to do that so I'd have to still by plane fabric that will see a gun
mother to me on the buttons passing on their which is the fray a sweater so
I've already made the fray a cow neck dress so it's essentially the same person from
Tilly one spoke stretch but I'd really like to make the top version as I got
a couple of different pinnacles now Orchy and so I'm finally wearing the tear so this
was my upcycled one I would say have an IV pinafore which is a Jennifer Lauren
handmade passen I will say another really nice pitiful that my sister got for me for
my birthday last year so it's really nice to have different tops that can go under
all of those and I think the friar quest is a really good one particularly for
the colder months recently I got a couple of holon x is a gift for Christmas
and which is something I said I'd really like know I never like that design and
that I feel comfortable wearing that I'm going to make some myself as well I've added
the free person by sullen of assonance the slip of it on here just because I
might make them as a gift and I felt like I needed to had a couple
of gifts on to my mate line to make it a bit more untunable because what
tends to happen is I make some stuff for myself possibly indefinitely in the first half
of the year I can only get to about June and then I kind of trail
off a bit I don't if it just gets a bit too warm or it's just
because people's besting start dropping up or I start thinking of Chris man so know maybe
other stuff's just happens at that time he anyway so I was end up kind of
losing steam at some points and then I start shifting on to make us for other
people so I gotta figured that if I had the old one for someone else as
well in the make knife and might actually make more than them the final item I
put on here is to make some trousers so I've signed up already to a local
Patton casting course and which is to make your own trials of lock which I'm really
excited about it is an introduction to pass in casting in twenty nineteen which I really
enjoyed so we night sky back to passing cutting and a little bit more but to
be honest I haven't done a huge amount since I did that interaction is passing casting
so I'm not sure if I'm jumping the gun about going straight on to the trials
are cutting one but I will say equally hoping that it might inspire me and also
I think it will build on that knowledge to perhaps all then real address all of
the past in casting I've learned so far and actually experimented it more I think so
that's my make nine I'm quite optimistic about this list actually I quite like during the
make line list just because it kind of gives you a starting point on what to
make I know you know different patterns come out during the year I mean I personally
got tons of patterns in my stash as those things I just want to make on
a whim as well you know a bit like last year when we make the beach
top poncho that was on on my neck line we just wanted to make a beach
towel bunching so well there any made a few of I make my last year I
don't necessarily fill that bad about it because avise it takes to change over the year
or and your priorities change so it's not the end of the world but it's nice
to have something to focus on particular at the start of the year so other things
I want to focus on this year making wise I am as I mentioned I picked
on to you in a passing casting course for making the trials of look so that's
definitely a core goals are already signed up to it and I hope to make as
parer trousers from that I would like to go back as I mentioned to what I've
learned on pattern cutting the other thing I'd like to do possibly earlier on in the
year is to get some of my garments mended so I do have a pile of
garments and bags as well to be fair their only fixing so I've held a plentiful
and I've got the friar pinafore which is the Kirsty Hartley person I don't know if
it was just exclusive in the simply serving magazine and but anywhere I did a review
quite a number of years ago now on this person I really do like this design
and but the trouble is I use this really nice needle board from fabrics below and
the buttons keep ripping off the back so I think I need to either put every
enforced and bit fabric on the back that's got really think interfacing or I might even
just put a different fabric of the back maybe a remnant of the custom poplin I've
got there or even a thicker yellow fabric I seem to want the other fabrics and
breathing only fabric and but yes sir I need to fix that so I can Waris
again about a couple of ready to where garments which I'm like I've got one that
has this bar across the front new your call again but it's come away at one
side so I caught my that until it's fixed I've got another dress it's a knitted
one and that one has got a couple of holes in it which I need to
down so I would like to get all of that done and then moving forward just
fix things as soon as they break so yes consistent mending it's definitely on the agenda
for twenty twenty there are a couple of special birthday is coming up in twenty twenty
and my family so I need to focus on them make sure that I get everything
that I want to achieve that their birthdays sorted out care if I don't think I
want to do address in this video is how I'm going to track my progress and
more importantly my makes so what I've done I don't know if I can get this
on the screen but I'll try to I am going to use I'm a spreadsheet to
do that so I think about schepen on exile online but you could do this in
Google sheets or and not the spreadsheet slipware I'm sure would work I've used an online
based spreadsheet just to that I can update it wherever I am I don't have to
be at home on the chamisa I can look it up the quick reference on my
phone in the reason I chosen to use the spreadsheet for this is I'm quite data-driven
and so my day job I look at a lot data and I guess that kind
of just spilled into my personal life I guess it just nice to be able to
track your progress I do think it helps to know how much you've achieved in the
year so I think I'll be my main motivation because then it will show that although
you know that may be times when you can't make something or you haven't been able
to achieve as much as you want to do but then you can look back see
all the extra imprint two projects the have achieved anything else really that's you know have
been added to your list and then at least you can then see how much you
have managed to do and faculty very motivating and inspiring so on my scratchy I'm going
to give each project a name I'm going to list which pass and I've used what
type of product is so I
have create a drop down this for this so I've added if it's a garment it
is the top if it's bottoms if it's a one-piece garment it is an accessory how
so would I some a toy I've put so I can look holding it takes me
or how long the project goes on for so I've got a column to put the
start day on the end date and then I put a formular in to calculate the
total number of days that took me to complete it I think I had a bit
where I can break the project as well I don't know for added it yet but
obviously if I have all show you if I bunch to this lay on the screen
someone that as well to look whether it's for myself or someone else and whether it's
Christmas make or not so I just don't get released would see actually how many items
do make for myself how many I do make for other people how many I make
for the house at the moment I feel like I want that information that it may
turn out that the India I don't even look at it in which case or review
how much information I really need to look so I've added a few things on their
and then I think all review it maybe partway through the year maybe at the end
of the year and then decide how I need to adjust the format so maybe that
I don't want to look for type of garment I'm making or whether it's myself for
someone else I've just thought of a few different things that I may possibly want to
look and I'll take it from that okay so that's it for this week so hopefully
I'll be back next time with any video possibly hopefully to do with the shirt I
showed you like say I'm really placed to finishing it but yeah hopefully I'll get it
finished by them and then I'll be able to review the pattern x leching