say I'm going to go through five possible quick sewing makes for gifts if you like
this video don't forget to I can subscribe so I'm just going to round off by
ideas I've got on quick sewing gifts you can make their role ideas where you can
find a tutorial online so if you're not sure how to create it yourself you'll definitely
be able to find some instruction somewhere on the web I think they're all quite quick
mix as well there is what I'm not completely sure how long it would take but
I just really wanted to add it for some reason it's the first idea is to
make their simple I'm as so there are lots of different three buttons online and also
if you got the firmest so we look at the library you could probably find one
and there as well so I know a particular one that I'm these myself is the
Italian the button is free my last person so there's a really good guided said as
a downloadable template if you follow that it won't take you that much time at all
to create one you don't need an awful lot of fabric for a sign or so
you could W's on some scraps if you make that the great thing with the imus
as well as you could combine it in your Christmas yet so good to get them
seven you no trouble at all the treatment or
I don't know it looks just them I guess other items that compliments and I ask
you know I guess the self-care kids it is the idea number two it's also from
Cillian buttons they have a slip of it as an I really want to make this
I haven't made this one and so this is the one where I'm not sure if
it would be I'm really quick make but I just really wants to do it in
some reason and again I think it's quite a good sash buster it doesn't look like
you need an awful or fabric to greater if you were making this for someone else
you would need to know their shoes signs that's the main issue I'd say and obviously
I guess
some people might not like that style of slipper but like I say I think it's
a really novel idea it's a bit different and yeah it's a free person so it
would be amazing to give it a go I don't number three it is to make
a head old urban so as you might be aware I've done a tutorial on this
and I've got a downloadable PDA half in which is free on my website but there
are probably lots of other ones available as well or I'm wrong post that could teach
you know how to walk up your own one to your own test again he could
couple some other shop for thousands whether you know you could get some nice to know
toiletries shampooed position of bubble bath
you know any other deconditioning hair treatments all of those words compliment and the heads out
urban really nicely I did member for is the classic Toot's bag so bags really first
little option you can only make one of them most people I think most be more
to be appreciative of one you can obviously personalise it depending on who you're giving it
to or you can make it as neutral was possible if you're not too sure what
they're interested in below if you are making a gift for someone I'd hope that you
leave him well enough or that you were close enough to them to be expanding the
time and effort to make a hammock lift so there are absolutely tons of to bag
platens out there and tons of three Hatton's so again it's something that you wouldn't need
to buy a passion for obviously if you want to buy passen that's fine but if
you know you're trying to keep the costs down and you just want something quickly you
can access instantly and for example money makes us got a nice looking to bank which
they broke and he takes twenty minutes which sounds about it but I mean I know
I used a couple of different Tobit patterns online some that you know have the
bottom to it you know rather than just having to front of backpiece stitch together from
the sides that's actually got base as well which will be seemings you can store a
bit more in your bag and again obviously you could potentially and you know you think
I am bag you're giving that person with a to bore item if you want to
do but it's definitely a good one on its own as well and finally I did
number five is to make some thought of the zipper pouch so I've shown a tutorial
on how to make a simple tempest previously so obviously cannot look at that and I've
got a block press which might be a bit easier to follow from the video on
local I expect that relate to different patterns that pouches out there which could help you
decides on the style that you like the great thing again about set pouches kind of
goes back to the eye mask and the head tallat heaven but again you could use
it as the case for the base for the rest of the gift so I mean
obesely traditionally and you know you put money and a
sip of our Chul pass but what you could do is had some other items that
you want to give them you to create a vanity that you can you know give
some really nice bespoke button and if they're intercross if you made it longer or a
bit bigger you could make a pencil case and add some really nice color and pencils
in there and starts going to obviously I'm
a child at school but it could also be good for anyone who's into mindful coloring
it's also a really good idea and for storage if you know they ballance of Croatia
hex they could store their gray shikse in and I stepped pouch it's about it for
tidies video obviously there are absolutely tons of different quicks own makes you can create that
or even quicker than once I've suggested or you know might be a bit more of
a suitable dependency you can to make for but I just thought I'd give a few
just a gettable rolling if you know you're in a something in official what to make
or you know you literally got you know what do you think to make it and
do you need to decide fast Pixley that will help well that's it for now thanks
for watching