today I'm sharing with you my talk non-essential luxury sewing license if you do enjoy this
video and you haven't already pleasing forget the like and subscribe so I'm sure you all
know there are loads of different sewing gadgets until without their or with different uses and
some very specific some extremely versatile and it's quite difficult to navigate which one do you
need which ones you don't
and which ones would just make your life so much easier than to know I'm going
to share the ones that I have in particular that I know what is not essential
at all you definitely don't need them but they're there quite nice if I'm someone's asking
you what you want for Christmas offer your birthday or just the trees in general and
most of these are ones which I probably have received as a gift and I'm very
appreciative of them so I'm going to share six different tools with you to number one
is the biased finding that so the vice finding that I've had for a number of
years now I think I actually I'm
at this one of my mom who'd forces online I'm and I ended up acquiring it
and so it's really handy attaching by is finding obviously I wouldn't say it's essential because
obviously you can attach wise finding using a regular sewing machine that isn't by is finding
foot and depending on the item you're making and what you're covering with bias finding it
can produce a really neat clean finish and sense to you can adjust it there's a
little section here where you can slide it across depending on how why to your eyes
finding it so you can see the go and some metric markers for the white hair
so for five more meters ten fifteen twenty the main places where I've used this before
is when I made path hats and it of got a bath papasan over on Etsy
and on that it's really useful because I'm just touching by finding on the broom of
the bath that and it's really easy to just
stitch down the slide it means that you don't have to stitch on one side fold
over and then stitch on
top citril way around it just does the topstitch section through both layers and applies it
you do have to be careful and make sure that your fabric is positioned properly into
this tool so that its slotted and right into whether the guidance if you don't do
that then there is a lot of unpicking to do
so it's not essential because obviously you can just use your regular sown machine but to
attach by us finding and actually nowadays I do prepare the finish where you stitch one
side to the first side with your son machine any time over and I do like
to hand so finish it now and then you just have a really nice clean edge
and but obviously again you can just and flip it over and top stitcher so I
guess in a way you save a bit of threat by using this tool and it'll
take you a lot of time and it just depends really what you're doing quite unavoidable
luxury iseum but like I say pans what finished you want and sometimes especially if it's
already bulky saying you think that warding and it's gonna be quite hard to get into
the stage so it's not always useful luxury so nice and number two is a thing
age so I really like this scene gauge I've had it for a couple of years
now it's really handy it's got this is a metric one by the way you can
also get an imperial measurement one I just think it's really useful because it's got all
your main measurements that you will need to they obviously one heart centimeters which is my
days of an inch and that's the common when you'll find on your sewing persons but
it will say has one sent to me so which I guess it's a bit more
common if your sewing and its past him and six centimeters I think that's as standard
hemp there's also for centimeters hair which she come across and two centimeters is quite common
as well and for certain seems on your garment I also use this grid when we've
got the sixth sense Mrs so it has all the lines for the millimeters and I
do use that sometimes it and for quick reference I just find this tools a lot
easier to use and but of course you can just use the tape measure and most
people got a tape measure that of her spear take measures a lot more best file
because you can you know measure yourselves you measure of the people with their I'm item
and said like the water bottle and carrier made you can you know replicate measure around
the iseum that you want to measure where is this obviously it's very specific to and
marking out smaller items or you know impressing but I do use it a lot to
press and mark seems just because it's a lot I guess it's a lot phanar than
a tape measure or not sorry if I use it a lot more for pressing and
especially you know when a party of hands or and presence that you can't see the
same answer even marking the seam allowance because it's just a lot farmers and take mission
in the past I have accidentally irons over a tape measure and not sure how accurate
is anymore not sure how well they can withstand higher heat levels so and where is
this I kind of feel like you know it's going to send the test to the
same machine a stool heat levels or it hasn't dated anyone I've definitely I do right
by accident so
yeah I just find it's a nice consistent way to
use it in that way this is probably the cheapest until that I'm sharing with you
and I'd say
it's a really useful one so if someone is looking for a little gift for you
this is the perfect suggestion if you don't have one already moving from cheap and cheerful
to very luxuriously expensive is this fiscals cutting tool so
this was definitely left and I haven't had it all I had it less than a
year and essentially it's a fabric guillotine so you place this over your that broke its
part of us all so essentially you place this over your fabric using a coughing that's
like this one
and you mine it up to where you want it to be and then you apply
pressure to this and hotter crops they obviously this is amazing if you're a quota because
you can just cut straight lines really easily with it and you couldn't also cut quite
a few layers of fabric in one go which is handy as well at all sees
the indirect making that if there is a really that I'm him say or some of
the sides it can be useful to cut those but mythically you know quitting but making
bags any accessories in that if it's a straight line and you know I made a
cushion recently and you can just really easily and accurately cost out straight lines which is
amazing is this way to replicate this in a much cheaper fashion would be to just
have a regular ruler or even a quoting really like this which would still be a
lot cheaper than this and the and dingily acquitting ruler and your
rotary cutter so that would be simple I guess the advantage or is that it's fixed
to this part so you can sometimes veer off for that even when using a ruler
and that's on its own that again this obviously is a logic of them even the
rotary castor and the rulers more luxury in initially goes the scissors and marking out the
line okay so I may have done to come by saying that the scene goes was
the cheapest by some on my luxury serving license list and because no before is one
of these which is one of those so I push out the corner tools they are
this is really useful it's got a nice home point so that you can push out
those corners without hopefully jabbing a hole
in your fabric as you push out the corners of use their plenty of times and
labels a gift and I'm very appreciative with it again the reason I put it as
a non-essential is because I'm sure there are plenty of things you could find around the
house to
out your corners I see is a mess pair missing the door quite a lot although
to be honest I used to end up poking a hole into the fabric a lot
of the time when I did that so it's not the most recommended author and pushing
out corners luxury siring to number five is the chalk man I've put this down at
the luxury tool because obviously you can just use regular Taylor's joke you do not need
it and and the pond the sensor but it is very useful I find start with
the regular and Taylor's chalk sometimes I end up breaking a bit of it early like
this one because that came with a range of colors so you can quite easily and
if you hold it on the top
you can change the chalk colleagues Porsena it also produces quite a nice accurate line which
obviously over time the other tamers talk that's in a triangle a square it does where
I obviously you can then sharpen it to a point again by guess this is always
ready to go and it's quick and but it's definitely a luxurious you don't need it
to dress make and finally
luxury item number six I kind of combine to him because it's the mini ironing board
and I am set and again pretty straightforward boy it's a luxury item if you already
proselyting boards you don't need of anyone and again if you buy implores you probably got
a regular iron of which means you don't need a miniature item oversee if you do
lift somewhere where you don't have a of space and then by means and many ironing
board is definitely not a luxury item and its beneficial it means it takes up less
room swim I'm and also this is actually you're really good on and so you know
it would obviously take you a lot longer as the iron your includes but it's definitely
doable I find both of these really useful just because I can just set it up
on this table hear it means that they had to keep lashing out to heal the
room to iron I sometimes to put the aisle in this room but obviously I do
share this room with my partner who sometimes like Steve this computer say and I don't
think he always appreciate having an iron board right behind his chair which is obviously a
bit dangerous so it's a lot safer if I use and this island good and so
here they
come up like this and this was from ikea and I think this is it an
answer
yes and this does steam as well so you can that waters but and it's really
handy if you've got something small especially if you're doing a project you know and like
when I was making my bag all the water Bhattacharyya all the pass you know it's
it's a lot of have to bring out the a guiding board and iron and so
you can save a bit of time by I'm just popping out the meaning set and
then you can leave it up while doing the project so it's quite handy especially if
you know you are short on time or like me got a chronic house issue sometimes
and kylies little corners can make it so much easier feed to and get on my
the craft project and but like say if you're really short on space and money you
really don't need it if you do have a regular I'm an ironing board so that's
it but today I'm sure there are plenty of other non-essential tools that I've got I
definitely got lots of sewing paraphernalia and so I'm sure there's plenty of other things that
I haven't mentioned here but I thought that would be a good snapshot for you I
hope you enjoyed this and thanks for watching