hello today I'm going to go through my seven quaint checklist the setting up for through
machine embroidery so you might notice from some of my previous videos that I do a
feather of free machine and murderee I have an ocean done a lot recently which is
why I've set up this southern quite checklist because last time I used that I forgot
to lower the dog feet it's good to have a checklist for setting up for the
machine embroidery just because you can make sure that your sewing machine is set up on
the best configuration afrits on my son machine there's a few different adjustments you need to
make compared to regular sirring it's also good as well actually at the end of room
machine embroidery to make sure you reverse these steps because there's been plenty of times where
of letter of Rui Xingu embroidery wondered why say that dog the aren't moving the fabric
forward I've also had the issue where I've left the tension loose on the other bread
and it meant like that to redo seems so the first one on my list is
to make sure that you lowered the dog feet or depending on your machine you've put
the darning place on their so when you do regular machine sewing you've got the dog
feet at the bottom of your machine and needs help to feed through the fabric and
so that it moves along and you only just the seed of that through the press
of it or you might you the Boston depending on your machine there with my machine
I've got to switch at the fact which lowers the deputy about other machines you have
a zoning plate which can cover up the dog tea so that they weren't into bear
and they won't remove your fabric for you so one of the great things about through
machine and raw Dariusz that's you get to move your fabric in all different directions not
just forward through the machine and lowering the dog to call covering them is the first
step to ensuring that you have that freedom of movement the second point in my tennis
is to change the press office so on a regular sewing machine that you will have
the
regular peh sophont and so on this one it's the one that's on the machine to
start with it means you can do both zigzag and you can
also do straight stitch you could do all the I'm machine stitches on their however with
an embroidery puts it looks slightly different it means that it's just a bit easier for
you to move around in all those different directions as I mentioned before make starting fits
of designed so that you can still use this exact function or a white stitch as
well as a straight stitch but it just means that it's normally got offering around it
I guess that holds the fabric in place I'm and yet just means that you can
go in any direction there are some people who do three machine and broidery without a
bombing fits and which obviously is an option I think you've got to be of it
all careful with how fast you need your fabric though because you are at risk of
sending or breaking the needle because you don't have that extra guards and also just a
health and city point is that you can stand runover your fingers as well I guess
the press of it helps keep your fingers at a distance point number three is to
check which machine needle you are using so sometimes I don't bother with this step if
I if I'm doing through she embroidery on away the piece of at broke I've just
so got something in a woven fabric previously it's a roughly similar fabric weight or just
leaves so what I currently got on that I'm but you can get embroidery needles as
well which I think there is it easier to threat I did it got a slightly
wider point and a white a hole in the needle so it is easy especially few
using fancier threats it just means that it will help you threat your machine it will
help to make sure that you're using the right so machine needle if you do end
up using the wrong one and it can obviously cause issues that can you know it
can affect the how how it's stitching you can affect how it's going through the fabric
whether creating larger holes or not so it really is worth making sure that you are
you from the right machine needle because then it will stop at it could prevent you
have in to resolve issues further down the line quite number for it is to choose
your are preterit and your bobbin so sometimes I don't want to changing the bobbin it
can be a bit for fast and sometimes I do change it it kind of depends
on the project depends on what I'm making who it's for will say whether it's going
to show up so sometimes you might want the Bob in to match the backload fabric
anyway if you know people can see that that sometimes you will want it to match
the other thread just because in case the tension berries as you stitch it might appear
on on the top of the fabric and then in which case you know might detract
if you've got a really bad the contrasting thread on the bottom you're gonna see flecks
of that on the top but sometimes you might want that effect so you know you
might purpose to the Jews of a nice contrasting thread on the bottom in the bobbin
so that you then can have that extra interesting detail on the top point number five
is to adjust the upper for attention I know some people do also adjust the Bob
intention and in the past of on a different machine I've had issue where I've been
broken the Bob in case so normally I try to shy away from adjusting of in
case I'm not sure how easy as to do on this machine anyway because it's a
one where you drop the bubbling from the top rather than so on my machine depending
on the fabrics of threads and just generally the project I'm doing I will tend to
adjust the tension to about minus two this will very
different machine is vary depending on like I say what you're doing what I assume machine
you've got that even you using whether you're using
a spit of big darning birds and you know how you're preparing your fabric which will
get on to shortly if you don't want your lower thread showing it's good to lower
the number lower attention on your so on some machine so mine itself of the point
so their correct tension there's an arrow the where it would be humbly so I put
it to minus two so if you your machine is normally sat on safe for because
sundial got on the number so then you adjust it to perhaps the real you know
to and up and see whether that works so is always worth testing that out that
that's something I tend to forget about argosy again if you do on that effect of
the dread coming up you might wanna see what it's just like on a normal tension
or you might want to actually increase it to plus one or two and the data
be here for could sometimes of you put it to high the treddle separate number six
is to choose your stitch and stitch length with free machine embroidery you're not going to
get the same effect with your decorative stitches some of them will just look like exact
stitches depending on how you feed the fabric through the machine because the machines
normally programmed to speed through to create the particular design because you're taking that element away
by having the dog tea clothes or covered you're going to affect how that decorated it
comes out saying that you can get a lot of good effects from it a lot
of the pre machine broidery I do is just the plains through stitch so I'll make
sure on my machine that I changed it to
number six on my machine which is the straight stitch where the machine is in the
middle of the darning but I also normally reduce it to a lower stitch length so
on this machine I've got the freedom to adjust it to hold on I want the
stitch length which is one of the reasons I decided I'm that this would be good
sewing machine to use so at the moment I've got mine to zero point five which
is a valued like you could fill all the way down to zero because at the
end of the day you're affecting how long the stitches are well though I guess that
again could affect how much you see of the lama thread the bobbin coming up onto
the surface of your fabric if you do have a machine which has preset stitch lengths
that's not the problem either I have also used I'm my other sewing machine which is
also returning to but it's what set stitch lengths I won't addressed it like this one
and I used to just have it on I think it was the smallest stitch length
I used to put it on but it's still went fine you've just got to adjust
how quickly you move your fabric over at all you know how how fast you I'm
not your foot down on the pedal and finally quite number seven is to prepare your
fabric so there's a few different things you can do or rather a couple that I
use anyway the name way that I do three machine of broidery is to use an
embroidery who so but one here
so all users you can see work it's great that on them it's great it to
get under the building but they sometimes depending on how thick your broidery who is and
especially if you're using it donning and darning plates rather than dropping the doxie it can
be quite challenging to put an embroidery hoop underneath a machine however it is really good
because you can get the fabric really sort with an embroidery hoop which is great because
it means that you're going to have less issues with the machine needle going in and
out of the fabric one of the drawback is that you will if you're doing a
larger designers you will have to keep moving the who and obviously you will need to
press it after because it will leave a mark on your fabric and that yeah it's
probably so my favorite method of doing through machine broidery saying that there is so if
I can scrape it under the and the darling but I will do that another option
is to use as stabilizing fabric underneath I think the brand name of the most common
like disposable for you can use a stitch in ten sometimes I'll use this actually just
to
design on top of the fabric if I'm following as something I've drawn out I'll put
it on top of my fabric instead of alone and then I can see have what
I'm stitching especially the bone a doctor fabric and I can't necessarily the fabric and in
Canada use and a thickish stabilizing proper on the boss on the bottom of it just
to help keep it stretched out it doesn't work quite the same as an embroidery necessarily
but it is another option especially if you are struggling getting where your use only the
dawning puts another option depending on the weight of your fabric is to use nothing so
especially for something like denim or really heavy canvas you don't actually need to necessarily put
it into
a murdering you could just hold it yourself and dried it through okay so that's my
seven-point checklist for setting up the three machine and broidery and if you think prognosis anything
out and let me go down in the current section as it's always gets to get
some more advice on this topic if you'd like see more videos like this subscribe to
the channel and you can find out more information on my word slides plugger creations occurred
on UK thanks for watching