hello and welcome back today is the best of a capture as always if you like
this video I want to see more please I forget to like unsubscribe if you aren't
already right so it's been a few weeks since we did a catch up last time
I broke fell back in know my fellow lockdown body there I just thought I do
a favor catch up on what I've been up to so I mentioned in my twenty
twenty pounds that there were a couple of big birthdays this year so ones already passed
as I mentioned in this I think I ever catch up and I made a dressing
gown for that and that was one of my make line which was checked with the
listened for this one I decided to make a shore so I am recording little their
early just because I need to post it and totally awesome
I've got it in here so and this is a drawstring bag that I have also
recently made and I will post a tutorial on it shortly possibly next week so it's
a nice simple was in mind drawstring bag I have actually used fabric which I got
one year or so Saturday event and that was local at the sewing studio in rubbery
Yep so I've done it designed so it fits the so nicely of an extra little
gift in now which is the brooch man
yeah I don't want to open up because it was packaged so nicely yet so hopefully
its find in that but I'm sure
so this is the shore so this is done with broomstick crochet
which is when to use a joint knitting needle that's about
to an often to meet us in diameter or twenty-five or
I guess that's an inch is
yes it's a really big listen you will be only use one and then you use
a creature her the inside and you basically draw up the stitches on to the sentinel
and then you croche double pressure the most in group of four
and so yeah but this one first up neatly agents and but I really just go
around to making it I think I always did plan to make it to this particular
to the first day not be so
yes just been just been waiting in the in the sash like not the other thing
so that's another of my neck minus to check up on the added again I sat
salad it was going to go with little carry one with the birthday seems so
even though they're just going to be in the house of the rain
and not having a party into obviously it's safe to do so and but I still
thought you know what I mean a badge for the other special birthday gonna make a
badge again or a rose at so I've gone for a slightly different design I did
a much simple one last time and but this one's a bit more freely and a
bit more like a river so
I've just used some scrubs in my stash and they actually much a set of pajama
bottoms I made them as well so you need to hear to chill out in those
pajamas and have a matching yeah but they resent it was I still had a bit
of that fabric left I don't have a lot of honor but I also made one
of those simple face was patterns that are online and I've made two different sizes because
I can't tell which one was that better
so I'm just gonna post both of them to and I don't know she
may be the smaller one on the teddy bear of a dozen sense
something like that as though she's got out matching facemask to go with her or that
the forest for she has the last so
she's probably sick of face months by this point and because she has to wear them
at work but I just thought this might be a bit more of her and what
is the domestic one so obviously and she can't bring the face mushies of that work
home because they need to be used at work so
it will make this argosy isn't as effective as the as a proper the button yeah
exactly so I'm cheek my life she wishes and she can match the but they wrote
that so it's really
you really like this fabric so it's a bit sad that I don't you got tiny
little cross to the left but it's good to use it I think I got it
from a charity shop to be honest and but yeah I've got my he said finally
on the best different I've made a card as well so and I mentioned before the
channel one day in the hundred-day projects where I'm doing a hundred days of free machine
embroiders animals so I'm a bit tired of through machining outside of that so I decided
to hands to this one for a change so it took a little at a time
but it was quite fun to divert of hand the broidery instead so just done backstitch
for the the text and Ivy's change search for the rainbow
this was actually you're right there wasn't a what he wanted have you dismissed it immediately
will not suggested it does make me think of the and
well yeah well to be fair she's you know she worked the hostile
she's faced with it quite a lot already and will be for a consider one time
you know it's a vector to work but
in the end I could think of anything else and then I thought well
you can't avoid what's happening and right by the matter colorful
the rainbow is being used as a support the NHS simple wooden the UK
don't
it's got a bit more by red
wine I said Billy asyla to go out for one day the houses of exercise so
it's why nice to see how many rainbows even spot
with the hundred-day project as its sons to say so over some recording this infant slightly
I've done just be the town centre the project
yes it's been interesting I have got to you sick about you know I think to
be really good I really please one should complete it I think the main challenge for
me is actually sketching out the design every day it's not very confident drawing a and
take a lot googling of how to draw this animal and then
also its finding the right friends I'm going to use up a lot of my less
Lester good quality threating this project
is quite a good ones that to the person
I might also need to more bleach halakhah before them because I'm not sure I'm gonna
get sent out
what's that
quiet I think my favorite is the any
yeah and I quite like the same rise and it will say because I had to
go all the same right while
I love have to document an informant
you'll do the time lapse in between which
is based it so many photos an Instagram consistently said
only place they may say
well that was quite late last night was nice but it was the end of the
working week and
I really time or the handsome the design yet
and then over seal be hard to make this stuff for the birthdays along the same
a meeting I walked in the white an internal used to get not Gianelli I can't
find from trans machine varied up an animal before you start like
I had so we don't have deck me at the moment
got that time available so dress-making was unbearable makes from the make it simple book
is
now I've recorded by to them
so it was the juniper dollars
which is more like a one and a half
because
it's like this you know for John the bottom but you have them to short
but there are really clear instructions to do and then the top of these shorty pajamas
is the top of Atisha
so I kind of felt like one and a half persons from the back
forty and and the other one I make more recently was the Safiya Danbury's but I
made a short version and I also kept the elasticated waste man from this the VK
suits
yes I'm already faced in a review on that which you can see I think next
I am going to move on to the tsuki dress
because it looks really nice and simple the main problem that I've had and the main
reason I have made it yet is because I need a fabric that's wide enough and
that there's enough of it because it's actually it's only me I'm going to make the
version that short-sleeved so I don't need to
cut out the long
I don't need to cut out the sleeve person yeah pieces however it does mean that
because it's got a slight grown on sleeve it's quite a wide happen
so if you got a narrow that fabric you can't fit
let's both the front and back next to each other you have to use more of
the length
so I'm just trying to find something at home I don't really want to buy any
fabric for this and also it's obviously taking a world to get deliveries at the moment
so yeah I want to see I'm might actually that green fabric
yeah so I think that might be quite nice I was going to use this like
agi picked it up fabric but I'm not sure it will look that right it's kind
of it's a very lightweight cotton it's probably almost a quilting Costas and not sure I
think it's gonna sharp creases really really
I think I'm not really sure I'm gonna do with that fabric possibly I might make
you a shower with it I think I would probably look nicer Lona's leashing draft but
I'm obviously got some nice fabric for a first shot when I find it round up
and apart from that the other thing I've planned to make
is a gift for another family member it is another birthday coming up in me and
it's
it's not a milestone birthday to say but I do want to make something especially it
or not really sure what else I buy for them at that moment I'm sure that
something again I can purchase online stone and get it sent to the house but
yeah I have to have a think about that that's probably the next thing going to
do but I think it's going to it's going to be a knit make and McKinney's
net fabric I don't think she watches this channel but just in case she got the
and say but I do need to fix my overlocker for the an essentially I really
damaged one of my overlocker needles when I was make when I was just finishing off
the top of the data for my pajamas and yeah it just completely and it's that
promised an instant yeah I think about
partially can use it with I'm only one needle see what three red looking so that
was fine when I was making this to be a lacy Embury hackbuts food next I'd
rather have faced needles and the Boche
yeah yeah so they've turned up now not and but we also thought that perhaps the
blades he had changing because I've never changed them
was also here for a kind of bad news about corn the fabric and pretend she
not counting off fast enough for us who it belonged yeah
to replace one place Harry that we see if that helps you know the interest and
see that makes a difference because I don't know how often use face to change the
blade
I mean is still casting and but I don't know whether you space to choose to
for frequently I've had it quite a number of years and I really like her mother
how long but you know it's not like it's just being a compass really was the
place
to sit it was a machine
that silly
and I guess you don't have to change them frequently they'll be interested to see how
often you should change them more interesting
when I just go and every a needle know that yet open so that that might
be wise and blunt or but before
made a horrible night I wouldn't recommend it and they possibly make some smaller items so
I might we've got like a puppy to recover which I think I've mentioned on here
ages go to town to recover I still haven't done anything I might go on like
I really did want to and get it into use
which we go to smash yeah I mean to be honest like it probably not not
will be the staff
at the moment so that's why they really wants why more fabric it be nice to
clear up a bit and then I'm doing the of knitting through the old netting throat
which is another of my make Klein it's still plodding along
they come on the sixty eight swearer of ninety
so it's getting there it be interested to see if I finish it before
the social distancing measures to
miss it or not
I am also sewing up this well together as I go along his wild sick I'm
not just constantly missing up the smiles I am sometimes taking a break in the sun
you know that of mine to get that so have you been silent
only move my directions that
which me nothing to anyone who was this what is that when the intellect out
on conservation area was not like the other day and the internet just it's connected and
then there was like Oh no no that's not me
internetworking fine
it's wise to find my own my way Ismet
have any achievements over the last few weeks so
much
like the
very possibility
is currently playing some with states months again and the blood is
basically the mission is that you're eating
the galaxy
very dramatic as recording the and the drawstring bag unfortunately I am going to avoid a
bronze is all the way to just
very
very interesting way you're talking
I think I quite like to take in what if we can get the stuff for
you hand subcity eggs with the field things
yeah deny still it right but I wish he said but
I can't think that's it for this time will come either another catch up in a
few weeks to think
you
were very be back in a boat we see a crunchy date called me
yes I can we do have time for a rocky them why deny the hundred-day project
sickness that you and you'll get it
because
the megadeath product trellising as well and paste that
here with us it for this time to hit cruel things I won't be sued by