high and welcome back
well it's mean a while has not it definitely
so we just that we do a great kept up
didn't happen intransigeant to what
what we plan to do that share and these things we'd be working on currently
you may have noticed to play a drop of requested the just move the last year
yeah so I think twins twenty what was the constant
was hoping to but that
didn't have another video ready well I think ready I'd edited the actual footage and I
needed to revise soma by distinct it around to works in time and it was Christmas
seemed so I'm not into place to get
the kick and wait until it gets yeah pretty much so um yeah addrest matawan so
yeah not a lot happened and its kind of reflective from the lack of videos so
to get a few things
I want for Christmas
made a pot holder
my sister the
so we got you listen things done I get my new Christian night like which by
doing place of a Christmas card
my Christmas so that that
but apart from that Oh yeah just a day jobs kind of dominated a lot of
the year so be a lot of changes in my role in particular and then even
more recently and your changed as well
so that's kind of effectives other areas of our lives over the last year
also just work in remote leaves though we're both still predominantly remote working
and to various degrees and to stretchable
mean it's like less than you bet
and that's a greasy had an impact that actually I mean we have essentially been up
remain working since we saw this global event and why been in I think it was
having an eleven days in Cato at this point since all and kept on the rest
of us on
beriberi the different points so and but still had an impact on on where we live
so we live in a black it's not huge its
tiny but it's not a huge sighed I got so that's that's all resee affected our
productivity at home so
pretty I've had to
essentially move that the table I used to craft on and on can ask there instead
and have all my work here there and which is fine it's a little bit with
because I'm to abort the start but and
for you made a an overhead camera like a roadie high one just a little local
to see one mother yeah so uses to camera motile I think she's Pizer right so
yeah it did the job by yourself directly above the craft as I can attach to
receive or
it's still there
yes I say we can easily get some footage and the winter in the day they
want to be fair I thought quite nice keep on it like it's no to college
isn't it the lights on it say so that looks quite pretty but you know not
very practical for making any craft videos or documenting anything do apart from work
Sarah yeso not very as we made it somewhere so my list of things to do
my god to repurpose that scientists call she be
over the
people at the peacocks clear to come
so
anyway so that that hasn't helped and I think so then we moved my craft table
into the living area so it's in this room and we just found that for I
found that it it just wasn't working out because and the way we had this from
arranged I was just it was in the corner of my eye the whole time so
and be saying watching TV but then I could see the table the craft table also
machine subtle not being aged yeah I just had already demotivate him just to sink in
yet I'm not crofting at the moment and it just looked really not see
you could just see it you know it's it's obviously not as especially designed graph table
once it's
a dining table that someone gave us
you know so you can see everything underneath that and yeah just like to mass really
so what we have done actually which we do that the start this year is move
around this great you say we were so she flipped them already having good and it
means that now the craft table instead of being kind of in front of us when
we're sitting on the sofa like we are now it's actually over to the side so
is common room dividers one yeah just the other side of the room divide up from
the widow with turn my mom covered with this a very gravely orange rather at home
but the last sentence we don't need to see get we did have it without there
in the wider result for readily than me and that works quite well as well me
I think just because it's there rather than in front it just it makes the world
of difference so fingers crossed that will actually have an impact on on feeling way to
a way to the to practice well
yeah well
you got new ever have camera there as well so well almost
needs to be attached to the season gone beyond it as I struggled to get me
well attached to the thing property not know I don't think so he's quite happening so
rarely by for her the Michael to come in the close cropped it lends too worried
about the weight of it I just want the because
we've ended up I mean I can't remember when you made the head while that we
haven't used it for many videos no in the end but I guess the main drawback
from that as you can't knew that once you are touched it essentially the way we
we did it was we just like packs and screams and listening like you like follow
wall once and schedule but I mean it is quite easy sickout this even though we
just need to patch up the whole spit
I'm not sure I feel like picking wobbles in the singly just rushes we have munched
but on a tripod fairly high the main issues if we wanted to get a shot
of the whole table
where we could get different mentally exactly say that might do it and we might go
up to put the tripod up slightly higher
than playing around though we were reviewing your living situation as well sick so as we
mentioned space of the premium hand so we were looking around see those of escape
possibly going somewhere those but in the end we've decided to sell put answers just maybe
reconsider fraction of this place I'm have a better reject especially with the cost of living
duty gastronomically
well we're okay here really only one be financially Sajid so
make risking a large pot to her finding that because Louis karakas
way to do and it's quite an efficient I could that is or is a flax
you know it's quite well insulated
it's a nourisher
it means that we've got the benefits of modern insulations
free means that Albert was hopefully wake up too much
that's pretty much
that's pretty much ten-ten one is not as they will show that are mine
so be about what we're currently done so
me pass so I've just finished a couple of some products which I didn't expect to
say so bittering out the new aircraft face in it and I've made a couple of
prayer tops now I want the fabric in October when we distance and family in Bristol
it do and to the focal Linda and I got there I took a chance on
this white fabric so it's a stretch fabric but it had that sort of unknown quantities
in it so I just so I wanted some more frail tops that were white because
I like glaring them with with my many pantoufles and so I cut that out the
very start of January I believe that really just finished the two last week
it's nice to finally finished address he can project because it has been a very long
top
yeso those two hadn't
put from that probably being focused on the on this project so
so at the at some point in twins twenty one I was talking to I'm saying
I have lips this I'm sorry project so I made this
year's dinner all started at a few years again and it was a way to use
up a lot of my wall as I have so much and I were to the
way to reduce astonish so I started this three hundred seventy it's one present throat and
eventually finished that it's full keep random assortment of follows is just what I had to
nose
and said ammono was like well you could make part of me because you need that
I didn't want to make another one for I have because as I mentioned burns not
if you don't need more than one through really I guess we can't put one on
the onto the raft about the here so I think the other problem as well as
it be hard to make one that match this because it was a whole random it's
still minimal sacred yeah so yeah so she went Oh you can make me a throat
for my sofa so she ordered some more and I've been making some Swiss for that
by the next few months
so on this new through it's not going to be a random as this it at
clovery because she's ordered the wall and the things sorted like six or seven dollars to
its I'm not going to be as random to think that more about the layout once
I've done it but yes so I've been enjoying doing that and it's a nice possible
one so if we are troubling I can easily open in the Bible bring it with
me
the other projector head is I've started a project that my dad's requested so dad if
you are watching please stop watching their
ways it was full of this cries
and yes I
not watching that but some yes so I have slaughtered making a jumper which she was
requested so about maybe a month or two for Christmas he went Oh you know what
I'd really like you to it next time you know like for Christmas summer is I'm
a jumper
I gotta love because I'm I'm very slow and after I know some people can live
and it's something in that like six weeks you know people quicker I mean to be
fair this are called to him and were now
my mom might and
remember it was not having less than two weeks because I'm yes she basically started making
it the couple of weeks before my back and managed to mention it all which is
something I definitely can't do but she is a very fast
it's yeso so I have to him and said
I thought he's talking about and the Christmas is just the past it was like yeah
that's not get happen it was like well would take it be a lead time of
the year
might get round to up and get on the moment and of his measurements either so
as to he was even more music but anyway I ended up going as measurements roughly
at some point Harmon the went but I've started making the doctor's though and it's actually
from the Princeton I found in one of this weekly so
our local library and the app they've got their digital magazines and they must be subscripted
which was willing so we did a search for a bit Mr temple something and it
came up for it might be Mrs Spencer
because it's bit more burst tough and so I found this one is here I believe
it's not a certain the sleeves
and it's not quite an interesting color that important hi it's quite simple because I haven't
made something quite this big before I don't want anything that was too involved
so as you can see I'm still on the back place still wear
slowly getting the rooms down on it but to be far I'm willing drawing it this
is quite a life school that I found in them as well me there's a couple
of all shops and Dallas now but this is just from them for local shop I
wasn't too expensive this wall I don't want to get anything too expensive Bachofen bruine and
I also want to sat quite easy to watch I'm so but he don't have to
wear about the the wash cabinet so ye so that's my progress and master
yes cut of aiming for this Christmas issue but at least wearing in the
mid fabaceae you think is cursed I can get everything else done on this jumper bottle
then
I think that's my project
the tracks kids the cattle
it's not too much as this couple of the electric certain things to come in the
camp beds again it's finally time to sit down and stop and settle over and Kaden
doctor but as Peter is not around this one
Testament's twenty-twenty say we all go to try and focus on doing to the sewing electronics
just because of it kind of Mary's up while table is quite nicely to quite from
it is a bit of
you got a technical challenge of travel sackett's fabric was keeping it is
so the only one the only project that we've shared so far the even Donte project
that we should one of them and one twin twenty-one biddy and it is the lead
but mark and all that
yeah we had to find a nice aesthetically pleasing
it was also a request the design firm money so is making it was making it
for my niece and and I asked my sister you know what would my knees like
of the design and she's
we then had to work out how to create a castle design that worked with the
ends on the circuit part that
is that what was next and only so we were kind of facing it off them
this is a good similar
yes there's a really good but I think it's out of print now but they do
have a website and that you can't is it
really handy website which showed you how you can make a simple bookmark but it is
very basic and on felt
and for this kind of tickets we don't want the battery exposed the Ficino many season
the old we wanted the battery pack hidden just cause firstly it will ruin the book
as much and a second it would mean that
we don't have to integrate it into the design
of it on the outside
but yeah the problem with that was that that's like an on-off switch on the one
the battery pack and you know that would have been very practical for my niece very
food lieutenant to be what it wasn't that while the end of used the fresh pot
of billions of the sin of challenges that we need to address some of our other
plans for projects that would like to make that there's like
got a Christmas catchers gravitic kind of have made for the mother's what film enlisted to
vis-a-vis in the design or recruit leaders design and
one it's Christmas I mean actually we make this fraction from from my or best thinking
here but will record it where I had actually get it out for December and then
we never ended up doing it I did edit all the message but I needed to
do a voice-over to explain and I have a brownstone that
the gods contrasting is more three dimensional missed its say the preaching of the battery a
little living and the branches had been hidden away
secured
they were conducted through it into any de grantor actual trigger was
making a wall were also not really much as we were going to make it a
retired to build a thing having it designed in a way where you could recharge the
batteries
and actually charges
be as interesting as for coming from teeter for the points on it
soon yeah that was an interesting product that we didn't end up share but I think
we might end up completely rerecording it because I'm making another one because there were elements
that you only really learned to go and so actually there would be better were done
this this all the way
even from the sewing point of view that you know like the soso with the reader
back and I realized that I shouldn't have cut out the antlers as to individual little
pieces it would be a little scared for just cast out the whole of the Rudolph
shaped heads with the others just stuck it to the back or them because it was
a different color to the face of Rudolph
I should have done on which you know if we will call that I've been do
it without like the way that I now think would be busted to I mean among
at work better but well we'll only find out if we did right
yes that can be quite as for twenty Quincy sea and the silent videos my change
about as all right dislike we mentioned got a different overhead camera start a high-quality so
I can that can be really good to any storages or clicking storages course once following
along you be really clearly see everything
wiring
that
really nice quality
but with earth with a new son to be different tamarillos and this Lismore the practicalities
in just the filmmaking process
yes so only first me to see the school we had done we are and you
could go out the side of this table or the long ends that way and which
meant that we could just take a camera in the front and you know have one
of the sides kind of angled to the side I think we used to have it
on the window and quarter to do the overhead and then we had them
but Amery's now just straight on as we do now that we should have only at
the side of the table so what we used to do is just don't think up
the audio one base and then we'd just like cut away to the different angles and
then when it looked best but we're not going to be up to do that because
it's against the Warner I'm just because it works better for the space
so they won't be any like head on shots but to be on a something for
love tutorials you don't need that
wanting to be a great interest to districts wearing was just how to film in this
new sat up know
what I'm doing bulletin that we don't need a better your je-sus yeah exactly so that
should be fun
I think the Kennebec test out these different angles is them I'm going to see the
hundred a project again to me to take a break class Jan was it a
lot of huge what happened punster and I'm going to do a hundred days architects old
cards so ability was a bit different to the hundred days of free machine embroidery amyls
I'm not going to necessarily record every day I might record about if every day but
I'm not necessarily gonna use all the footage I'm just going to do a bit of
a collage or a summary video every ten days so
I'm gonna combine
so happy ten video is essentially or ten Instagram and posts and I'll put the ten
different costs I end up making on that
just because it would just make it a bit less time intensive I think especially with
the animals it was quite simple was very formal back
the worked well but text on cards it is a bit more burst style and I
haven't planned it as much tools to last time I had landed animals planned to the
box than I and I used to shake the books that leads to pick out a
round of the speaker in that time of which animal is doing Monday so then I'd
still have to look up the animal and to sketch out the design of tracer and
stick gesso still a log work on the day but this time I have landed at
all but all the cards I've got a few ideas so you know any wonder into
deep today which is good to cut any to go after this and then I'm you
know I've got a couple of other Eitan's I'm just because I'm there are some other
cards I need to make for other people the other advantage of
grouping together the card since they are making individual videos or post silence crammers that I
can make cards and four people will turn this time period so for example when you
know there are a couple of birthdays coming up and of the same other and Sunday
things like that and it just means that I can
create Kant's for people as well it won't me get a bit ahead on worldmaking I
tend to make carts rather than purchase them
but I always seem to leave at the last minute some time and this will get
me really all the nicer to and I stop what parts but the and hundred thanks
to all and it is not going to be exclusively free which you can birders we
are doing a bit of traveling it were going away twice during the hundred-day parent at
least so I'm going to
especially for one of them I definitely could bring his own machine say I'm going to
leave it open said I can do things like hand embroidery
you know the things that I can paint texted you know different textiles offices so like
you to the burn into it and these different techniques reversed Peking of the king
couching all sorts things are just cut him open to apso there might be some cards
that look similar to each other isn't it is the same design but try different text
or very subtle them
but I think it will be nice because it be fairly small still quite tangible but
with a very practical so that
when it warrantee place Katz's also got some little case concepts which we say
yes the clear there will be on the video after this one of the shed it
feels a bit like we started setting up the new the new life will not Mr
clean she should be
the quantum
well we'll see how it goes
please using and export