how you welcome back today I've got my partner Phil and he's joining me today as
we thought would do a bit of well we've decided to call it a craft da-da
says that yeah it souls with the station which
yes so will go with crafty date for now but if we've changed the name in
the interim it's because we thought of something a bit better all changed our mind
so basically what we're going to do is
do some craft based activity together and so today you choose an are activity Hanako
and toward Christmas yeah yeah so we've got this a tree decoration boulting it from Bobby
craft so you choose a from hobby graft the other week than you yeah because I
didn't see it you just suddenly turned up for that and went Hey it's three pounds
will not keep polar bears get the
right
so I don't really do any crush
is a crafty one so open she used to do some life into it
open not gonna help you with felt but
I've never done needle felting either I've used an imbalanced it before and in a textiles
class
and I've tried a bit of wet belting and but not needle felting before so this
will be news both us
what we should have precontact attention and but
it's true
so we've got the instructions on the back of
the well yes and then we've got them other colors which
be for their own accessories for little to come with an older needles
that terrified the shop I can't have cut down
I was seeing my face be able to do you are they different sizes I don't
know enough about
the swallow
and that's kind of the thing I think he stabbed into I want to do Nomex
then you will say got these and so we made the shape of the pool of
us did they stay inside
I do just stop it into the phone and the Loki
he's a good question something the retreat dropped out
and then some one for it
right along the way
okay
before you get started separate out all of your felt shapes you can identify which shapes
they used for each part of the pole of as
I realized there was the same size actually I but they were like you know you
rode up once in a baby one Burgess' just
okay how to make president's times three
divide main fair father into three equal pilot heads
into the dirt away
what a separate off some of the lot of my dad was there would have the
scale that make sure they were able to get the scales there's light then I don't
know what do you think what is it not really matter what happens the scales for
the voices could be really hard to tell him into the team
right quick break
take one boarding born wrap in roving and hold walls gently stabbing in a downward motion
with unbelting me what to his ear the wall to the policy in the shape you
not stop to hearts so things just isn't too like product about with did you go
through the to
the more you felt the family or what he will be
you just you don't you like I think
when you do where felting and of have to like teach them out and makes us
shoot of its I don't know few days for the
I'm just wondering what do you think I guess maybe you don't have to such a
safe racket round as
I read the next instruction to shatter wrapper section a small section will around your thing
as in a place in the front
of the front of the head where the snow would be felt into the time
had more for that definition to that
when you got to save of it for his leg
maybe you just
because which it helps some
export I think I promise my quite nice people out you know that I might add
the more is not very big as don't quite bit less then it gets my tool
as maybe's this is like when you're making a hat
pretty sure it's like that as much I know about to
this might take while on time
yes I really so diffuse I'm
a machine based in Belisha it's like this but it's got about
six needles so it it's really with services the new carpet that you don't like Fred
but it's just a machine and he used the pedal and you can determine how quickly
the
needle punch down
so it's really nice that they're actually quite spend what they are
very good if you're doing lots of
fishing
I've never seen them the
needle thing that like this to me like
this the more you punch it with the needle the more has that so very unmuffled
effect like the front cover
so the less you can see the mines enough so it is good to practice yes
the use of so much more thicker than mine
I know that's why means you think I've been nice to know I'm pretty just as
not let alone
come to sweeten of that scene from aliens
the bishop with
white with the yeah I've seen another finger reference and
surprise yes actually as well as you requested yes making me think about that that sort
of
rhythm
use it didn't really see a kind of six bit like a hammer
we can anything
maybe we were gonna make although that the same size we are going to make like
three bears fresh
it was the rusty little discussion
and were back after a short break
was chained by clouds because this isn't taking for
welcome to day to of three decoration something hit by a hobby craft
in October yes well it's lucky we start said now yes
yes so you can see our progress gonna take the
best me to go a bit too into and
damaged his tool might be why you get to you rather than you know that the
same time that you say that's my one and you
about this
six can't support
all right thank you me down you should stop
for long time lapse snatch
the boxes the discuss
what he stop yourself the reason
I made it to bunny rabbit
got another color Maximo we will at the ties that it can be
on the Christmas tree but we need to make pale bear number three beforehand to make
sure we've got enough and
cotton for the stars on the boots
first attempt a needle felting how did you find it
took on anything suppressing the time it took
be told our in yeah be quite as this
is really fun trust you
would you get again
and but
I don't need a needle felt
no your committee necessity
I mean what she found by a panda one
red founder was bigger than quite nice level the details or
would you make a bigger
needn't not
just the base
well we're now going to take hold desert break your granny Loveman
and I'm gonna saidi up my craft table I guess
but it's a bit messy
thanks for watching