welcome to take our minds off the awful pandemic and locked down you part of a
crafty day for us to do say what to be fair you came up with that
crafty day so today we're going to make ourselves from the face was so I was
going to make them anyway and any suggested that we both make them so that's what
we're going to do today as always if you let this video and would like to
see more please I forget to like a full squad with you haven't already so it's
not a tutorial were going to follow another free tutorial were going to be using the
Italy and the buttons face mask there is so many out there I just couldn't decide
the ages which must to do which is why it's kind of thinking two months to
make us face once I mentioned in a recent catchup I did make one from my
mom I'm just because I had some not to the fabric and from making her back
to match that I thought Hey well don't make a matching fixed mask for that thing
anyway I wasn't that keen on the shape of that face Marceau I thought would try
a different one specifically one with Clete's know we're going to do there to the buttons
one but I do you have some elastic so I think we're going to substitute the
times for elastic
just because it be easier to put on a not so the first thing we need
to do at Shiva is use the iron so for an island bought a little other
one
just listen
I've got a same data
which will help so do I make to go bust to you then
I will watch you on
so the first thing we need to do is
really
important
it's a trial anyway to see if it's a good one so the first thing she
seeks to do is twofold a centimeter
in on each side and then a father once and tweeters never got there seeing gauge
which makes it a lot easier
for me anyway
because it's a nice stable caught in it being a price and it's a minister like
say I'm just gonna fight over that lets them twice wollen down this and
that's it you can see just how the
case that's one side done and then
going to do the other side that was the last time he used to serving dishes
my sewing machine
and
so you have the wrong side facing it men and your funding one sent me sit
down
I mean you've actually got gridlike fabric but press actually where the what it is instead
the top of the white square and I just so maybe repress the spences right on
the white square and then carrier
next were stitching down and please forwarded edges in place they were just stitching place to
the
inner folded at your base slide across a pro
so really just seen textless no more qualified than me
but the first
right the next thing we're doing is where
we weren't ready
right see need to bring my still working with rightsize to
so you need to fold it in half so that your to
hmms edges are at the top
there for the awesome I guess and need them matching yet that it's going up about
it so the meat
and then you gonna do
you need to find five centuries in person so it's five sentry to them and so
I'm going forward of that and that I'm using the lever's go back to implementing diddies
at the school
again all right
okay so the next thing is to press it into its shape roughly
right so I'm working out how much elastic I need so I put this off to
my face bearing might there's a one sent him to see a lance
that I've just measured that had formed in the last time
I
gonna do around the day that you might umbles which is about eighteen centimeters
waiting
but this whole real it kind of looks like I've been holding the last iha but
I had it is
specimen unfunny cheek sometimes last the clothes we went right so I felt to and then
what I'm going to do
is stop them inside
she'd be honest can do
well that's a can add a filter
so I'm just gonna put it there the bottom
right then bustle and long gonna use a patient again the main as she were gonna
have it is we have good the pleats yet but the elastic brunch and into the
nearest we might accidentally stick from the last
because my machine doesn't like this at last it that much your very best going from
the middle to the edge
to keep in mind with
the center imports the city
folks were this manics teams meeting
seven just grasslike
and now I'm going to mark where the pleats are going to be
have you ever
been around have not to sing at the time and I already clients the share that
is true I just do your in time was
right so the measurements to need back to the spirit down the side and then just
make a little parks they hope the zero to the top
like said to the dates you need to
move that talk point to the second point
and then repeat to the next to Marcus
you start with that point to the second
you are stitching the side so one sent me to away gentilities that guide it is
getting a bit funny though with the elastic again but what I do is stop a
little bit further down and then back attack over it and then stop and hopefully work
he just needs to the china surgent if you fall again half
the ever speak
to the other way about the logical the city
and then if you bring it up to hear
from one of these you just need five centimeters you need tomorrow we can use one
of the square is my second
and then you just use put it on each
and so try not to put together
we cut your precious you got you wearing quite a lot of thank you
for
the final that his pen the nose wiring
so if you go to the back of your
mask it's gotten openings that you can bet a filter in it if you want to
but this is the way to access that channel we've just created
well you know what I cannot say down
it's a good stories and been in the right
questions that
god may the tapes the heart
you need to delay
or it's not effective but some graph were
is that all right the last equity
was so close so we'll have to prepare this or camera I just stitch on the
outside
I did say needed to reported and I needed to tell an outline it was excellent
once really good to
us or so machine still is sets off
I see what people mean about and he's not steaming of the glasses
somebody told me to reinforce
after a quick
where because one but he says maybe she'd seen that
she was right but what you think of it there it's
what I can do it's Tyler or not
that's what I've done mind and I think I've done it it to time
I personally felt like this one that's much better
than the one I made my mom
yeah it seems to be quite well there I quite like the fleet's because you can
still talk
so over all I'm really happy with this face mask I did next time as you
noticed I've tried a couple of knots in my hat elastic next time I will probably
cut the elastic eventual to so that it's better and but I mean this is a
good point if you do make one with elastic and you're a bit too generous with
the elastic you can just tie a knot in it and make it shorter so I
think it's really good design and as you can see you know feel like but different
face shapes and if it's both of us which is I'm very positive I think the
pleats work well so the one I did before didn't have pleats but I think it
works well because then it has a bit a gift so that you can talk while
you or sat on
to reach him
if you want to mbs you can see like they hadn't slowed on the sewing machine
for fourteen years and even then you carry into a huge amount of saving
souls or did you
know so I mean you know you managed to make one will we see we did
have a slight debacle with the elastic and but you did manage to make answer is
a fairly to get a friendly project which is a social yeah I don't ricin if
you made it with the ties it would be more big in a friendly because that's
probably the most challenging thing because we have changed the ties to elastic it meant that
we had to be careful that we didn't stitch it into the scene I like the
fact that you can put wiring to shakes the nose it's obviously a really beneficial feature
to make sure that you've got the best of it on your mask and it's great
that you can remove it for when you want to wash it and yeah I just
think it's really nice that it's from one rectangle to it doesn't take long to cut
out the last in peace to London and yes so you have got this opening firstly
to get the wire at the top out but also you can't get a filter and
I think I don't know it's the government or I start on the BBC website but
you can use a bit of a
kitchen towel in laughter is the filter
how that works
but yeah sorry happy that I think now that we've traveled up I'd be quite happy
to and batch make a funeral
and be making another one
be
yeah but you need you need like a couple of those this one's in the wash
the Latins in the wash and this might be good as well for where we live
could there are quite a lot of narrow lanes well you can't beating me to the
what you do meet someone so it will mean that you know you could wear this
and east through that path the hair that's all crafty late for this so I'm and
a bit of a religion and them in addition there I guess it's also a so
a review for this because I don't know if anyone else and feeling this but I'm
feeling about face mask passed in overwhelm because there were so many on life I just
couldn't decide the ages which wanted to choose I really just wanted to find one that
works nicely that I could rely on and this one sets the belt so yeah I
definitely reprimand it and yeah you could definitely substitute elastic for the ties in the baston
right so I think that's it for this time you so yeah so we'll be back
soon with another video but for now thanks arching like into shrine