hello its Clary from club or creation today I thought I do a little bit of
a craft hall and over the last month I've brought a lot more than I usually
do I'm just because they're have been some authors around which I couldn't refuse so there
I've been to a few different charity shops in the local area I've also been to
hobby craft
yeah I think Oh yeah I got a couple of things from out there as well
so I'm just gonna quickly show them and let you know if I've got a project
for them or not
so the first fabric I'm going to show you I've got in Helston the other week
I haven't got much to show you because as you may be able to tell I've
already got something out of it
I can't show what I've made with it quite yet as I'm it's a person test
for someone
um yeah basically I was trying to find some nice knit fabric to use for this
I'm test pattern and fortunately and we happened to go into this charity shop on the
way back from something else and it matched the other fabric I had for this project
a lot better than the other scraps I had in my stash so
I picked this up the it's quite a nice medium-weight knit
it feels really nice and soft that was about probably just over a meter of it
no more I'm definitely not meter and a half the I have managed to squeeze out
the project I wanted for it and I'm hoping possibly to do and a headband to
go with it must be looking at the unstitch sisters ones that they've done recently as
I think it would damn much what I've done really well so yeah that's some what's
left of that fabric it already been knew straight away which is very unusual to me
the other fabric I got from Helston in a different charity shop is this
it's quite pink actually this fabric which is unusual for me and I don't tend to
wear a lot think I'm not very keen on the color pink I'd much rather wear
red
and which I'm wearing at the moment
so
I'm not sure what type of fabric it is and
I was hoping it was a crave but I'm not too sure now it's not a
soft so
not completely sure I'm going to do with it I'm thinking possibly address
but it just depends on not sure if it be to it chief or that so
I kind of need to do a bit more investigating on this spit the yard is
a fair bit of fabric air actually apartment by how much but the definitely is enough
to do address if I wanted to
the other day I went to a much place a charity shop in Penryn I think
it's called Penryn treasures and they were having sailed on their items and I managed to
pick up this lovely
rettore fabric and from there for fifty peace
I think that's about
to know whether there's a good couple of meters there and it's quite wide
it's got lovely print and and it will drape really nicely you say
again I'm not sure what I'm going to make out of it or when I'm going
to make something out of it hopefully soon and I do have other things in mind
at the moment so I think
it would probably make
quite a nice
probably quite a nice dress I guess you could do a blouse with well
nice big print on it so so I'm looking forward to you using it by just
need to find the right happen for it first I think in the charity shops as
well I was lucky enough to find some sewing patterns a lot of the charity shops
close to me anyway have really gone off and like some sewing persons the one when
there was first looking at sewing passions there they used to be really cheap but you
know tunnel twenty pee and more recently especially in firmus it's about one pound fifty to
to found and these are for persons you know which have already been used and cut
up might be torn of it
so I was really pleased to find in Penryn Carmen brought the charity shop called but
it's a newer one on the high street and I found some sowan passenger for twenty
five p which is a really good price and if it makes you you know because
sometimes you don't know it someone's cut the wise you want or not so
you might be purchasing one then then you find out part of missing or you know
you can't retrieve the size you want so yes so I've got a few
the first one I got is this make it easy and it's in a pouch
shows you how to make a trench coat plus various variations and there's also a long
nice us lace trim on there as well which is probably quite nice for the hot
weather we're having at the moment so inside it comes with
the full person thesis
it looks like someone has cut out a bit of this I'm not sure
they've made and yes and then there's the book that as well that comes with it
as well so yeah there is this lovely trenchcoat I've never made a cape before I'm
not sure if that's something I want to do with my sewing and this does look
like a lovely patterned there are lots of lovely detailed pictures for each section and ways
that you can
make them much it
also variation where they made it into a dressing gown which is why nice to see
there's also a coatdress but I don't think I'll be making
bit of the night he looked quite nice and simple safe and which is probably a
bit more realistic for my skills at a moment's
this next pattern is a butter passion and actually from fabric land which
is one of my favorite shops
with this lairing pattern I was really drawn to the design I've previously had I'm ready
to where short thoughts tops which just like the ones on the front cover and already
like that sort of uncurved and at the top and then the loose of it for
the rest of it
so I'm not sure
not completely sure what guys have been can hear or a suffice has been caught to
doesn't look like
that it's being cast a to
actually it looks like none of this person has seen that which is brilliant because it
means that
I've definitely got my size there which I think I'm the top size for this pattern
anyway
but you so for twenty five p for a baton that you know
is something that I would wear I'm really happy with that
the next one I feel like I'm I actually have this pattern from a charity shops
and which is fine because I think this is a slightly different side so I picked
this up firstly because it was only twenty five peace and and secondly because it's a
nice nyt design I might just have one similar to this I'm not sure what I
thought if I wanted to make any of the rest of my family
something for them I could
use this if it is a different size to the one I've already got I feel
like I might have the size down from this one I would they got this and
bedded there's a blouse
yet another one I'm not sure when I'm going to make that and probably more likely
to make the other talk first so
that will probably be added to my stash but the interim
the final things I picked up from this particular cherty shop is than this random pattern
so I don't know
what this was from
dozen Oh okay it's a cupcakes for Clara on then it's got coffee right from twenty
twelve so um yeah you can kind of make I mean I yeah this is a
rabbit though I'm you can make a rabbit
fastie it's called
make your own rabbits fasci or you can also make
you can also make a kitty fasces know
the choice is yours I just thought it looked like quite a nice simple
fairly simple makes they just them
and I think also
so what you do is you trace the pictures and these templates here but I think
I'm someone's already traced a bit for me he's
just need to double check it but I might already be partially left
doesn't like quite a nice sweet idea so you know it might make one of these
are my name I'm not sure now from the charity shops that I got the fifty
p fabric I also got this lovely
box and its listed as sewing patterns on that but it's not
it's actually a little compendium of different and sewing techniques just to guide you through so
I think I've got this it says to pound on the top that they actually gave
it to me for a patent
because they were having their so so yeah each bit so it's got an eight of
them on it and it's all conveniently in this little box so if I just bring
it over
and
so if I take out a for now just so I can chew what's on one
of these on each and card for the
letter so for a its call all of them listed for
alterations to patterns and then it lists the cards that you need to go to to
look at alterations farmhold back bust combining two patterns all of those are down there on
left and and there's also for a plea case so then
in front of them is all of the cards for a so on the front you
can see there's the armhole
alterations that you can look at so
and then on the back there's alterations to passions
which its own card a one
just though I mean I have got some older
sewing books from charity shop and I think I've got one from my name as well
and that this just looks quite nice if you want to to quick reference you can
just get away at which
which techniques I want to look at I quite like that I know I've seen one
I think it's under said
on the god for that it's got
and Zip's at the very top one is avoiding them so if you really don't want
to make is it it gives you advice on defending what you're making how you can
go about
creating a different fastening or avoiding a fastening altogether
say I was really pleased with this and I just think it looks really sweet and
it's a lovely archive that I can look through when I'm
if I get stuck on the pattern or I am quite interested with with that I'm
combining two patterns one say it's definitely worth having a flip through
so the rest of my whole is from holy Crafton as to say
a lot of my stuff was from the church choked normally I have been trying to
buy less fabric just because I've made flat and there's a lot less storage space all
they
there a look there are more benefits to living in this flat it does mean that
I can't store things the same way you see and this means that my fabric stash
does need to go down drastically
anyway so I'm gonna show you the stuff from hobby craft they had a sale I
think it was last month so probably the start a last months I bought these
so the first thing I got it's a bit creased because I need to iron it
is this lovely into the woods
cotton fabric so
actually got more than I think I asked for it was near the end of the
role
so it's fairly in I mean it feels really soft so I'm just wondering what to
make that why they're going to make something for my knee perhaps the dress
or otherwise I'm just trying to work out if it's some it cannot to make some
crops and pajama bottoms will cut from a short
if it's got on the side where it's from
from unholy craft anyway
and it was half price I think it was for found to me to say
I asked for me to but I think I've got about meter and after
the other fabric and the same collection which I'll have to look up and link
I got this
I think I've just got to me to hear because it was at the end of
the rock and again it goes of the and bare and
fox designs got head shrugs and leaves on can I just thought it is really pretty
and it's probably something I'll make
and something for my niece with whether it's a garment or making a bag for her
I'm not completely sure yet the final thing I got from where we craft is this
huge would of jersey fabric now this jersey fabric was half price I think it's normally
eight pounds and meter but I got it for for pans a meter which is a
really good price
and so it it looks like a single net but you can see the pile on
the back and I asked before meters although I think I've got about four and a
half metres saying that I have seen a stain on it which I probably won't find
now but
so I'm a bit disappointed with that but saying that is still benefited from an extra
half meter so as long as I can cut out what I want that fine I'm
torn between making a journey dress a cocoa dress or perhaps and another Molly dress
there's also I've got and Wendy was sewing with nets book so I'm wondering whether to
make the t-shirt dress out of that as well so
that have been looking for a lovely starky fabric for ages I'm now
wondering what to make with it just because
I probably make to dress about this or I'm hoping I can because it is a
wide fabric it's just I'm deciding which two dresses to make below probably be dresses
and that's as far as I've got finally the Brandon once my craft whole is and
that I got these from asda so the
sheet
these bar sheets are a hundred sense meters wide by a hundred and fifty cents meters
and they were half priced so I think there were four pounds each now what I
want to make with these I've made a couple of beach dresses and I've recently resorted
to hours just because telling fabrics really expensive I don't live near any
major fabric shocks
so I wanted to make another beach dress but I didn't want it to be an
already bland color so I made this yellow one the other month we want to to
again so following that I've seen some people who he was
wearing these really nice
towel throw over there thought of I mean a lot of the ones I've seen have
heard I don't know sir only want one with his but the gullibly sort of kimono
sleeves on them so you can just throw on after you've been in the sea and
as I live really close to the sea I thought it would be really nice to
make one of those so
I do have a plan for these at least and the I just thought four pounds
for a meter of a
meter of fabric is really good and then I sinned callable so that's why bought those
two
okay well that's everything for this time I hope you've enjoyed it and hope the will
be vaccine to show you what I've made with these things thanks