welcome
hello today we're going to show you how to make your own Christmas breach like so
it's also our second crafty date so we did one last year when we did needle
felt and bears which took absolutely hours so we thought we'd go for a bit of
a quicker one this year because it seems to be an annual thing at the moment
and Christmas think she was a crystal hopefully but will sleep because I kind of locked
up this tutorial and the last time we use the natural kit that we got from
hobby craft this time I've made something up so this will happily be a template which
you can download from my website so you'll be completely from and then you can either
follow along with the video or I try and give some really simple directions on the
website in a bog placed so today we're making some Christmas themes breeches so I've just
done to designed for now I do have other riders in my head a bit just
something like some simple issue so see you we've got a Christmas Google that you can
make and so this would just be you know you can pin it on to your
told Paul your bag just just a little mini festive
embellishment and there's also a Christmas looking breach I guess it's one of those things you
know might get they lost on the top like feels wearing today but you know if
you work sunlight it like those place to work where they don't want you to be
too fast of at work we could probably get away with a little fragile brooch which
had the little marker of Christmas is coming but you know it they weren't quite ready
for folds the jump or the other day that's just let's just put it that way
and told him he was too early and you can only why our own Christmas trumpety
this is another which is a resealing one day in the year which is a bit
of a waste of you forget
what every day to set the
right let's get started so the first we were going to do the prince ah-ah-ah fickle
Pete of my lovely template
which designs you want to do you want to the Google all the stocking stock yeah
okay so the first thing that I'd like you to do is pick out what felt
you want the main bit of the stocking in and then the top bring peace this
is my during box in the felt scraps and
pieces
I can't believe I've got this much felt actually I'm surprised okay
what Collins you won't stick of sucking and engineering
sort it
I'll do the other design and
that your and made intension
they will be fast ever know that's why not Suckley yeah maybe all means that and
I need a bit so well my design which you don't seem act of lump-sum top
but you need a little bit for the top of the bubble of you there maybe
I just use a bit white pullup yeah so I mean this step is and slightly
optional but what we're going to do is were actually going to trace out the first
template and all that box was really dirty
and we're going to be the first one on the left each so you're going to
trace out to a pair of these so one this way one in reverse better but
it will be on interfacing so I'm just gonna use some interfacing because it will strengthen
about although saying that I don't know if you really need to use of you probably
could get away with it but it will just help give a bit more structure
yeah and it easier to trace I've got a really to
its basic
so as you shall I show you what to do what I want you here obviously
try to keep your interfacing nicely bolded and then it won't get really Greece like this
right so I'm just gonna hold it over
mechanical answer
I'm going to get
there actually with my design it probably doesn't master too much with her
but the designer let's try to the other way because it's
a symmetrical design or oversee or quite match African at one side
you have to the same way I'll just don't cut the
yeah I'm never really sure if anyone knows let me know that within to facing I
just want to sit but blue water that so I basic because I accidentally bought an
extra couple of hers that dress-making scissors when I didn't notice they were right friend took
me once and I'm using like a cheap peril dress-making Sissons to cut this out but
I do sometimes wonder if you're better using regular systems or whether it would want them
so I just need to see you can start to tracing yours so
are you happy with that you
so I put the in spacing as and it's my lovely old and facing so it's
coming away from the city lights on away from the cake side and I'm just going
to
check the interesting and the enticing
basally I'm going to
write so what you're doing that I'm going to I in my not as I'm going
to do some decoration on my Christmas Google just the hands searching before I said that
events together did you want to decorate your stocking it
where you coats were clad beads you could do some random stitching so I might do
some cross-stitch some stitches you could do a line of running stitch
or wandering is making sure the shiny side of my interfacing is facing the out and
then I'm just going to iron this on to the felt pieces
just going to
labor something
to this general election
but the shiny slide down yet yet shiny shut up
yeah so if you just at that right on something I hold it down safe about
eight seconds but it might need more last endings anywhere we have to me that after
that
your custom although and I cut out the top section which is the middle template on
the Christmas bawble template and I dressed that one to of it Wanda web
and and I'm just going to attach that to mess around a bit of white folks
for the top I just got to be careful but
as I say this hasn't actually
because my stuff so old good to get it the glue attached to my iron which
will be great see how the wonder what stage is entirely optional so you could tell
us
underwent sticky on both sides so it's got a sticky side what is two layers so
there's a sticky by this quite a demonstration this is a bit it's come away it's
just the sticky Bob which attaches to the belt and this is the paper bet so
you draw wherever you want to
cost that so you can do really accurate looking out on you draw on that section
and then you
cut it out so normally this would be attached together because my Bondo ever so old
it's come away
and you either with the paper side up
and then you cut out the template and then you
here away the paper section and then you attach then you can attach it to another
bit fabric
and then only reinforced with some stitching because it might not stay on this
don't know in on this layer
which is why did the paper for the first time you take it for the first
side and then it should be sandwich between fabric for the second won the bet you've
just you mind so far as the interfacings so that just gives more structures with fabric
so there's only one sticky sighed
very
right so the next step for you is to use a bit of my relief bold
really on
this is big and affection
with another of this
you can let the trees after that lower down but it all things to
yes if you just want to trace that see if you draw up again yes the
to
stand up
the I'm just going to attach to talk my global so I held the paper they
are my that
yes you have to hold it as she got out
of that the rest sorry if you get like a fresh there when he said
Mike say you don't have to do this you could adjust trace that you know could
have traced the template drawn into felt after and by that it's just I'm just makes
it easier sissy have to stop my not
so it just means that it's not going to move when I had to my decoration
right so you need to say with your contrast fabrics of the Korean superbly up here
somewhere
what I'd recommend it is putting this sphere so if you come over to the iron
and then I'd recommend
so yeah
like station for a farm but saying need that flower savoys it come out the shape
to one
and put that right over the top but the extra cautious with my own they will
be caught of the
yeah
yeah then just again like before just put the eyes on for a few seconds until
it's
what you're cutting out and just going to trace the cardboard peace for my one so
just to give it more structure after the interim going to add some cardboards between the
two days just because it is a brooch and
just give him in more structure so I'm just going to
trace around them something on the right so when they got one and card
say you if you were patchy yet we do need the only so if you want
to press that is at the front of your obviously
everyone's you won't press that into the top see I just change whatever when I got
out begun to be the front
yes you now quite that way I've done that many times when I positioned it
just how I wanted it and then realize I left the paper so it wouldn't stick
discretion just one
right so do you want to trace out your the couple with the middle
yeah so can you see through the paper
see if you just done trace around that
that's what I've just done in the speckle about and I've got his a strap in
of powdered I say from the reciting
I guess you could also just got up from this paper
you will
have to go someplace so I just talk my not see him cut out cried not
say what I did what I placed my sampler over a and then drew round up
so obviously you could just make this to make the Christmas decoration c-could stitches to what
together as a
at a bit tearing at the top and then it could be it could be a
Judy decoration Beatrice or anywhere up to a tangled wooden brooch we will need to attach
a brooch piece on the fact so what you will need us to get them back
peace if you're doing a bridge so I got these and have retained
right so you do you want to separate you're so
yeah
they're well I'm gonna add some decoration on mine so I'll get this round out as
you'll get to go around your
okay so I chose then some orange stars and some white thread from mine so what
I'm going to do is sign the and
the way or used in broideries red is there are six friends
in a bit of in the
light so I separate two strands from the rest of the bunch so
why not necessarily x that way of doing it
trying to put my thumb through where I'm dividing
again with the two strands that I've selected I just make sure it's untangled
going to grab the needle
the way of Lanta I don't know this is to do with cross stitch or whoever
taught me but
I get the two ends to meet
and then not in the bottom
right so I've got my from peace and which I need with the added the white
top that of the global elaboration so I'm just going to add
some simple
cross to looking
so what you could do here is you could draw so using
friction pin or you know a
fabric and circle like this one which banishes gradually in the air will you know I'm
ones that disappear when you add water to it
so I'm doing slightly different cross-stitch cuz I want them to be separate crosses on the
room
so what I've done has just gone a long and done
one side of the crops and then I'm just going to go up
just like crossed it truly
down so another option if you do want to decorate
either this one or you destocking is to do some free machine and broidery on the
same machine or you could even use some of the supreme set stitches on your mushing
in this meshing to got one with a huge range of decorative stitches what I would
recommend though is perhaps drawing out the shape of the design ordered to the fabric but
maybe not cutting it out straight away just to you've got
more fabric to move with and then you can cut the actual shape at
once you get your decoration on that
case I don't rather wanky looking and were as such as that but never mind the
building that so what you need to do next is do you want to add any
I'm order these out like stitching to secure your green peas
so you can either do something like a backstitch you're running stitch or blanket still it
would look a bit different on back the way to the edge
I avoided this when you went there and I know in the class the of the
day we did three strands and then we just like no one and but what I
do as I used to you strands and then I get the two and its to
meet a possemen doing up see you in love with for strength so it's so I
divide up I pick out the two and I put my thumb through
the can left that attached
right so I've got a little back feet it's really smaller so happily will hold so
this is field backpiece I just got be easier to sit down before you want the
cardboard and stitch it together so what you need to do is
you do that prudishly it's just position it where you want it to go wriggly someone
like
and then you see without whole lives in the middle get to just stitch several times
on this side and you like coming through it now
and then go to the side you and do the same until it feels really secure
that you can't get there over the hole for the invite you stay hold this terrible
right so I've got a bigger for each back so it's got three old
interruptions
and
we won't go to get so we went to get someone to get some so brings
you
got so go back touch
okay so we're gonna attach to the better carpels but I don't any the way stairs
just use that double side it takes it's not like we can wash this right so
I'd recommend pissing your crumpled but only flat next now that the bridge sex by hard
to the touch so you want it really central the got a nice even border on
the edge
yeah yeah just make sure those two
pieces from send us
right the just Carter's school back just to it facts are just gonna adat one side
and sped toward
came and the bed that was I to take to this side it's okay kids you
can of own but
I just go be easy to use the flat piece
with a bit harder on the shiny side of the cobbled
really
busy nourished there and you were
right so what situla wants to run the edge
the free of to do it smaller than
discuss the carcass in the way so again you could make this without gargled in the
middle I just think it gives their level structure
back fast
enough
on the other one I made intubated chain stitch
its cause of brought a Christmas decoration I'm going to add a little better one of
the sort that young to be like the leap the other down to
cut the string on the top of the bubble
tree
for a dancer's to us recording this really is
what coast in don't forget to like unsubscribe
very I almost got it in your stocking
so here's another one I made the only test when I did before we were hunters
and so is another bubble decoration here but I've actually done three machine embroidery which I'll
add a little video of me doing that and what I would recommend if you are
using machine stitches or doing free machine and broke broidery is to not cut the bauble
and design out straight away maybe trace that honors you know where it where the order
will be but then if you've still got it on your piece about will be a
lot easier to move the fabric ground and the and spacing felt help if you're doing
through machine broidery and having that one back you about because then you don't need a
hoot is the who could damage the belt and that will be Sefer just doing regular
stitches there are a lot of beautiful preset stitches on sewing machines so you could just
do some really nice lines on that just add a bit of detail and but yeah
I would keep it on the main bit of felt because otherwise and they could get
chewed up by the machine at the ends to just something to bear in mind okay
so that's it for today O'ahu enjoyed this video and were probably try and a record
another one scene we're at she got another ideas we might not wait another year but
what we do another craft they
knew so this is a nice little simple idea that you could do it if you
want to add a little not towards Christmas and to join in the festivities if you
don't want to go on a low in a job like this
and yet so that's it for today thanks torching that you to like us to strike