hello today I'm excited to share with you some of the craft items I've acquired over
the last two or three months okay so I think I'll start off with the fabric
that's I were quiet so a lot of this is from charity shops I haven't any
fabric I'm on the meter for
probably all year actually can I am trying not to buy any fabric so the first
one
is this father
is increased but it's a lovely sort of
its got that crinkled effect I'm assuming it's fantastic and I think that would make a
lovely dress
I'm not important in
the other side of table
next that is this lovely bold floral prints
fairly sure cotton or it's definitely of cotton blend I say yes of this lovely old
print
again I mean there's not a huge amount of fabrics so
that's the widow
pearly-white actually
not quite a meter and a half so
yes it will be interesting to see if I can get something out but obviously would
be lovely it's not all definitely at the scarce out of this so get I'm really
pleased with the spin fabric it came actually the fall from the same charity shop them
somewhat oversee generously donated these fabrics in the next one is this nothing on this one
actually since it is a fine great
love it when they are so which don't you want the of fabric and so as
you can see it's
a lovely black wanting great again this there's actually a fair amount it in this piece
of well I'd say he's fully about a couple of meters so I'm gonna see public
through my patterns
possibly
possibly make dress and
although I've really got into you making blouses since I made the silly in the Aston's
boat laws and I'm also made
and other plans before so
quite tempted I do have some loughs pattens so all have a think about it to
the next one and as a ferret this fabric actually
it's only see I'm being caught up for another project and it's still of navy it
feels really stuffed lacily this again thing it probably is a Carson yeah I have no
idea I'm gonna make with this actually it probably would make my stressed and
makes a nice trousers to be honest and there's probably enough there I'll have to think
about it the next I said this isn't actually from
I don't know this from which I shook my mom gave it's me and
it's either a tablecloth that and city is basically a late stable of so it's either
one that she's owned and no one wants to use or it is
from a china shop and she thought should do something with a hazard so the either
with this I am temp's to keep it as the table loss but I think all
the adventurous
and essentially I want to cut it one of the corners
is used and we need to wash this actually I can't want to make something that
wraps over
white be using a pastor for that I'm going to make up the go along but
they do need to think about how I'm going to
make that work so yeah pretty something I should leasing will the weather still nice and
the
I guess so from that same charity job names they had where I seeing a person's
as well so I was very lucky but several so I got this I'm in its
white a sense of water is
yes is Mrs followers and capelets with trim variation stiff and if you can see there's
I'm some lovely variety to choose from them it is actually not in my size range
but it's only just out with my size range and I'm seeing where people have traded
it down to them so I probably looked into that the next pattern is this new
look to six for double one and if they keep the omit rigid great and so
on this one actually recommends the crate
what I like about this is it does have
it doesn't have sessions leaves they look more right and shape yeah it looks like a
really nice simple make and that all good to making a look more like a wintry
pattens the next one I was very excited when I found this it is the true
but create beginner person so and she I think I might have been thinking of making
this with the black fine great not complete you to all the like I say
yeah just it looks really nice that's the problem neck by institute from so that's like
a skims bronze neckline and the little service we hope neckline
the sash around the waist I think this would be lovely again probably best told a
big somewhere on winter cool seasons really the naked
make it warmed by wearing
you know types with it so yeah I'm really looking forward to trying this person out
I'm not sure I try to let them actually I thought about trying and testing that
with the breed and they've got that soul better talk I looked into making that by
then I made it sick haven't started it all
so yeah I look voice trying out that person
the next one is
simplicity ten eighteen I got when I pasted this on Instagram itchily I got a lot
of comments that people really liked this pattern so it kind of looks quite like my
style as well I'm and I'm probably used up some scraps looks like there's a nice
bit of you know you using different passing combinations together to make this or you know
it works well in the fullness sleep anyway so deeply it will work with whatever fabric
five brought in my stash he'll be that different anyway even it happen I've got is
the simplicity Kate one tree seven see this is some ple stk ate one of three
seven again and and lovely-looking wrap dress and there's also a top variation so having a
little again actually this would work with
a lot of the fabrics I've just showed you so again quite something I just have
to check on the amount of fabric you need because
it looks like you need a fair amount of during the room dress so I'm not
I would have enough for all of these but again it's always worth even straight out
of all the person leasable camass and you might still be up to fit them in
the fabric by tweaking the pass and layout right the next one really quite the
on this one as well is the anarchist tunic my simple so I really like the
look of death again I'm thinking possibly for the autumn winter
and then at the moment because it is really warm and it actually takes my mother's
dash within again they are from a charity shop to
got a couple of fabric choices for
which is nice I'm from within its but very think so square Jack define it
which I think would go quite nicely with it
I've also got
this fabric which I think
would be really nice however it's in the left fabric and I'm not sure how that
would affect the pattern because it is designed for woven I mean it's quite a stable
was like quite disable it
and then Stephanie in a fabric hair but I look really sure I might just use
this for
and its past Incas' its face that I've got enough of them by still want to
make so so yeah I'm gonna think about that is this one person that I got
from that charity shop and that is it so that was clearly stuck up the months
scope when I went at him it's the Juliet tieback about another simple say one and
another one on and from that people commented was a nice make it looks nice and
simple which it took from simple thing now I did get more Cassian's over the last
couple of months so my partner I think the next time
we traveled to the sound he then
he went to get a haircut because he doesn't like it lit up in call me
where we are and just gussy isn't found a bothers that he really like I said
he got his hair caught once in the sound and now he just weeks tilting back
and in the area to get her cot against so
I guess we'll have to visit every couple of months to make sure that it doesn't
get really
anyway so if you got two persons the first ones bird is seven and three seven
three and which is there's a top of the scope Darien and address not quite high
neckline and
but I quite like the style so I think I would like how to go about
so I'm and he also found
the seven for eight nine and which is another wrap-up addressed by the looks of it
so
the one I could use that and I'm grateful
I'm sure it work with some of the other fabrics as well answer that I did
find some patterns locally as well in a charts show and probably only last week actually
so I got a nice and I've got a long one on the way no
children I picked up a fairly tackety looking
copy of McCalls printed out and seven seven eight three and which is a big side
so I can only make the
one denied to age three
this is something else I faced it all in scrab about and I don't realize till
I came home that this passage or says suitable kitchen and in the bottom corner it's
very small but um yeah
I didn't she noted that on this one first is because I noticed it on
one of the other passengers Yep so I will say what the Macau's nineteen for nine
printed method which is another dress
but this one at the bottom is not suitable for traffic this snow and that breaks
from the nineteen of sixties
explains
a lot
fortunately things have changed these days
yeah they are all twelve the fact they felt that they could
print that the person and has even a beside the one that in suit but which
Abby suddenly how you can address the person for the for the top of your child
Ya-Ya interesting so actually I've already made a spots on this passen the one souple creature
me and I'm doing variation see witches if you can see there's a top and short
aspersion so I thought that would be nice for my niece putties around that age and
I had a nice fabric that I got a while ago in from hobby crying about
a year ago this cabin it takes Peter to think through my fabric traces and the
can hide in all my love refashions like so yeah so far it's a really simple
make actually I'm so the shorts a lot of complicated than you think that's got a
front waistband
and then its last cases in the back sections of the shorts it's also got
yet it's got a plate on either side of the front piece of the shops as
well
and the
and at the top has got a sit in the back in the center back so
so yeah bit more involved than I thought it would be all they saying that it's
um sewing up really quick which is great because I haven't seen anything I'm recently for
a bit so it's helping me get back into sewing and also I'm using a really
stable kosten so I'm not having many issues at all the lockers like I'm fine I
mean such would
hopefully it will carry on the unfined so yes so then
you the one more suitable Tommy's and has different address versions will ever you make this
August think will be a little bit
for my niece
here then there's this other one is why which she had a lower place in the
front and papillae so yes in this one's buster it five three six to there's no
reference and I'll bake the time but let's just say that and then you I did
get a couple of
adult pattens so I got this dress which I spot a nice and band at the
top at the neckline
and Oh yes this is the past that I was
also thinking of making as she is not and then one either better sheet might go
nice with the
oval of fabric I should previously like nicely with this fabric is this
simplicity eight to hate to see from nineteen sixty night
so yeah I think that would be really nice again probably more autumn winter-time but yeah
I really would like to make that one their necks licensing gonna show a ones that
been given to me I'm due to
and someone clearing out for this lovely item
I have tried on I think what I will do boat is I'm going to I'm
in a tenant something else as I ah probably cost it up maybe undo the scenes
I really like the fabric and I think how it currently is I probably make their
long he saw them but I would devotee get his elbows something else with this fabric
and and it's a lovely front it did run a lot though when I watched it
so I'll have to keep that in mind I also got a couple of house
so with these I would like to make one of those cover-up things like a penguins
our group is from a book called made for baby
I first pneumatic setting is in a magazine I'd bought and they have the past in
them but I can't find the page you get little the templates on so I reserved
it in the library so that I can get the person visas so you can to
make that for my new knees who is due to
I'm not sure if these tales of wideness the that's the only problem I do have
a bit of white toweling left over from when I make it my head out urban
which is another video that you can watch where you have a maker and you can
found this pattern on my websites
yeah I will say god to moments of yellow so I'm thinking I'm probably gonna make
it looked like a pinguin just one person and but yeah high clocker with that seen
the books now available selections the next time ago to the library of the up to
pick that up yeah I go given this is in Brandom the fabric it isn't it
got like a fuzzy texture on it since it's lovely again another book design
was obviously not losing probably about the quarter of the meter is the length and oversee
it spend wide snake I probably does me in the project with this I thought about
it's an enemy spit well this is definitely has some
of what some of this so I don't know I might make a bag of everyone
make
that urachal anything like that I still got one that I can finishes area those are
passing and there as well so
potential one to make my niece I guess a while is in the three but
I don't think I haven't
you need for all their twenty Raffles
actually I do have a bit of three like it would be in a cream life
and I hoped all my sister would appreciate that night I've just got scraps really so
gone on for officinal
the same
perduring you which is always useful
Sullustan where the opulent it's a drastic measure and cause of any so it's all so
than
boxes while which assaults of embroidery thread it for a
bigger
needles and and various one's got a symbol
safety net sat up and the others also
this this has got Stokeley needle them and it's a really good base for as well
yes though I've also got this organizer so I put all of my embroidery thread by
of myself into here so my incorporate some of the other friends to go I've just
kind of roughly put them with similar colors and I found this really useful because I'm
recently I made
hand in bed a typical and it was much easier to and the colors I needed
so yeah I got given this as well as part of that clear up see it
that's all I've really got to say this time and underrate having it through things so
yeah happily all get when making some of the boutons like example and a start up
with the toddler passions and use up some of my fabric ronins doing that
but you have it for now fence watching