hello today I'm going to go through the top tips that I have the crafting with
the credit illness so oversee there are lots of different chronic illnesses and that one that
I've got is not really a graphic ankylosing spondylitis which are all
from now on described as a yes because it's a lot quicker and harder to mispronounce
so with asked it's an autoimmune disease it's also so a form of arthritis it's essentially
where your body's attacking your spine and which in the end results in the worst from
your spine fuzing so as a result there's a lot of chronic pain involved and not
just in the spine it can effect on that for a free joints including your iris
and which I think I've mentioned briefly as a previous video so the main issue that
I have is that I get extreme fatigue and I do have to monitor so that
I don't get I have bad pain symptoms as well
so anyway it's these tips are what I personally find useful obviously anyone who has a
chronic illness or anyone you know dealing I'm with an ownness at the time there it's
obviously I'm trial and error to just to point out what works for and these are
just the things that I personally found useful and I thought I would share its I'm
gonna go through six different points so the first one is to do your physio exercises
so this doesn't sound very crop paste and but I do feel like it strongly linked
my productivity and how productive I am with my craft
when I first got like those with us and before I got diagnosed with the as
I did have fideo exciters I've been to physio on two occasions that two different hospitals
and I've got to be honest when I finally started going to regular Hugo lessons and
then after that I started really taking my physio and stretches and strengthening exercises seriously I
found a significant improvement in my symptoms I still get really tired and I am not
completely without pain all the time I do find that if I do my physio exercises
I feel so much better
now it is I don't do by the zero structures but say but I do follow
the yoga mat Adrian YouTube channel I find this really useful because a lot of the
exercises with in yoga linked to what your taught at physio and a lot of them
are really good feel bad and you know stretching out your hamstrings which can in turn
affect your and how you're back and your posture works so what I do is I'm
will lead with a done channel they provide you with a free calendar and suggests videos
that you can do that each thing so essentially I don't need to think I just
need to follow this calendar she tends to
put them in a plate list as well so it's really easy to find the videos
the role in order and you just need to pick the next one the next day
so I find this really helps because I don't need to think about it keeps it
very because I don't necessarily know what I'm what exercises I'm going to do the next
day it also means that their exercises very so that I'm not just doing the same
ones all the times
the second if I've got it is too it's more I guess I mean paste and
is to cut your fabric on a stable when I first and she is before I
but I goes with the s probably a year and a half before I was making
this and each dress cover up so made up town in fabric and had by sliding
all around the edges and on the top of the pockets
and I did all the talking of the bias been doing I cut it all out
on the floor I text it all on the floor and then I had to attack
the zip up into place when I talked the vivid place I got what about like
sciatica
then I went on a working all the day and just had to face up on
coucal to get through it and which in hindsight probably was the early symptoms of a
us but since then I have started I found that my tolerance to casting on the
floor was a lot short and so I couldn't spend prolonged periods cutting out the fort
Wayne angle so I started using a table to cut out fabric which had been put
off with it before just because you're I felt that you'd been limited by the sides
of the table and that's you know I'm it might be harder and some wake of
the least on the floor and it can lay all out there are slightly depending on
not much both spaces caught and but this isn't the case I'm there's lots of good
techniques that you can apply you know to make sure that say if you're using a
stretch fabric that you put a child is that it doesn't I'm any of the handle
just stretch and just thought the fabric out of shape
and yeah I found it's really useful don't really go back to the cotton on the
floor unless I really have to and its normally right I see yet I've found that
that's being really useful and I definitely recommend it if you do a lot of sewing
even if you have to uniquely the time one table brief later and to use that
in between meals or something like that can my third tip is to commit to fifteen
minutes of crafting a day so as I mentioned of the to a big issue with
a and other results I find that this affects my motivations him to pursue and complete
projects so what I did I think just over a year ago and the stark both
twenty eighteen I decided to commit to fifteen minutes of serving a day I found this
really useful because it feels like a manageable chunk of time so even if I'm feeling
really shattered
I think Oh okay I got fifteen minutes Oh it's just in attacking this seemed together
on I'm gonna save this particular seem
all you know if you're if you trace your passes it could be tracing out of
and you know one of the pattern pieces it does mean that it you know it
takes longer to complete a project and theoretically they're saying that you know if you're pissing
of crafting because you know you're feeling so side it means that you're not getting started
with a straight away anyway and you might find yourself more during by spending a really
other day just solely crafting so in my personal parent second that I was more productive
I actually got some projects off the ground and completed
and yeah just I'm I guess it's a bit more energizing in one respect especially if
you restrict yourself to that fifteen minutes because then it kind of inquirers because you want
to do more but if you go note that's all I'm doing you look forward to
the next chunk the next day and see it's worth trying out with that especially if
you are circling with motivation to the next to it number four is more to do
with if you do so for propped the long periods of time is to set a
timer to ensure that you do pause and stretch out so I'm do about my own
criticalness with a as and because your spine is ultimately going to fuse together one of
the main preventative measures is to ensure that you retain good postures so that you know
if it does a fuse like as to be stupid and I straight back because historically
that's I'm you know it's known as Mandy spine and
says that classic hunched posture so
recently to be very careful that my everyday activities I've got good foster so naturally you
know sitting hunched over a desk going it when I'm cutting out fabric or slumped over
the sewing machine and even you know listing all crocin in front of the TV it's
very easy to search and you know get all twisted round and to not have a
brilliant posture so having an alarm going off just kind of remind you to pause you
know maybe do some stretches even if they'll you know the ones you they recommend you
doing an office you know during some twists all that in your chair so that can
really help just and prevent any damage occurring while you're crafting because it didn't number fibers
to monitor your thoughts and be kind to yourself I think it's very easy to get
stuck in a ruts and also and the virally negative thoughts especially if you are an
overachiever so I think the hardest part of my diagnosis is that my mind still wants
to do a hundred different things and it's really inspired and motivated but my body is
not necessarily keeping up with my mindset
and this in turn then makes me feel a bit defeated when I don't get you
know my really long chanceless completed so I mean realistically this is good advice with anyone
not just someone with chronic pain or chronic illness but it is worth noticing those thoughts
because they're not going to help you craft as the long run it's gonna make you
think are well there's no point be doing it because you know
I can only achieve that you know x amount I want to achieve twice as much
in that time but you know you can only do what you can at a particular
point and
treating yourself harshly and with the way you're talking to some internally it's not going to
help that so I just just be fine to yourself trick us off like you would
a friend as they say and even just observing these negative thoughts can really help you
you know take a step back and notice what you're doing this probably isn't a problem
for everyone but I certainly find the you know I want to do more than I
can and then I'm annoyed at myself but there's not a lot I could do about
it and its best just
you know look after yourself in the final point I felt like I friend someone once
when I was trying to look at waits to
deal with their crashes or I like to say flops that happen so with the fatigue
sometimes I just have a complete crash and this onliest when I'm kind of sprawled out
on this over I've just blocked and I got this from me and not making a
lot to drinks and I just can't do anything so a good idea is to have
some sort of
coping station if that makes sense so and what I've got it I've got my what
at the moment I've got my missing his so it means that if I do drop
normally
I might be able to do a popular reason missing so this is them to sleep
with a guard gonna make at the moment which I started at the beginning
so it's taking a wall and
and anything else to leak how to knit your medication if you take it than
any other things that will provide you with some further perhaps you know he had a
seeker apply it to anyway you brought pain
the remote control so that you can watch something and the I do find that even
having a bit of craft material telling Nick have a bit of hand to broidery it
might be that you can't face going up to the same machine to field shaft into
that it might be that you can you know
do a few and it's a hand in bawdry well you can create a
couple of rounds
even you know have a book here just you can read and that because
you know unfortunately these crashes do happen but it's good to
and plan for them so that you don't feel that but when they do have a
cutting the thing I was ready for this and and then you can just accept the
crash and then hopefully it won't take us long to recover from it in case that's
all the tips of got to provide for Nell and so I hope this is abuse
and some of you I'd like to say I do find the musical personally I might
not follow them all the time but I do have these strategies their own place if
I do need them
thanks watching and seizing