hello today I'm going to share a tutorial with you on how to make a water
bottle carrier as always if you enjoy the video please don't forget to like it the
subscribe if you haven't already so here on the table I've got all of the fabric
pieces that I need already and cut out but I'll just quickly go through how I
measured up those pieces the first measurement I took was the height of the water bottle
so basically from the base up until the point I wanted the main bit of the
carrier to go up to and the other measurement I took was the circumference at the
widest point around the water bottle so the first piece that I caught out with the
outer peace so you caught one of these in your main fabric and I added a
feasible police to mind just because I had a bit spare from when I made my
I'm shoulder back in order to work out the width of the outer peace I calculated
the circumference and then added to lots of seam allowance so on mine I believe I
used a one centimeter same Alonso I just added two centimeters to the measurements for the
circumference Stouffer the height I did the heightened centimeters past two centimeters from my to lots
the seam allowance and then I added to lots of one point two centimeters because that's
how big I wanted the casing to be the next piece I measured out was the
lining so I caught one of these in the lining fabric I didn't put any fuel
police on this piece so for the what I did the circumference measurement again plus the
seamount and for the length of it I did that height measurement plus two lots of
the same allowance the next pieces I cut out with the basis for both the outer
peace and the lining so for this I took the circumference measurement divided it by pie
which is three point one for then with the answer to that I divided it by
two to get the radius of my circle and and then I added one lot of
seam allowance I'm just because I was using a compass to draw this out so that
just gave me an idea on how to measure it out using the radius next I
cut out the strap basis so for this you need to cut out to in the
main fabric and to in the lining fabric and interface all of the pieces just to
give it a bit more strength so you need to cut it to the desired voice
over this you need to cut it to the width of your darings and also the
desired length you want it to be once folded over and be sure to add the
seam allowance on both the with and the height the final pieces that I cut worth
of the strap so I caught one in the main fabric and one in the lining
fabric again I used in facing just to strengthen both bits of fabric or so it's
good to mention that you will also need to D-rings and which will oversee affect them
with of the straps and the starbases to swivel clasps which a correspondent with a slider
again will need to be a similar measurement to the D-rings and swingle clasps and you'll
also need a short length of elastic to put around the top your bottle I don't
actually think this step is necessary so you could leave out the elastic bit and to
be honest to be a lot easier because that was the hardest part so to begin
with you need to stitch the side seam of the outer peace and the side seam
of the lining peace the lining is a bit longer just because it holds down I'm
and has the elastic casing section so there I am just I'm I'm using quilting pegs
just because it's a little bit quicker
and then I've taken it off to the sewing machine to so those seems down so
although mentioned I've used a small team of one centimeter that you could do it and
wider all shorten that handing him like and then I've just trimmed it with the pinking
shears just because you don't want to much bulk on that now because I've used quite
a different lining fabric I have had to then change over to a different threatened bobbing
so I'll be doing a lot dropping changing during this
so after that I then pressed the seams out so let that lie flat
right so next I folded down the top edge of the lining peace so I've roaded
it down so that I've got the elastic casing section folded down and the seam allowance
so you can see I'm using my seem go chair which I mentioned in a previous
bit video that I might like to use and it's just a nice quick reference and
if you don't want to use your take measure and but obviously a tape measure is
just as easy to use
okay so after that I then folded down the seam allowance for the out of fabric
so again so this was only one centimeter I would say actually it's probably a bit
easier and gives you a bit more margin for error if you
increase the simulants at the top of it just because it might be a bit easier
to unstitch it all together at the end
just something to bear in mind
see yeah so I pressed that will down but because I had the fusible fleece on
it it wasn't really holding itself down that well especially because it's only a one sense
to me to seam allowance so I've just added quoting clips just to keep it in
place while I get on with the next step right the next step is to stitch
around to the base pieces so and this is just because I'm
you'll then going to cost into the base layer in a moment so here I am
just switching back to the other color
get my head in the way of the camera see again just I'm working from the
raw edge to stitching on the seam allowance line
okay so then I went and caught at regular intervals up to that stitching line just
because then it makes it easier for you to attach the base peace to your main
pieces for the carrier so here I am I'm just attaching the light mainlining peace to
the base lining peace so with those notches cost into it just makes it so much
easier to to mold it into the shape and as it is a circle it does
make it a bit trickier and then I repeated this with the outer pieces as well
again the quoting clips are nice and easy to use and but obviously if you're feeling
a bit unsure about stitching and round in the circle what you could do as well
is I'm do a bit attacking
so next I cut my elastic so here I'm just measuring it with the top of
the water bottle that I'm using stare have just taken the measurement there and then I've
just allowed a bit of room to overlap the two ends of the elastic to stitch
them together so I am just holding the maybe each other and I'm just going to
stitch those together with a straight stitch but all purply reinforced it a couple of times
so that its secure once I did that I then tucked it up into the lining
peace and where the casing is and just clip to into place there I also put
the lining into the main bit of fabric so that they were wrong sides together I'm
just in preparation for later on when it's all stitched together so again I've just used
closing clip says to keep the elastic right at the top just because I didn't want
to stitch it in when I secure the two fits together however it probably is better
if you either tack it in place or you use pens because I did find that
is lit quite about okay so now we're into the straps on the strap basis so
you need to ensure that you've put interfacing on all of your pieces to start with
so to begin with you need to fold up one long edge of your struck pieces
so you just here I'm just forwarding the seam allowance and on so that its meeting
the back of the bit of fabric so the wrong side and then I'm just repeating
it with the other strap peace and then repeated this with the strap faces as well
so just along one of the long edges put up a one sensory to seam allowance
and pressed it in place
case the next I pinned together the outer strap peace with the lining strap peace and
pinned it along the long edge that I hadn't folded at him down on I was
so did this with the strap basis as well so I put one lining peace with
one of the outer pieces so next I stitched all the way down the sides will
be down the long side but with the main strap peace I also so to the
short end down as well using the one centimeter seam allowance
once I had done that I turned to the corners on the strap peace just so
that I could get a nice point on the edge and then I turned it around
the hair I I'm just I'm turning it right side out and pegging it in place
ready for when I do my topstitching because I'm using interfacing it's it's staying in place
quite well but obviously you could press at this stage I said it the same with
the threat faces so I just turned it
so that the right sides were facing out obviously with the strap basis I just left
the short edges role because I didn't need to worry about those and because that the
only inside of the water bottle carrier of the main section
wrote soon next I assembled the adjustable strap so I'm going to do my best to
trying to explain this because it's one of these things where I just kind of fumbled
along and worked it out in the end looking at another bag I think that anyway
so what you need to start with is you will need your strap cheese will costs
and the slider you will need to slide one swivel class on to the strap with
the clip slides on the right sides of the strap he then need to add the
slider after this feeding the strap above the middle line on on the slider but under
the outer sections of the sliders your kind of going under the outer edge over the
middle line and under the other average then you need to from the short end of
the strap underneath itself so that the slide is no caught between the strap so the
lining should be I'm facing each other and the outer fabric should be only outside then
stitch across the width of the strap place to the short edge to secure the slider
in place bring the remaining short edge underneath the other end so that the swivel class
and slider down one end and the lining side is showing on the remaining and focus
remaining and over on itself and goes through the slider as before by going under the
first edge leaving the strap over the middle section and dipping back under the outer edge
pull through this end until the swivel club pull through this end until they attached to
spittle class and slider it down the other end slight the remaining swivel class on Cilician
ends of the strap with the class and showing on the outer side fold over the
end so that the lining sides of the strap are facing each other stitch in place
close to the short edge of the strap right so if you call that then you
should have an adjustable strap done finally you need to assemble the main carrier so we
see could do this before doing the adjustable strap but for some reason I decided to
get the strap over and done with I think I was just avoiding this section to
be honest and because using elastic it is quite tricky to do this section so receive
you don't need to use a brilliant avoid up so you need to fold the to
strap faces and to so that the outer fabric is on display and start a daring
on each select there in the fold of the strap face position pin intact them in
place I would actually recommend stitching them to the out of fabric before attaching the lining
and which obviously I haven't done here but I would recommend doing x it we just
make it a lot easier still yeah and if you haven't already slight the lining piece
into the outer peace that the wrong sides are facing each other can tackle the way
around ensuring the raw edges of the strap bases are enclosed and then topstitch all the
way around I would recommend during a couple of race of stitching just because it will
reinforce it and make it a lot stronger
finally attach the strap hope you will to go to inside and you're done
okay so just a few thought after the tutorial that I initially recorded so I've had
this carrier for a few weeks out so I've been able to test this out and
on the her I'm happy with it I don't think there's too many issues it is
quite a tight fit and that's just because I didn't really add any wiggle room for
it but I mean it makes sure that it doesn't slip out so I'm fairly happy
with that and but it does overseeing it's a little bit tricky as to slide on
and off one thing I probably would change and the only reason I didn't do it
I'm on this one was because I didn't have the resources and I just want to
get on with it but instead of using a last stick up here is to attach
a drawstring cord instance and then you can adjust it it could also make it a
bit more best time see could use it for a different side water bottle they probably
would still need it to be roughly the same height another thing to note is that
I probably should have made these and
these unstraps that the Deering's are on they could have been a bit smaller so they
didn't need about this tool I think I decided to make in this big just because
the actual water bottle it is quite tall so I think it's fine for this bottle
but if you had one that had a much
smaller lead you could over teacher in that down it could definitely behalf of the length
that I've caught at him so these are just thinks to bear in mind defending the
last bottle that you're using in particular but otherwise already happen with the shape I like
that it you know designed to mold around
the water or so the straps really handy it's really handy that it's adjustable so I
can move it from being cross-body to just over one shoulder nothing I did as at
the end was I that some of that weatherproof spray on it which is suitable for
fabrics and shoes I just thought that this would help it last a bit longer because
I want to work so it just means that it's more likely to withstand the elements
and for a lot longer that's it from me today I hope you enjoyed it and
thanks for watching