hello in today's video I'm going to show you how to make a simple zipped purse
with the lining been started by tell you what I used to make this pass I
used as if so my one was a fifteen centimeter along them
I cut out to outer pieces in the main fabric
I caught mine and thirteen by eleven centimeters and if he did want to make the
same size one eye was a cut of a fusible place just because I used on
the matching bag and I had a bit left over I cut out to line in
pieces the same size as the outer pieces and I caught our bit of a break
for the key rings have you only need about for Bible centimeters but I had a
scrub so I didn't actually fat it down immediately you also need a the puppet in
the first step which is entirely optional depending if you're using useful place is to add
the futile place to the main fabric pieces that will be only outside of your past
with this fusible place it takes about twelve seconds I think and the one I've got
any way to a deer
the first actual step is to attach one main fabric peace and one mining place to
sit for a cup them images of world to help you so first you place one
of your main fabrics right side up you place the zip right side down onto the
main fabric peace so that the edge line up with the top edge of the main
fabric next you have the lining piece on top of the zip right side down so
the lining peace and the top edge will line up with that edge of visit and
the top of the outer these so intact and then machine stitches in place using using
her press Evert
once you from that's called the main and line pieces back so that the right side
for now facing outwards and press it in place so that you can now see the
zip again
second surface to attach the remaining main and lining pieces to the place the remaining main
fabric PC have in front of you right side up and then placed the visit once
more down on top and but again facing downwards and then like before then sandwich as
if again by putting the lining the remaining lining fabric peace over the top right slide
down in tap and then machine stitch in place using your the progressive at once more
and again once ditched all the main allying pieces on the second flight back so that
that it can be seen between the two main fabric pieces and the two lining pieces
press with the iron and then chop which
you also need to secure the dipper either and so just a little line of stitching
at both ends just that when you open it a little bit later if you won't
they we've become disjointed and keep it shape the next you need to make the new
the curing layers to me to folder loop fabric in half and press unfold and then
from the raw edges to meet the boat line you created refold at of old-line so
that the raw edges and our tax in the middle search close to both of the
long edges you won't need to neaten up the raw edges as they'll be on the
inside of your past and then stitch close to both long edges
one can a half some of the raw edges together and an already to attach to
the main peace so set number five is to stitch the sides and base of the
past an important thing to notice to keep this it open to ensure that you can
turn the best right side out hold the person of the lining pieces line up together
right sides facing and the main fabric pieces match up right side facing they need to
decide where you're going to position your name way you would like it on the side
of your past the need to and put it in between the two main pieces of
fabrics that when you turn it out the right way it will be on the outside
so pin attack and then stitch all the way around the back that remember to leave
a gap of the bottom of the lining for that you can turn it right side
out
the final step steps on the six is to turn about very side house finish the
lining base and added hearing so as you noted by already asked to come on mine
before turning the first right way out recommends trimming the colors of the bag and possibly
the seam allowances throughout with pink quiches this will have a few debts and better points
on the corners of your past so want to trim that any can push it through
so that the right side is now facing Albert's and you can use Evelyn's angle a
tool to fish out those corners do with the lining still picking out of the best
you'll need to then finish off and the gaps it to you called the pass through
so with this you can either slip stitch in place where you could just miss the
regime such very close to the edge to secure as well depending what finish you want
to the inside
they once that don't you just need to talk the lining inside the first and zip
it up I meet if you haven't already at the keyrings belief and your damn you
can change the size of the sick person you just leave changed the dimensions of the
main and lighting piece of the fabric and it's just a really useful person you could
make a little gift sat for a friend and by Pinson stationary inside it or obviously
it's perfect as a pass to hold point then we could even store your buttons stash
in it as always if you enjoyed this video be sure to like it and don't
forget to subscribe thanks for watching