hello you today I'm going to show you how to make this question
if you do at this video I'm about to see more content please don't forget to
like and subscribe if you haven't already okay so basically I'm making a cushion because someone
I know that birthdays coming up and I got this would be a nice gift to
make them having an awful lot of time to make it so that the other is
an awful for a vision but I think I'm it won't take too long it's like
that normally I make an envelope fold when I do a kitchen so that's when it's
caught and you don't use to to for anything or any other fastenings and you have
one long better of fabric before one bit over at the other side overlaps so that
if you do need to push him pads you want opening at the back the only
drawback to that is you don't really have a proper back if I just am get
an example so here is an example of an envelopes volte cushion which I've made previously
so as you can see on the back the to therapy back pieces and the overlap
so all day the kitchen had isn't on show you can get it out if you
did want to wash the cover not actually sure why I did this one with any
opening because it is probably quite difficult to watch
any apparently I thought the option so obviously the advantage of do in the envelope old
style is that you do don't lead as it but why do the sit version the
reason I'm doing the that version is because I had really limited fabric for the back
peace I wanted to use a playing white for the front because I'm going to do
a bit of three machine embroidery on it but the back I wanted to have I'm
a color background so going for this great which is lovely but I use this for
three aprons last Christmas and it means that I haven't gone and pull off and left
so I just about had enough to cut this square of fabric so as I mentioned
I've got a plain front I get this is reached out go to be assessed and
the design I'm going to be using
is on a circulant Funt because I believe she likes button-front so break down of what
you need if you do want to follow along so I cut out two squares the
a break for the front and the back of the cushion in their colors that I
wanted they for less this is forty two centimeters by forty two centimeters the reason I've
done it the shape is because my kishen pads is for to two centimeters although it
is for two centimeters by forty to and I've got out peace which is exactly the
right measurement this is actually factoring in a one centimeter seam allowance all way around because
I actually want the cushion paths to end up faulty centimeters this is just because I
think it's nice time or really from mastication so and by not giving a lot of
wiggle room it will mean that it's I'm a nice competition so yet obviously if you
do want to make a different size cushion just major your cushion pads depending on how
plump your petition pattern you pay once you as a seam allowance on top of that
measurement rather than doing more I did so in that case you just need to add
whatever you prefer is your seam allowance but to lots of that one so one on
each side and then do the same for the to the length as well it case
to do the two main pieces of fabric eyeballs they got a scrap because I'm going
to do a bit of PK
on it and it's going to be the pot section of my design so what I've
done to create this template is just I've drawn loosely around the outside of the pop
because what I'll do is are free machine stitch the line which will just be inside
the applicator of fabric I'm going to as you ever see if you want to add
a with a decoration you need your design and then I've also got some different threats
to you so I'm probably going to use black to draw out the the parts of
the bottom I'm not sure whether are gonna black or just go straight on to the
shapes of green for the leaves I'll have to think about it when I get there
I would obviously you need the step as well so I've chosen one that's and this
was actually quite long it's forty Paul's centimeters so um it's more than enough so you
just need to choose one that's essentially the
length of one of your site's to ensure that you've got enough that I will say
go out a magic pans hand so I use this when I want to be a
bit more accurate with my free machine umbral treat design I'm also going to use a
bit of wonder whether to stick the plant parts section a cases to begin with I'm
going to overlook all of the edges on my front peace and my back these I'm
just doing this now just to get it over with no really I just which the
scene and then overlocked but because I'm heading as it I don't want to forget to
do it and put the second first so that's Mephisto obviously if you don't have an
overlocker you can just use the overlooking thing on your phone machine and do this exact
stitch or depending how much your fabric phrase you might envy of tissues pinking shears
but as I do want this to
be able to withstand the washing machine if they do to slide to watch us every
soften and I just think that it was locking it will help it lasts longer
I'm not going to get a move on to
creating the design I'm going to
trace my
aunt part on to bundle
my wonderworks quite a bold to them to the sticky there and the paper layer coming
away from each other so
it is something to I remind the Fuehrer make use of soup on the one of
the seven to be extra careful that
I'm calling on to both players that they cut together
next I'm going to attach
my shape to my brain fabric the Emeka that I thought
they want you all that fact there were busy make sure the sticky size is against
the fabric and your whining on the paper peace and you can cut the ants
so discussing
just rollings actually you don't have to the great exactly the shape my clients on only
I actually just caught it loosely for the first day to them
wants this find on I then prefers to duty to that it's done I'm just
going to take off the paper
acting now just because I've done it before where I have
touched I have to position it will campily and then I realized on the paper and
hand me that so the next step is working out where you want your meeting so
for this one what I'm going to do that I'm going to work out roughly with
middlers
I'm doing that just by wanting in the heart down folding it and heart again
I know that's roughly adult my just
magic in
there we go so I can see my metal that the fork out what the middle
is on this
scene it doesn't need to be exact so just
it's pretty
much the
same so when confirming happy with the positioning
going to
this section
and I'm just going to iron this on first because
don't want to eye in the fabric pen design on their or it may become permanent
right now I'm going to draw the
lines that they want to fall for the
free-motion design
case with my design thrown out I'm going to go into the machine now if you
do want to make a similar design basically what I did to find that the
design I wanted it was I just had a quick look on lines the research to
succulence found an image of a succulent eyelight and then just use that to Roman version
that
case now but the design on the front allocation smutted out I'm going to move on
to attaching the zip so I want my debt to be at the bottom of the
cushion so I'm going to
move out over to one side and then placing my backpiece on top of the front
peace
they line up
next I'm going to mark for centimeters
from either edge of the side that I'm fisting the zip on the reason for this
is just the that there's a bit of the border on either side so the whole
edge isn't completely separate make sense
so just marked that with the magic pen and then I'm just a few clips and
so that it stays in places I never hope to the machine so I'll just do
a straight stitch over the for sense to me to the
top and and the bottle and
so now it's such a one of those two ends are going to the ward back
with one side pressed out I'm going to put the it
right side down
just grabbed a few Hennessey Atmore pins if you want so now I'm going to stitch
that side of the simple
for this I need the zipper for
someone pointed the tips detached so Merricks finally to
attach the other side
in place
I'm not going to talk it's the final step is to go around so
but yes not just going to now finish the seams of the other three sites and
epically
we should have additional of that you might need to trim the corn and desolate from
out nicely I'm just gonna check how it is another thing to note its to make
sure you have your lip open
so that you can turn out right side out and which is what I thought to
do
you think I'm going to also trees that they thought now as well
okay so that you have it as the cushion so as you can see it's not
too difficult to add as it I'm just depending how much your Perikles and why he
gets up it's just cheaper to do number like food rather than as it one bit
and it doesn't use less fabric and also means that you could have done the double
design Seeckt at something on the back of well obviously I didn't in this instance but
I oversee has a much clean of finish not having that you don't need a contrastive
life of them and it's just I'm trying to not spend too much on my hobbies
to ship so I've used one that I picked up in a charity shop in a
previous year so it only cost me twenty be which was brilliant it's also a really
nice missiles and I think it goes nicely with the
the greenly leave some in the settlement and that's it for this time thanks for watching