today's a video is showing you how to make your own Trani cover
now by trolley I mean one of those treaty trollies you can get them in ikea
the one I thought is from hobby craft the one I'm making is for my mom
and I know that she put the same one as me which is Hoby crossed and
which is perfect because I have my want measure
yeah if you want to make caring and I'm so free to follow along and I'll
show you how I managed to make this one as always did you like this video
I want to seem more don't forget to like and since right on this truly have
that it's very simple it's just one long piece that goes all the way up and
down obviously if you don't have a piece of out a long enough you could add
a seam at the top you just need to actual signal ants on that end and
then I've got panel up front and a panel at the back so clearly made up
of three pieces but then I will say got a lining again made out the three
pieces and then the joined at the bottom and the design have gone for it is
versatile because my one wanted one where she could potentially store or in the top chef
if she wanted
so it's got a tan up at the bottom and it's just give you an idea
of what I saw in my trialling and I'm not sure what my own stores and
hands I think she's got a couple as well I don't know which one she wants
a cover for it in anyway so I've got lots of bread at the top of
but my snap the pastor's
other little habitat reason I bought a random
section of fabric said and I look like of just dropped my embroidery thread there as
well I don't normally start on here and then at the bottom I thought all marbly
a pocket friends so the first thing I did in odas to make the trolley other
was to take some some measurements from this the first measurement I took was from the
base so I took the
depth so from here over to him
I took the with
between these two points and it took the height from again just where this mess of
it awesome finishes so just above the Wilkes they didn't want to get to get in
the way the world up and to hear but then I did had seven and half
centimeters just in case she wanted to add a bit more a bit like I have
it's not it's not flush to the top just so she can store a few extra
things in the top section with those three measurements of then got about to creating the
passen pieces so this pattern that you really need to draw out to person templates and
they're both rectangles which is great the first one you need to do is just like
paddle so that's just over one of the wider Emmons so I guess ministate the width
of the trolley so what I did was I took the wits measurement added two centimeters
I had a sense AEC one-ounce either side or whatever simulant you were to use and
then
with the height I used the high that I wanted for the trolley cover that I
just worked out and then added two centimeters on to that I don't want to worry
about any corners I don't know why I just thought it might look but life there
is it was and so what I did do was I used a simple cup this
is for my key actually and I just put it in the corner the top two
corners to draw a curve and the light cut or then I drew that curved color
rather than keeping the end the other person please let's make worth of the other two
sides of the truly cover and the top section so I wanted one long piece to
go all the way over basely one side the top then the other side so for
this I took the
depth measurement and added two centimeters to get the width of this person least it so
for the length of this long piece I took to
I calculated to lots of the height plus
the
width of the trolley and then I added to sent to meet us to that now
because other one he's late to paper drawing at this template I wanted to cut this
based on the old so I then divided that number by two now there's a chance
that this might be a bit big when it gets attached to the other person peace
but I'm going to work out like a lot to that
the first passed in peace so I thought to Elise
as you can see Oregon pass
where does it so much point
so we cut to pieces of this passing please the first one for those side panels
and as you can see there's my coat edge that I made with the cup and
then for the really long piece
I cut one of these all the fold if you haven't got that far break that
long enough obviously what you could do is cut to pieces but you just need to
add another schema land at the top edge
there you go so
so essentially records three
fabric pieces for the lining and three fabric pieces for the main fabric so the first
step was to pin or peg in my case I'm using the quilting clips to attach
the
panel with the curved edges
to the long narrow rectangular piece they are just working from one end
pinning it all the way around around the curve up on that top side and then
allow one that long piece to then be pinned to the other side so to save
time I decided to pin both side panels to the long narrow peace straight away as
this wouldn't affect it so I just yeah I got both sides picked on and then
I moved to the machine to sew them in place
once the outer peace had been made I lended the same with the lining so I
ended up with two of the truly cover shapes so what I did was I put
one of them inside the other so that there were right sides facing and then picked
them all around the bottom hem edge
and picked those together
so once I pegged the mall in place around then moved back to the sewing machine
and stitched this in place but I left a small gap so that I could turn
it right side out at the end
so once I'd seen him at the bottom I then begged it out the right way
so I found that gap where I'd left a hole in the hands so that I
could turn it right side
and in once I'd got the right side showing I then poked the lining piece into
the main cover peace
ready to them topstitch my way around the whole piece
so here is the final truly cover as you can see it fits fine impacts the
be a little extra room head I get it tends will you fought on the top
players I haven't got it and that overloaded at the moment that you can see of
for extra room in case I did add more stuck on to the stop shops as
they had but one that went up to him I can just lower this turn up
at the bottom and then it should still cover up the lower section I think if
I knew what I was going to store on this top shelf if it was my
own because obviously I'm given us the way to get
time depending on what there they're going to regulae so in this truly father what I
might do is put some popples in just to keep that turn up in place in
staying up okay at the moment but obviously if it probably would look a bit nicer
or if it had a couple of this will ties or luxe a pauper's just to
keep us in place just because I am bit worried that's gonna get a bit in
the way and perhaps though the older against it might get a bit more worn out
in a bit more prone to looking down the its own so after I stitched the
two layers together I did find that I definitely had to catch the two sides of
it together so the lining in the main color so it did do a tiny bit
of hand-stitching in four corners at the top just where the curves are just because I
found that otherwise and it would be quite hard to put on top of mutually because
they're you'll be continually contesting with it if that makes sense because
the PC went on the inside might be floating college was trying to find to cover
level trolley the asset is just an idea if you did want to I'm as a
cover to your truly it just saves again dustier guests I think my mum's probably thinking
if my niece's around that quite young it will at least such them and grabbing hold
of lots of potentially dangerous lyceums that could be all know I don't know watching stools
on that but I guess you know it might be a little smooth listen things in
that war is this will be a bit more of a deterrent but also you know
she might be storing stuff that she doesn't use white as often as I do with
my trolley so it just means that it keeps dust-free well so you have to wash
them cover every dime then I guess that's it for today thanks for watching