today I'm going to show you how to make your own fabric birthday badge if you
like this video and tamid already please don't forget to like and subscribe so I can't
take credit for today's tutorial it comes care to see of my mum or brother she
made a badge and I've had a look at it and trying to replicate or so
and she made this batch for me for one of my birthdays and you can see
roughly what the construction of it is so there's a little circle in the middle where
she's converted the age there are two outer circles so you got the front and the
fat and then in the middle you can fill this something sandwich there so I'm in
my case of gayeties garbled I'm assuming at the cardboard which is used embroidery thread to
stitch the circles all together and make a bit decoration out of it and then she's
finally added a ribbon to step and a little bit more flares there is almost a
bit like a result rather than a badge and she's put a safety pin on the
back thanks to my mom for the inspiration of this video and yet I'm completely ripping
off this design so for this you will need to draw out three templates they are
circles those so you could potentially just draw them on to the materials straight away if
you want to make it the slice that I'm doing you will need a small circle
which will go in the middle where your embroidered the number that one I've done is
a fight in half a centimeter diameter so it must just be
a bit over a couple of inches you will need to cut out a cardboard center
so I've done miners nine sense metas diameter and you will need an outer circle so
you'll cut to bits of fabric out of this one and so it'll be the front
of back and this one I've done is twelve ten meters so I mean you can
display it via you know just find some cylinder things at home you know different parts
and jars here are the resources you'll need to make a bad she like I am
you will need a couple of different fabric scraps so I have chosen a really small
scrap here this will be part of the inner circle and that all have the number
it all to so this is this a bit of navy cost and robot really to
see any scraps should work fine and I've got a much bigger fabric for out there
to some polka-dot navy as well and and this will be the outer circles on my
badge so as you can eat the colors go quite well together you could do contrasting
colors you know flash a couple of different persons possibly I guess as things fairy mind
is with a smaller circle because you're going to be embroidering the number on it all
you know about a message on that you might want to have it a bit planer
or the pattern not being too busy just so you can appreciate your hand embroiders work
at the end beyond these to its fabric scraps you will also need a bit of
ribbon or some sort of trimming this is just to add a nice though at the
bottom you will need a back for the branch so I've got I'm a brooch fixing
here but you could possibly just tell on to say sleep in it depends you you're
making it for and port resources are available you need a cardboard circle in the middle
this just is a bit more reinforcement so and I've already cut out my some type
heresy and so this was the nine centimeter circle and I've just used regular is quite
then called achieve and you could use a thicker one to make a bit more substantial
this is optional I've got some double-sided tape I'm just purely going to users to help
me likely fix the fabrics against this cardboards just to help me when I'm stitching around
to secure its and but we see you don't have to have that you could pin
it in an entirely optional additional results but it could be helpful you need some embroidery
press so I've decided that these stitching I'm going to add it's going to match my
ribbon so I've been with this lovely orange I've got regular systems for cutting my double-sided
tape and every scene if you haven't got out long cut board template for the middle
you can use them cut that out I've brought some embroidery Sissons and for when I'm
handing bettering elements and sewing
I also got pink inches to make a knife decorative edge to my circles that I'm
going to cut out you will also need a darning needle little later stay with your
own broidery threat and you might want a fabric can if you are just directly drawing
the circles onto the fabric over ready for something that you might want to use if
you have one at home which is a little embroidery hoop just to keep your fabric
toss well you stitch the digits on to your badge front in case the best I'm
going to draw the circles out on to my fabric so with the and this small
circle this is going to have the digits and brought it on to it so I'm
not going to cut the outset way I'm just going to mark where the cycle will
be and I'll do it roughly in the center of the fabric because I'm going to
put it in an embroidery hoop next
I'm going to at the digits as well just give me a guideline of where to
stitch
I'm going to use my fabric come to draw on this polka-dot fabric and I'm going
to on the river
up I mentioned for the two larger circles you can cut these out I'm going to
use my thinking chairs straight away
there my two large little bit now it's time to so out the digits so as
you can see I am
going to turn braider sixty on this one so for my embroidering
I have
two strands of embroidery threat but then I've bubble that over the say is actually I'm
for strands thick I'm going to do a chain stitch around but obviously you could use
or ever sit you family
they know I'm going to
know you but your number embroiders like so you could probably do it at the end
if you want to see but it might be that trickier than the cobbles and place
I'm going to position its onto my front large circle I might actually work out where
the middle is say I'm just going to
hold it and half twice
this is the blunt and pollution of it back
just
so I can see a little glimmer so I'm just gonna see if it looks sorrow
it may be just it slightly I'm pretty happy with that so I might just get
a couple of ends and to popping in place so being careful of my pens I'm
not going to stitch this want to up front fabric know I realized that I don't
use orange for this know I'm going to use some white to match the paper up
this time I'm going to do our half the thinnest I might don't take out to
France but I'm not as she going to double it over because
I would like it to look thinner than the numbers thinks well actually with this one
I'm just going to do a running stitch and I'm just doing it really close to
the edge
just so it tickles
its own is a nice decorative search but it's not attracting too much from the numbers
its merits the
front big circle and the little settle attached I am now going to at my carpels
peace so and just going to place it roughly in the middle going to admit of
dog cided tape just to keep it in place will
secure it so I would just hold lightly and that it had another bit to the
other side of the card was
so what you could do if you want to Nessen up if your two seconds don't
her line he could then go around on the thinking she's again so I might do
under the and I'm not sure like to see his so what you can do is
just cut out that a cold without confitures at first get to the stage and then
drum them and then they will align much better so I'm now going to do stitching
around to secure the concord in the middle I'm going to go back to chainstitch what
you could do is actually the stage you could add the back fixin but I'm just
going to do the and even though it might be a bit tricky with this card
would center
let you know and then you can decide whether it's once and with stitching the digits
I'm going to
double up my threat so it's for strand sexo final touch apart from having the back
is to add the ribbon so it's going to be a nice little the bottom
very final there is to add the bridge so free gonna pick quite high up at
the top so that it was intercity much and I want it to the level with
the writing
okay so there you have it a birthday batch so obviously you could make it that
bigger or perhaps make me in a circle of it larger so that you could add
a message or put birthday boy goal for it's my birthday something like that having just
put the back into this ivory would recommend attaching it before you put the cardboard in
now you just what we really caffeine a bunch of the fabric but it probably is
a bit easier I'm not sure this very was driving both ways and I will say
press this ribbon a bit because it is a bit Cresap that's it for today thanks
for watching