hello today I'm going to be making some gift tax if you like this video and
would like to see more police so thing at the life and subscribe okay so with
Christmas last little week away I thought I'd make some fabric gift tax I don't only
do this and I'm not sure how awful with the end result I just thought I'd
give it a go I'm going to make some for my partner's gift because I think
everyone else has got their gifts now because I won't be seeing him and between now
and Christmas as well so close to it because I see well every year it's very
easy for me to scoop up the gift like in him so it does mean that
it's something I can reuse year on year I can make a few of them so
depending how many gifts like a fill each year you know I could make safe five
of them and then if I didn't ease one of just packet away with the Christmas
decorations and yeah basically I can just store the effects with the I'm Christmas decorations and
then when it comes out next year I can then reuse them again but yes this
will be the trial run should we say and then I might roll it out to
other people I actually make up yet swore and protect me in my family so what
I've begun with is I've got a simple table which I made on our document so
with the word document on portrait alignment I created a to by five table and made
it as long as the
sheet
obviously had told the the order as well
and the I said is that I'm going to draw some potential Christmas designs on here
what I'd like to do in the end is I'm going to have two layers of
fabrics I'm gonna have a piece fabric was gonna have a design on and the other
side his games have the message now it's not for everyone but I really like writing
with three machine and orangery I don't know why this is probably because I studied English
I really like handwriting and
is an arrow just quite enjoyed doing it free hand obviously if you have an embroidery
sewing machine which has Lesters brilliant you could write your iMessage even easier with that so
you could create your tag a lot simpler but I'm gonna do a free hand and
if you don't have an a greater in the machine and you don't want to do
machine stitching you could just wrote it with the fabric pen that would be absolutely fine
as well
rights I'm gonna get one and create some designs in case my first crops get is
a slightly wanky looking Christmas tree very basic I've just done a cone shape for I
guess the triangle seven kind and I did a little star on the top and then
a couple of lines to the trunk and then puts at the bottom I've left a
little bit of a gap of the top because I do want to add a little
home to that I can that be that string with wine through so that I can
attach it to the and gift in question you also want to leave a little bit
of a border just because you'll need to stitch the front and back sections with the
tag together I think when I do this I've done this slightly over to the left
so for we will shift it slightly
my reindeer find looks like a pig with amahs
the cockpit grain that
I don't want that
it's
okay so I've drawn out a few designs and some of them I'm not going to
use because I'm not that keen on them so
the ones I did you like to start with I guess
I'm quite fond of the speck design the best silhouette the Christmas pudding I think the
Christmas ball will be good and the snowman
possibly this I'm simple version of a Christmas tree so it'll just be a line basically
will probably used I'm a metallic thread potentially
and possibly on a dark fabric for it to stand out twice even in a regular
threader crow-like quite nice were just in a green so I think they're right the others
are
miss I think I was trying to do this squiggle version of the Christmas tree without
growing a draft cone shape keep saying cone is the triangle shape but up during trying
which at first so I decided up doing a squiggly line and I don't mind this
Christmas treaty much I made possibly devote to all perhaps adapted and use as a design
I'm there's also my first attempt at a stag which looks like a pig with and
listen or perhaps this model I'm not sure and then I've done this which I think
there will be quite nice idea which is them a few different Christmas buckles on the
type but they're not really lined up very nicely and
I think if I did do I agree to stitch buttons on and then add a
little tech to those or stitch of it
for now I think of leaves that one I think a lot of these I'd probably
actually preferred to and perhaps draw it and then liner up nicely on the computer so
I have drawn them in these boxes just to make sure I don't draw them too
big but I probably am going to mind the but better because you know it's like
this Christmas bogle it's too far to the top that needs to move down slightly this
her hands bit of to left and the Christmas pudding is not to babble it is
slightly to left and yeah they're just all of it off to one side and at
least I'm looking Uther I think correct that but it's okay I can correct it on
this I'll just draw the outline with the box first and then I moved and trace
this where I want it on in the rectangle against another I've chosen my designs I've
gone around them in a black belt tip just that I can see it easier through
my fabric and it probably comes up there on the cameras work so I've got my
lightbox head it's and passion one with the bold Antony and you can get Hammond once
I think now but anyway this is why I've got so that's what I'm using going
to draw to of the designs on to this crap out of reach khalkha so I
think for this one I might actually go for probably the bear outline and I might
do the stag as well just but I do really like these two designs right so
I'm going to just one around one of these and boxes and I'm really strong that
out first so I know where my borders are and then I'm going to proceed with
tracing my to template roughly where I want them within that box
so when you're doing pre-mission boring you have the larger
underneath the fabric and then you get a small you can talk
just type to the others life
so as of his then looks while the videos I'm using that my magic pen which
which is every reasonable
now I'm going to meet over to the sewing machine and stitch the outlines for both
of these so I probably just do outlines
on this occasion and but obviously you could appliqued a both of them and me to
get you know a suitable fabric to do the main body of the bear that would
be quite nice and same with the stock roding you just do a silhouette of the
stack
yeah just move over to the sewing machine now
he's now done all the stitching I'm just going to and trim all of those extra
strands of thread
a next I'm going to cut out the for panels ready to stitch the out together
what I'm going to do is I'm going to cut one of these out one that
I'm probably not going to use
I'm going to place it over just to check that it's I'm coming out for exactly
like just because my lines are about waiting to see
don't forget the as well at least between machines which I just on it
especially or like background you might be of to see some of the threads true so
it's always the practice to remove them anyway
okay so I've got my did how I would faced them long sides together they bought
the mighty on one side and then I've got the writing on the other side I'm
just going to
leave together well for these the crossing grips
I'm just gonna roughly come in together and then I'm going to go back to the
side machine and just to stitch really close to the edge
I'm not worried about the raw edges here because it's not going to get much where
it's not like I have an item of garment where it needs to be that secure
of course it might for a bit but I think that would just add to it
trunks just make the edges a bit more interesting I just use my thinking is to
cut right place to the stitching line
to think this is make them a bit later
the fining thing to do realizable in different directions nothing to do is to add some
sort of holes that I can add some wine and attach it to a gift I
say here's the tool that my one found in a charity shop I have not used
it before and it's from we are memory keepers
yeah and it's a gadget little all sorts of things but I just want an island
we
came with it was
so I've just got to island bases at random here they're both orange but that's
okay so I need to work out roadies us
the first thing I need to do is make a hole and I think need to
use this side because it's got a smaller
smaller it makes us more hole and these aren't huge so
looking up in case I may be about five centimeters wiper city and
the whole saying is I can see the spare room advice
okay very go about
eating as a left quite gap which is good one too
I'm going to try out awfully that
I guess let's talk really shop its managed to as a hole in the load of
fabric which is great I think then
she either on to it now I'm gonna go with a one do you think
this works
that I might have pressed on it to hold our fair it wouldn't do it
okay did the one for it so
okay so they have it to tax for Christmas gifts face addressed to fill on this
occasion
Yep you
so obviously if you don't have and I love whole maker and these nettled list of
it and then you could just make a hole and it might not last as long
it depends if you don't remove the twine which probably will last a fair about the
time
trying to think anything else to bear in mind obviously its white time consuming that if
you will use the mere after year that's quite useful know they're easier if you didn't
want to make a gift tag with a gift you're passing on someone you could use
this method to create and little name codes for the table and which overseeing if you
invite the same people you're on here and you'll get lots of yerselves so one main
issue with this is you can kind of see the other side slightly for because of
youth white like you black threads and to remain that I guess you could put a
layer in the middle just to to hide the other side stitching possibly I don't think
it's that bad but is something might consider in the future or perhaps I'd use a
different colors of one side of the design so it could be you know that there
could have been on the blue background and then I could use wait for the writing
I hope you enjoyed this video and thanks for watching