today I'm excited to share with you at the beach control that my mom and I
made a few months ago so I've been avoiding editing that's just because we recorded our
the village both on the camp order and my camera
and a lot of matching up to do and getting it ready to release and but
I finally go on to that and finished it today so I'm excited to share it
with you now it's all edited so basically what happened is I got two large towers
on sale at the sleep market and I knew that my mom wanted a beach and
how concho to born after I'm going to reach so I thought this would be the
perfect opportunity to try it out
I don't have many
fabric shops nearly so it's quite handy to use house it's a large enough so this
was a brilliant opportunity to have the correct fabric for the project so yeah basically what
will happen is I'll guide you through what we didn't so I've sped up on the
footage because obviously it took us a few hours to make it and so I time
up to the footage but I've done a voice-over so you know what's going on and
I'll try and add some graphics as well just see how an idea of what I'm
doing in case it's not there about were really happy with the end result so we'll
put some pictures up at the ends and I have to enjoy it
so we roughly worked out how long we needed the main body peace to be so
these towers are a hundred by a hundred and fifty centimeters so the width is a
hundred centimeters the length is a hundred fifty we decided that it needed to be just
over a square we made their main body length a hundred and five centimeters which meant
we Carter forty five centimeters so we laid it out on the table and cut off
that amount obviously we kept the bit we cut off as well just and because would
use that later on for the hood so as you can say I'm using the fiscals
and bit like a fabric guillotine and but it didn't work very well with the toweling
fabric so
we ended up going to dress making to this in the end anyway
and because we were using strike towels we needed to ensure that the stripes
well we kind of decided whether we wanted the stripes to match or not and you
do need to think about the not as well with toweling fabric but it was either
going towards one side or we decided that it didn't matter enough and that the stripes
not matching on the shoulder seam would be more annoying so anyway so we cut the
second howled this exactly the same way so they're both now the body pieces are hundred
by a hundred and five
so just to check that that fisted okay we pinned down the sides they'll be the
future side seams and then we put I'm quitting clips
for the shoulder seams leaving an opening for the neck
so this is a beach cover-up that will make my mom so she can see there
she's tried it on
and were just looking at how the neckline should work so we decided that it just
needed to be around the collar bone so there's me doing a fabric mark just where
we think it should be cut
okay so then we after and an awful lot about the hood
and
basically I've fast forwarded this really quick we spent ages having a look just I'm judging
it by I pinning it
trying to make a luxurious looking hood really catastrophically failing so in the and so we
we kept pinning it
and yeah in the end we decided that it was best a copy of a simple
hood from something we had at home so what we had at home was a nice
hoodie of mine okay so what we did was I'm as you can see yetts made
out of to pieces this hood so it was a really nice one to trace so
we got some scrap paper to use and place the hood on top of that and
then we drew around the head marking and all the edges that you can see we
did add a seam allowance to the I'm back of the hood and the front
we hadn't added one to the base so that's what we did that and but after
measuring it up with the and what was on I'm the opening of the beach dress
and neck opening we actually had to add three centimeters just as it and completely match
up with the hood word chosen right so happy with I'm the template that was created
we then cut out the two head pieces so and we folded it over here we
did actually in the end it out again could we didn't pay attention to the stripes
so once would cut out the two hood pieces and there I am using the overlocker
and I'm overlocking the curved back seem of the hood
right so we're happy with the hip there that fill in the background just looking around
wondering what's going on
we will say nicked his chair though which is why he's kneeling
see I were happy with the hood so the next thing we decided to do
was work out exactly where the hood would go
here I'm overlooking the shoulder seems so I'm going from the end of the neck opening
to where the armhole openings and then I repeated it with the other shoulder seam as
well
okay so with that done we then
went about to attach the hood so
what we did at the front was we did cut down to where I marked the
collarbone so I've got
a nice opening their so yeah then we just lined it up in the center and
pinned it all the way around
once we pinned it we then tucked it into place and just because the toweling fabric
does move about quite a lot and so it is quite challenging to work with and
it is really think even on the overlocker which is fairly adaptable to most stuff it
was struggling a little bit
so before we attached the head we did check it an honor to another fitting just
to double check
just because it would be alright night manner to you on pick so we thought better
safe we will say double-checks and how the armholes would be
a that was the moment we
realized that the perfect pocket for it would be a kangaroo pouch bucket so here we
are just roughly working out where we want it to go on the beach dress
so here I am just taking some measurements so we pinned it where my mom thinks
it would hang best and I'm scribbling some rough measurements I think we ended up tweaking
this as we drehte out but just to give us a rough idea of how we
were going to do it right with a rough idea of the measurements and we then
drew out
the kangaroo pouch to scale
as you can see we were adjusting as we went along we decided that the original
measurements weren't narrow enough at the top
so we ended up increasing the lower their the base of the pocket and shortening the
top edge just to give it more of
yes sir an angle for the pockets he ended up drawing out in a different pen
just the region which was the correct line to castle right say next week cut out
the patch pocket
and here I am overlocking all the edges just so it won't fray I don't think
we bothered with the top one because it was one of the
original ends of the towel
so now here I am just marking up some prep folding in the seam allowance as
its patch pocket so that we don't have any role Rogers edges on the outside
and then there's my mom she's just talking so she's just taking the pressed in the
folded in edge that we've just created and again just so it doesn't move what we're
trying to stitch it on to
the main peace
with that tact we then went about guessing it's positioned on to the front of the
towel cover-up so here I am just pinning it all the way around so that we've
got it there before you attach it to the front peace you do need to stitch
where the pockets open so the two
diagonal lines so you just need to do a straight stitch on this I did actually
forget to do this so we ended up hand-stitching it
which I wouldn't recommend I just do it on the machine if you don't forget so
once I'd pinned it on to the front peace I then attacked him to position again
like I say it I just didn't want to moving around too much and I felt
it was a lot safer to spend the time attacking
right with it attacked in place I then used the sewing machine to stitch the top
side and the lower side interposition as well as the two
vertical lines on the sides of the pockets just before the diagonal lines web and which
are where their hands go into the pocket
with that in place I then pinned the sides together we left a little gap at
the bottom
and you're using the pen more pinned markers that we're done
we then added
we ensure that we didn't stitch over the armholes right so with the side stitched up
the final thing we had to do was a bias binding to the front opening where
we'd just cut down to the collar bone we didn't have to do on the hood
if you did to cut your heads on a raw edge I'd recommend put and vice
finding all the way round the hood as well as the neck opening but as we'd
only done it on that lower section and the bit I guessed from the neck to
the collarbone we just had to do it on that be shaped bit there
again so I hope you enjoyed the footage of the beach I'll punch of being made
so we have a lot of fun creating it as you noticed we have to
think about it as we made it up but obviously if you did follow these instructions
you could probably make it in a much and short a time
with the town in ferity do need to be careful just does it quite thick so
you've got a basic machine you might struggle unless you had a walking fit and yeah
I found that tacking really helped me get through it and and it did struggle on
the overlocker events so you just need to make Jordan's you know you're feeling that you
live the fabric together appropriately so yeah we took a couple of vota among wearing it
and more recently YMCAs of the sovereign the moments in the UK so we managed to
snap the a shot of her wearing the beach on Joe on the beach which was
lovely and that we do obviously had some pictures we took colony fat finished making it
as well so we're really happy with the result it's a nice comfy I'd say it's
quite the universal size of well so have you know I tried it on and a
slightly different and shape and size and I found it really comfortable as well I think
the any difference if you're making it the different sizes you might want to consider shortening
it a bit more and if there's someone is really putties or you might want to
move the I'm the pocket peace a bit higher or lower depending on that person's body
light and but they're probably the main adjustment spend much meant to make him very still
keep the neck opening pretty much the same and to the local very work for most
people another thing to consider is the weight of the towels or the thickness of the
town's that you're using we used quite substantial towels so although it nice and cozy an
absorbent if it was a really what they might get a bit too how after a
while I think of the barn in the beach and called all day you're quite shoaled
after that so you probably won't be a problem down here but possibly you know if
you were going elsewhere it might be a bit too warm for you and it's also
obviously takes up more room efforts to pick the fabric though you know if you were
packing it the holidays you might struggle to get it in your suitcase and I will
stay that way to say you know it's an extra weight on your shoulders they speak
so you can join that I'm considering I'm adapting the past in thesis that I did
make Paris and writing it up into and easier to follow pattern so let me know
if you're interested in that and but that's it when I won't thank for watching