hello today I'm going to show you how to make a mesh laundry bag so you
don't need to much for this project you need some sort of net based fabric so
I've got this fabric here you also need a zip that's
just a bit over the width that you want your mesh bag to be you'll need
some matching thread you'll need a zipper fit and a regular press of it for your
sewing machine I decided to make mine so that the ends bag was roughly twenty six
centimeters with wise and thirty-six centimeters height twice but obviously you can adjust this depending on
the zip you've got all the size that you want your Longy mesh bag to be
something else to highlight as well which I really should have done at this stage because
I did end up pulling the zipper of my that my zip was one of those
ships on a role that you can buy and if you haven't seen them before essentially
it's a really long bit of dip Tate and you get ten slider's on it and
you get to decide how long the Zip's going to be so it's um it can
be quite economical it's really great if you want to use is it for something like
this and you want to Taylor it to the sides that you want it means that
you don't have to cut down a large as it size you can cut it to
the sides that you want but if you do that I would suggest just doing a
little zigzag stitch just like the I'm and six at you do for a button whole
I'm at the top and bottom of the Boston hope if you just secure pits and
stitches at either end of the zip once you've cut the bit as it take you
want otherwise you can accidentally and put the slider right off the end which is what
I did during recording anyway so first step is to place one short end of the
mesh fabric over the zip with the zip facing upward towards you and line the edges
to me to each other pin in place and stitch together using your zip of it
so what you want to do is to place the zip slider in the middle of
the track because it's going to get in the way of your stitching otherwise so once
you get close to the slider you can then move the machine needles so that it's
in the down position so that you won't use your spot in your stitching then with
the precipice up you can then wiggle the slider and push it into the section that
you've already stitched you can then re-adjust your stitching put the presser foot down and carry
on stitching right through to the other end to finish off the line once you've done
that you need to press the fabric back on itself at that stitch line you've just
made so that it is no longer covering the zip track and then using a regular
machine for stitch a straight line of topstitching down there to keep the mesh fabric away
from the zip section you may need to adjust where your needle is depending on how
wide your it is next places it back down on your table with the zip facing
up again without twisting the fabric you need to bring the other short end of the
mesh fabric over the zip and line it up with the other edge of the zip
like before you need to stitch it in place again I'd put the slider about halfway
to two thirds down stitch the first section and then when you're coming up to the
slider you can then put your so much a needle down move the slider up to
the bit you've already stitched and then carry on stitching the rest of the line when
you're doing the second sighed you do need to be careful that you you don't accidentally
stitch the looped a bit fabric in with you zipper once again you'll need to topstitch
it so if you fall the fabric back you might need to twist it so its
right side out and then you can stitch down a nice neat line with your regular
press effort so now you should have a leap of mesh fabric attached to is it
the next step is to make the side scenes so for the side scenes I have
decided to use a French theme just because this will make it last a little bit
longer and this will be Hering in the washing machine quite a lot and it's going
to be taking the brunt of the cycle with the zip right side out you need
to decide where you would like you as it to appear on the front of the
bag so with the one that I'm doing currently I wanted the top of the zip
to be about five centimeters down from the top edge so what I did was I
adjusted the loop of fabric accordingly and then I used these little pegs to pack it
in place once I was happy with how it was picked up I then stitched both
side seams now I allowed about a cupolas enemy to the seam allowance at the side
so what I had to do was stitch the first scene for my French seem so
at the moment its right side out I then stitched the side using a just under
one centimeter seem alone so I'm actually using the edge of my regular sewing machine press
stuffers to guide me how so once I'd done these two seems the first seems in
the French seem process are you still got the zip right side out I then turned
it wrong side out and pressed the corners out and the edges so that I had
a nice sharp edge I decided to use a pressing cloth just because you do need
to be a bit careful sips just in case and you accidentally melt the plastic on
them and then it might not work again so I've just used a pressing cloth here
just to be a bit careful now that you've pressed it the next thing you'll need
to do is stitch the second stage of your friend seems so I did a proper
one centimeter seam allowance so I used the guide on my sewing machine for this one
and just stitched right down those side seams again it's worth noting that you need to
be a bit careful with when you go across the zip-tie just because there is a
slight risk that you could accidentally break or bend your machine needle so I always go
a bit slower when I'm getting to the the zip-tie so once you've seen both sides
and the French seems with it wrong-side out you can then turn it back so the
right sides facing out again and what I did was give it a good press again
so I've got some nice sharp corners and there you have it so weary seek it
at any other embellishments if you want to you could make it so that it wasn't
completely made out of this mesh fabric especially if you don't have much metals net style
fabric you could make it so that it's more of a window or perhaps the front
section is mesh and the back could be just a fabric of your choice so there's
lots of different ways you could bury it you could add a bit cotton tape or
perhaps a bit of ribbon on to the slider just to help you move that across
all sorts always to personalize it but I just thought it's quite nice practical project which
you can use around the house that's it for this time thanks for watching