hello its Clary from clubber creations today I'm going to show you how to make a
hare towel turban
so in front of me I've got the printed Patton
so I've turned this into a PDF Paston it's based off and the past and I
made when I made one for my Nan for Christmas and I thought and other people
might want to have a ghost it
so there's an introduction page just advising you how to and print it out as with
other PDA pattens you've got to make sure it's on a hundred percent or actual size
and there's also on page two which is on part of the pattern there is a
test square so you can just print out page to check the scalings correct and it
measures up to ten centimeters all four inches and then you can go ahead and front
the rest
I will say got and the fabric I need so I'm actually using
both shapes I find it quite hard to source tomming fabric and it's quite expensive so
answer this project I've just got a bath sheet from my kiah and its roughly a
hundred centimeters by a hundred and fifty but for this project you only need about
I'd say about three quarters of the matter you should be able to squeeze one out
of that if you do you manage to find some suitable fabric in a store I
will say god and of course of elastic here so this is the quarter inch but
I'd probably go for a slightly thinner than sekar elastic just because you want to be
able to loop at round your button okay I'm which brings me onto
and that you need a button as well
and then I've got my matching threads and a bobbin to go with it
right so first things first I'm going to construct the PDF person
where's my guillotine
have you seen it anywhere we put it in the box
rubber that
I've left quite a large margin on my PDF pattens just so that it definitely prints
on different sized paper so it should work for us and UK and size paper what
I normally do as I leave the first she and don't bother casting off anything on
that one and then on the next one eye caught the left-hand side
and then when I get to the next row I do the left hand slide and
the top as you don't need to cut off all the edges and they should help
you line it up
okay now that I have cut out my template I just thought I'd highlight a few
points on the pattern so I've marked for notches on this person two of them have
labeled the other two don't the two that don't that around the long curve
these ones are just simply to help you line up to two pieces before you say
them up the other two
I've got one at the bottom and one at the top
there's one which is labeled button placement markers so that's just to help give you a
guide of where to place your bus at the end but obviously you can adjust that
I'm and I've also got
one at the top and this one is an elastic placement marker
so that's where you're going to add your elastic so it's um it's worth adding those
marks on to your fabric but yes so now I'm going to cut out my fabric
right so much you can see on the camera that on my fabric I've actually used
the stripey section on it so with this and it's quite handy to find out where
you know to to get it lined up nice and evenly
and but obviously there is also a grainline printed on there to help you
so once you've cut out your fabric pieces it's time to add the elastic so for
this you need to grab one of the pieces
and you need to have it right side out so I'm just gonna take the bottom
layer as that one's right side up already
the first thing you need to do if you haven't done already is to cut your
piece of elastic to eight centimeters long
right you need to hold your elastic peace in half
light sight
and then you need to
guess it to meet with the raw edges on your fabric feaster or putting on the
bright sides and your placing it
where your marker is and I'm just going to
add up into position that for now
I've just
use the sewing machine to tuck it in place
but you could just and hand statures well
now we've got this that the last attacks in place I'm now going to place
the other person piece on top of it
and now I'm going to
pin on my case opera please and closing clips and then I'm going to sit all
the way around this long curved back edge
which will form the back of the hair towel turban
if you do have an overlocker what you could do instead when you cut it out
you could have the seam allowance so I put half an inch on this which is
one point two sons pieces that you could
reduce that and just use your overlocker and
go round the edge of always you could leave it how it is and allow your
overlocker to trim off so if you do have an overlocker you could just over look
at this stage if you don't and you will need to go into the zone machine
stitch through and then you'll need to neaten
the raw edges after
attentively if you do have an overlocker still by all means ikan as it's quite a
curved edge you're more than welcome to just and use your sewing machine to stitch the
original seam allowance to start with and then you could overlook the ends after which is
what I'm going to do in this case
one thing to note if you are overlooking and you're going to trim these seem allowances
is to just make your markings for the buttonhole a bit clearer this will just help
for aligning as you may end up chopping off the bit where you did market so
I'm just gonna extend find down a bit
so that I can see it after I've overlocked
once you've neatened off those dms I would recommend giving that seem a little bit of
a press just though it lies a bit flatter so my overlooking I've just overlooked the
two layers together but I'm just going to ensure that it it presses to one side
before I
Nessen those front those front raw edges
the next step you need to finish off the front rule edges before you and eaten
up this seem so I'm going to use a noble locker because I have one and
if you don't have one if you just use a zigzag stitch just to prevent a
bit of frame
and that's what you need to do next
now that you've eaten up the war edges you will need to press under a half
inch seam allowance for one point to centrepieces
all of the way round and then you'll need to stitch that fairly close to the
raw edge but just dumb be careful of where your elastic is taking outspending health it
aloft to use it might go lower down then you expect you might just want to
adjust where you're searching liners
okay so your health heaven is almost complete their final step is adding the button to
this end so and you should still have a marker and if you transferred it about
higher up so I'm going to use that to broccoli gauge where I want to put
the button
have actually changed my mind on buttons while I've been making this so I've now decided
to use a slightly bigger bottom
so the button you want to make sure it's
tied on really secure just because it's going to be holding back that the elastic which
might be quite taught
just bear that in mind so I've been
doubled my neighbor and tied are not
so with a handy to give it a little bit of wiggle room as well so
I'm just going to find
something
in the back okay so thought of walking for gauge underseas the round but
okay so now you have your button in base
hello again so here is the final hair towel turban so I'll just give you a
quick well around see can see it from different angles
so from the back you can see that I've got the button down there as I've
got quite a big head it might be better if I positioned it slightly up so
that would be my main recommendation there I have put where the busing could be placed
on the pattern I'd recommend you know trial and error seeing
you know whoever you're making it for if you're making it for yourself and if you
got a small ahead it probably fine lower down there that if you got a big
ahead like myself you might want it a little bit higher up and you could also
extend the elastic a bit although that will wear out in time so it will become
a bit later and more flexible to this them but elastic I've got there is quite
tight but if you use something like that elastic it approve of it has a bit
more gives than this one so although I do feel the button could be a bit
higher up for me I think when the elastic and where's in a bit it won't
be a problem for me anymore
so I'm quite happy with the fear and I have put this on with dry her
so it was a bit challenging to put on but if you've got Wester hair I'm
sure be a lot easier and to put your am hair turban on
and another thing to note is and I've got quite long hair so what I do
when I put a towel turban on is I've just fold the excess in so I'm
if you got head that's longer than the length of this and that's what I'd recommend
doing
okay that's all I've really got to sonnet see how few do you want to make
this yourself just and click on the link below and you should be able to download
the PCF that I've created for this thanks for watching by