so I created this the ward proof setting mass which is two days sewing tutorial it's
got a simple strap ground-up
which is held on with a proper or snap pastor that you could easily use a
button or belt crow or some other fastness so that goes round up
one wrap up its folded in a half with the
waterproof side on the inside
so as you can see I've just made a very simple
curved corner square I think there's a better way to say that sicher square
a square with curved curved corners square with curved corners so you are the strap on
the side you've got a nice colorful top layer which is just made out of his
dirty Carson and you've got a waterproof this is more of a canvas see fabric but
it's still very flexible easy to roll up and then on the inside see minds a
little bit crinkly
and it's got a an insulated warding layer so I mean you could use non insulated
warding on Jerold so do the job it just means that if it is a bit
cold where you're going to fit it will hopefully make it a bit more mothy the
idea came about during the pandemic so in the UK in particular they have a lot
of rules about where you could meet people a lot of them revolved around you could
meet more people outdoors or at one point you could only meet people outdoors for social
situations just because the ventilations better and even when
restrictions started easing off people still wanted to sit outside rather than indoors or a lot
people did finally got around to making what was in my head and I thought I
share it
first let's start with what you need so for this project you need half a meter
of your main fabric which will be the top layer
you need half a meter of insulated warding or any warning you have
half a meter of water grief fabric for the base so I used a fairly thick
canvas like fabric and but still had enough flexibility to fold away you also need at
least thirty centimeters of some form of straps so for the one I've made I've used
Hering bone twill tape as I had it to hand but webbing might be more robust
if you have neither you could make a strap from left over fabric you will need
something to
secure your strap such as a snap fastener they'll grow a button or some other sort
of closure you was they need matching thread a quoting foot and a temporary fabric spray
are useful for this project but not as essential to make your template it's entirely up
to you what shape you want to make but if you want to do the same
as me I made a fool to to by forty to centimeter square to begin with
there is an I did this was because I decided to use one sense to me
to seam allowance and I thought a forty by forty finished square would be sufficient once
I have the square base I then used a small plate to soften the corners next
you need to cut out your pieces so I cut out one of the template for
the waterproof base then I cut out one top piece from the template
once the top peace was cut out I attached it to my warding using the temporary
Adisa spray however you could also use pens to keep it in place next I needed
to quote the top layer to the warding peace for this fabric I decided to use
a crisscross pattern but it's entirely up to you how you want to quit your top
layer to the wedding I decided to try to fairly evenly put I'm diamond shapes in
between the dolphins again you might find a quoting fit handy for for this step but
it is an essential especially because insulated boarding isn't that thick so hopefully it using a
regular foot went to Stuart it too much
for the quoting I used one of those friction pens to mark out my lines just
so that I had a guide when I stitched so these are very useful because they
do disappear when you apply heat to it although I think there is a risk that
they then can reappear if it gets too cold and but obviously you could use a
proper fabric pen he could just use the pennant so if you wanted to it's entirely
up to you just bear in mind that it might be worth testing it on a
section of the fabric before you commit to it so once I'd drawn out where I
wanted my quoting lines to go I then moved to the sewing machine I added my
quoting foot and I choose a fairly long stitch as I didn't need the stitches to
be too close together I did all the lines in one direction and then I rotated
it round and did the other lines that intersected once all the lines were stitched I
then moved over to the ironing board and pressed it so that I could remove those
lines that I made with the friction pen once the quoting was done I decided where
I wanted to place the strap so
for this one it was roughly eleven centimeters down from the top what you do is
just line it up with the raw edge so I put up to the left of
the
front peace near the top and I would recommend just I'm taking it in place at
this point I think I forgot to but you could attack it in place first before
moving on to the next step
so the next step is stitching the front and back pieces together for this you can
use quoting clips or you could use pens to attach the bits together I guess I
decided to use quoting clips because I have them to hand and I don't want to
piss the waterproof fabric unnecessarily oversee if you are using pins you could just pin within
that one centimeter seam allowance or whatever seam allowance you decided for yours
so once I'd pinned to the two pieces together all the way around I left a
gap on one edge just so that I could turn it right side out I then
moved over to the sewing machine and stitched the front and back together with the one
centimeter seam allowance
once that was done I then trimmed around the corners so I've used pink inches in
this instance but you could just Antrim it with regular scissors just to help those corners
or the curves come out on the right side
then I flipped it around to the right side out and I used the wooden to
adjust to help me on those corners in particular
one stands right side out and then moved back over to the ironing board and pressed
it to sharpen those corners now its right side out I then got a needle and
thread and hand-stitched the opening closed
then topstitched around the edge I did it one centimeters from the outside edge but you
could bury this if you want to do
the final step was finishing off the raw edge of the strap and adding a fastener
so
in this instance I decided that I wanted my strap to be about twenty five centimeters
in length so I folded the raw-edged two centimeters in and then I folded it in
again and that tucked in the raw edge I then stitched this on the sewing machine
close to the inner folded edge to keep it in place you could also stitch the
other folded edge as well just to make it extra secure
then added the snap fastness so I added one end on that edge where I've got
the folded over layer which is why I didn't bother adding the second line of stitching
so I'd recommend just double checking by folding your sitting Matt and rolling it up just
to check where you want the inside proper to lay further down the strap but in
my instance I think it was a few centimeters from the actual Matt section
so a final step which is entirely optional is I put some brain and stained protectors
prey on the nonword proof side obviously you could make the top layer award people water
resistant fabric and this will help protect it for me I thought it would be nice
to use this particular fabric which wasn't more to resistant or waterproof however I thought this
might help it from getting too McKee when it's out and about so there you have
it there's the waterproof setting that obviously you could do a lot of variations you could
as a loop of elastic instead of a strap and then you could just flip it
round and fasten it like that you could leave having a strap entirely if you don't
want to roll it up will you could make a little drawstring bag for it to
go in you could use a button a buckle Velcro is all sorts of ways you
could vary this depending on what you've got and but I just thought be a good
gift for yourself or for someone else
thanks for watching