today I'm going to show you how to make a simple lined drawstring bag as always
like this video and would might seem more please don't forget to like unsubscribe if you
haven't already so let's go through their materials that you need they need to cut out
to pieces of your main fabric and to pieces of your lining fabric now that will
be the same size so you need to decide how thick you want your draw-string back
to be so I did mine twenty-six centimeters with wise and forty two centimeters tool this
is so that it could fit the sure that I'd made however you can decide on
whatever measurements you want so no dust find out the size of my particular drawstring bag
I measured how white I thought it would need to be for versal and then I
added a bit of extra room and then I added a sent to me that either
side so two centimeters more in total just to add some seam allowance so for their
height I had to not only add the seam allowance I also added a bit for
the casing so for the gaps of the casing I added one a half centimeters and
then I wanted some and a half centimeter top to the drawstring bag of buds to
the where would gather for the casing obviously you could just make a really small top
section or there are some thrusting bags where the drawstring far is the top of the
bag so it's not necessary use any to cut out either some ribbon cotton take whatever
you're going to choose for the trimming for the drawstring section you will need to bits
of ribbon I measured mine at sixty-eight centimeters for the smiths but essentially you need it
to be twice the width of the bag plus about fifteen twenty centimeters have a ruler
to hand and of fabric him it's one of those erasable times
the first act was to put the lining pieces right sides together and then mark where
I was going to turn the bag right side out at the end
so I've decided that I was going to leave and opening at the bottom of the
bag so I've just marked a short line at the base enough to turn the bag
at the end right sides out one centimeter away from the raw edge after that I've
put some quoting clips in just to hold the two pieces together before I saw it
on the sewing machine so we see you could use regular pins if you want to
so I think that all ready to go so that when I do go to the
so machine will stitch down the two long guns and partially on the ottoman next like
we've done to the main fabrics though again like the lining I put the right sides
together for this one instead of putting a marking at the bottom the openings are gonna
be for the casing
so the opening is going to be for the casing for the ribbon or in my
case cotton tape so I've just marked this eight and a half centimeters down because I
want my talk to be seven and a half sense meters tall and then I've just
worked its somehow sons meters down and then another mark a feather one of the house
lens meters down and I've done that on both sides of the bag
they once I'd done that I leave my quoting lips again to secure the two pieces
together into the stitch
once I had both the main underlining fabrics together I lonely data the sewing machine and
stitched the to side edges and the face but making sure that I didn't stitch over
where I put my marking it's also worth noting that I did use the backstitching to
reinforce those openings as well
so at once I've stitched all the way rounds what I did was I trim to
the corners so I've just kept them so that when their turn for outside out they
should have a nice Chris corner and once they were done I then means over to
the ironing board and pressed all the scenes out
I mean the main peace the right way out and then put it into the lining
peace which was still run sides out
then lined them up at the top and again use my quoting clips to secure them
together before leaving it to the same machine and stitching and together
now because I've left a gap in the lining I didn't need to leave a gap
up here so I've just ditched all the way through again with the one centimeter seam
allowance which I'm using throughout
once the stitching was done I was unable to turn the back right side out using
that gap I left in the lining so once it was now obviously you could use
a turning to or some sort all to pick out the corners I then stitched the
gap in the lining or the base of the lining peace
just using a simple slip stitch where the needle and thread
with the hole in the lining an eye then put the mining back into the main
peace matching the corners and the place is also worth pressing their in place just so
you've got the top section nice and secure
next I measured the distance between the top of the bag and the
edge of the halls of the casing so I receive because I planned it to be
some nuts centimeters that is roughly what it turned up to be but then I measured
it on my sewing machine and you to get what she said just so I could
use as a guide
now because the top of this drawstring bag is quite generous
I was to be easier if you do decide to make a smaller top bit over
your casing just because you can either use the markings on your so machine or
you don't have to get as far up the staring machine as I have here but
anyway so once I had stitched the top line for the casing I then use the
edge of my crusta fit as a guide to work out where to evenly sich the
bottom line of the casing
one says to raise of stitching were complete I then go on to adding the carton
tape so I've used the method where you get a safety pin that you attach it
to your take over them and then you guys it through the casing it just gets
a little bit stuck at the same announces just because I didn't stitch these down before
so I ended up using a leap Turner I think and also my turning out to
it just helped widen the casing there at the end so that I could guide the
tapes through so what you do as she put one take through one hole but it
all the way around so leaps back and comes out the same and and then you
need to get your second piece of table ribbon and do the same thing again but
from the other opening on the other side of the bag
finally you need to tie the ends of your ribbon or potentate so I've just done
a simple not on both thesis
so though you have it that's how you make a simple lines drawstring bag obviously there's
a number of ways that you can customize it for yourself and making it a different
size deciding how much overtop you want you can use ribbon cotton tape other trimmings for
the drawstring parts and obviously and it's a great sash master as well and a good
way to store various items that's it for this time thanks for watching