hello so today's video is a bit of a catch up Rileys I'm just going to
go through what I've been up to whether I've been meeting any of the goals I
slept for twenty twenty and what I'm looking forward to next as always it's like this
video I want to see more please don't forget to light unsubscribe if you haven't already
I'll begin with what I've been up to you because I can't actually share a lot
of that so there's a special birthday my family coming up it's actually exactly a week
from the day I'm recording and for that I've made quite a challenging project for me
anyway so I've finally finished that earlier this week which I'm really excited about I think
one of the royal thrills I've got is that I've actually finished it with while over
a week to spare which you know there's quite unheard-of with me I have been known
to finish off making gifts on Christmas day while the persons in the room so yeah
I seem to be improving on that respect I used a pattern for this project so
I'll be able to share a pattern review for that and I'll probably schedule that in
for a couple of weeks' time I made an extra Lisl something as well for this
special birthday and I'm going to share that as the tutorial probably nice week apart from
that I've just been cratering in my spare time so I'm working on another long-term project
it's one of my make nine and yeah I'm just calling along without releasing actually over
half way which is excellent I might actually get on to my second yuan based project
for makes mine say that leads me on nicely into progress on my goals so I
thought I just do a better catch up so well almost two months into the year
so it felt like a good time to review what my goals actually were because I'm
one of those people who said guess what I am striving toward if I don't look
at them regularly throughout the year so in times of my make nine I have got
to of my projects done and the third one as I mentioned as a young base
though on halfway through that which is brilliant the first project I completed was the two
can talk which I've already shared in a couple of videos on this channel the other
one I will share in a couple of weeks once the recipients has opened their gift
I'm not too sure what I'm going to start next to my make mine I was
going to do the Mina dungarees next however I've got distracted by some other projects which
I will share shortly I may possibly make the friar top because I really want want
to put underneath the pinafores I have and obviously if I do eventually get around to
Mason Mila dungarees I'll have an extra top that will go and meet that another goal
of mine was to get through my mending and to you finally get one of my
shop-bought pinafore dress style garments hand which was brilliant so I'm going to try and crack
on with preparing some other items in the next couple of week another goal was to
get on with making special gifts for the special birthdays which as I've mentioned I'm on
track which is fabulous my final section in this roof video is to tell you what
I'm looking forward to and my plans for the next couple of months so I got
this book in the post this week it was a cruel this gift from my sister
which I'm very grateful for so it's the new to me in the buttons book make
it simple and I basically want to make Tom's out with it so I think I
will probably try and do some reviews quite soon so that's my focus over the next
few weeks there's some of the projects in this book as well as lots of good
advice and just some nice quick easy reading as well you know for example we have
got how to make time with the creativity
and as
as always with the books they got lots of different variations for that pattern so you
know if what some elasticated trousers is the first cousin in the book it's the Sophia
trousers but again they show how to make it into a simple comfortable and Harry dungarees
how to put pockets in here there's a couple of different types of pajamas you can
make in here so
yeah I'm not sure where starkly I was going to try and go methodically through the
book
however I don't think that's going to work for me I might possibly make the cardigan
and him fast just because I think it will be the quickest to whip up and
I'm a way
for about a week so I want you to make anything in that time I really
want to make something just before I go away it will of course depend on whether
I have time it is a bowl of other things to prepare for the best day
that's coming up and I've just got to so out my flat as well because what
might be making that other project everything's gonna just got about a while say so it
would be nice to get something done but I'm not sure I may possibly just end
up having enough time to make the sleep mask which has very cute that is the
birth or card again is the one I'd like to make first ideally because I think
I could potentially make it straight away and I have some fabric which I want to
make it out of have this lovely reds net fabric which has a lot of drapes
to it as you can see this is the fabric that I meant to make my
Nana cardigan out of
just over a year ago and I accidently cut into the one fabric which you'll probably
be able to hear a brief explanation of in my putter review of the Bibi pinafore
and possibly when I reviewed the kinda cardigan because that's the cardigan that the past and
I used to make her cardigan with but yeah essentially I had to
to fabrics that looked the same or similar color but they were quite different in their
structure of and thickness
and I would have much preferred into barken out there so the best the card again
I think I've got more than enough here I might be able to make to so
perhaps I can a twin it with my sister
we will see but I'll definitely want to give that a game first it's just whether
I can make it before I go away for a week beyond standing to the in
the buttons book I also have a trouser passing cutting course coming up which I'm really
excited about I don't make an offer all the trousers and I don't actually where a
local of trousers I much prefer wearing dresses if I do wear trousers that only something
like jeggings it may be that ready to our trousers all the transit I have tried
to make just on the right cart and I haven't been able to fit it well
to myself so it will be really interesting to see how you do adapt
trials a person for yourself because that's definitely a weakness in my sewing I believe that's
how much time and it's over a few weeks because it's in the evening after work
I wouldn't have a pair of Travis at the end or just have a block and
probably I'm a virgin made out calico which I can then adapt to make trousers for
myself that's pretty much it for my catch up I hope you've enjoyed this it's just
useful for me to just review where I am and where the is going next week
I plan to be back with a short tutorial for you thanks for watching