hello today I'm showing you a video of a recent birthday card that I made using
free machine embroidery so as you can see it's a picture of a cat wearing a
party hat and sitting in front of a birthday cake
obviously I don't recommend but in your cat right by a lit candle but this is
just for humorous effect
okay so to start with I traced a drawing of a cat's so I looked online
for something that looked like the idea I had in my head
just to give me something to face my drawing off so I found a picture of
a real cat that was sitting in front of the cake I then drew my own
version from that so I drew a more I guess comic looking cat
and I didn't outline of this I then drew it on the computer so I used
a simple drawing software the one I've got his Leonardo
and with this I printed it off to the size I wanted that would fit my
card template so once I'd printed off the design in the size that I wanted they
would fit on to my piece of card I used a fabric pen which would vanish
over time I have used the water soluble fabric hands but I don't if it's just
the one I was using or it's the quality of the thread I'm using I think
I'm his hope and see not that great I think the color from the thread the
die from it was running and obviously that's not a brilliant effect that you want on
your final design so to begin with I used a thread to go all the way
around my design so think on the plate and the cake I used a black thread
and I used a gray thread around the cats
and you can see a wasn't too happy how I did the eyes on the cats
I was trying to make them look a bit more realistic like cats and but in
the end I just went for a classic cartoon dot eyes just because they're so much
easier to do in free machine embroidery
and yeah I've obviously got some hang often doing other style eyes C s once I'd
correct at the eyes I carried on going round to the design so I added a
little sort of pompom onto the top of the birthday hat so for the tabby markings
I switched my machine stitch setting to a zigzag variation I actually use the ones where
it varies from short zigzag to long
as you can see so it kind of added a bit more texture to the design
so I'd really recommend that if you're doing a bit free machine embroidery have a go
at some of the other stitches they can come out quite nice you could always just
use you don't even need to use the free machine embroidery fit on that section you
could have just had it on the regular precipice and but I mean it's I guess
you've got a bit more control on how place the stitches are and it's just I'm
because I was obviously using the three machine fit start with I would have had to
take in that off and you know put another press the foot back and so just
a bit laziness really that I stuck with the free machine foot as well for the
markings on the face I went down to the Smalls' exact setting so will we see
if you do you have a machine which where you can adjust the stitch wits as
well as the length I think mine only does length but if you do have one
week and and adjust the with you can oversee I'm completely table at that which is
excellent for the face because you don't want the the tabby markings to be quite as
weitere
so once I was happy with all of the stitching for this particular card I decided
to use some fabric pastorals so I just had these I'm hanging around from when I've
done textiles in the past I'm facing this cat or my nans cat so this was
a card for my Nance and so as a result so she's got a ginger happy
but quite a pale ginger to be so I was trying to trying to get the
tone correct for her cat I will say use the pastor's to create the color on
the plate the cake the candlestick and the hats with these past was basically you can
put a bit on the fabric and then use a bit of water to help spread
it and lighten the shade and as you can see the near the plate it has
actually run a bit over the line marks though it's just something to be aware of
if you do decide to use them yourself
okay so that's the end results I hope you enjoyed this video and as always if
you do want to see more content please don't forget to like unsubscribe if you haven't
already thanks for watching