hello today I'm sharing a time-lapse video of me making a birthday card with a dog
on it
so it's a bit some of the to one I've made recently I made a cat
birthday card so this is essentially my dog variation so I've gone for a Jack Russell
and this occasion just because the person who I've made it for has a Jack Russell
at home in whether to create the design similar to what I did for the cat
design I had a look on line at some real life pictures of Jack Russell's I
think I actually found one of a Jack Russell who found a picture of a Jack
Russell with a party horn in its mouth so that worked out pretty well to begin
with I went around the whole of the outline of my design as before I mainly
focused on creating an outline from the picture so I had a look at the picture
then sketched out a rough outline that I could use for my design and noted any
extra details on to add such as the face features the nose the eyes and but
also obviously Jack Russell's have quite distinctive markings so I had a look at that as
well I began by going around the whole of the outline I just find this a
lot easier when I'm doing free machine embroidery and I've got the stitch length to zero
and I'm just using a simple straight stitch I'm using a plain black threads just because
I want it to have a really strong outline
once I got around the main details I then added some circles to the hat just
for some extra detail
once I was done with the black threads I moved on to a brown color and
started to shade in so on this cards I did a bit more coloring him with
pastilles last time but this time I want to do everything in the stitch I'm moving
the
fabric a bit quicker than before just because I want the shade I don't want it
to be a solid bit of brown color I'm trying to make it a bit more
shaded and looked like fair it's probably quite hardly in this recording but I'm stitching in
a way that I believe the for would fall on on the dog if that makes
sense
and I'm adding a bit more
stitching or closer range stitching on the edges of the is just that it's
up that way it just adds a bit more shading and makes it look a bit
more realistic not that actually think that looks like a real dog obviously looks like a
cartoon
for the posse hat I used a multicolored thread which I'd picked up when I found
some gutterman thread half price and hobby craft last year
for the circles I decided to pick up an orange thread and I colored them all
in in orange
finish up with I colored the party horn in a blue color
so that's it for today I hope you enjoyed this video has always if you like
this video please don't forget to like and subscribe if you haven't already and I'll see
you next time