hello today I'm sharing you a time-lapse of a guitar card I made for my dad
and my dubs very and to music and I thought he had appreciate this so to
start with I had a quick search online to find the outline of a guitar as
I wanted to
make it I just wanted the silhouette
say once I found one on my phone I then drew out roughly how big the
card was going to be and as I had some card templates at home
then sketched out the guitar outline that found online will they obviously you could print it
out and then draw around it and to save yourself sketching us out and I come
of people that to do that so once I have done the rough outline I just
need in the top of it as I broccoli sketched it to start with and then
made their lines a bit more prominent
then choose an embroidery hoop I was using machine embroidery for this when you use the
hoop you need to make sure the fabrics really thought this a that this it stitches
through really well once I've done that I got a fabric pen because the fabric outside
to used and was light enough I could trace through easily from the piece of paper
once I had the outline and drawn on to my fabric I then moved on to
the sewing machine
so to start with I
went around the whole of the outline a few times to really get that section to
stand out
you can see that I decided to use a multicolored thread and this is a Christman
thread I just thought and as I was keeping the design fairly simple it would highlight
and this lovely choice of third
one both been through the outline I then decided to change to a different stitch
I decide to look at some of the extra fancy stitches on my sewing machine so
you can see of use
one of the exact stitches there and with free machine embroidery sometimes they don't come out
brilliantly but it again it's just about how fast you move the fabric under the needle
and
which way around you decide to guide it as well so and you can get some
really nice events there I was just experimenting here essentially so I went around different ways
I think in the end I found my preferred stitch to use
and stuck with that for the most part but I have experimented with a few of
the decorative stitches
once I finished that I cut off all the least threats and then taken out of
dean broidery who I did say you press it with a lion which you can see
on the video
now the way that I stick
machine embroidery on to card templates as I use double-sided tape and list so things that
you could take it off the card if you want to do after using it as
a card
so I just roughly and draw the tape along and Custer as you can always hold
double-sided tape in on its don't fit still going to stick and yeah I just cover
the whole of the front surface that the meeting sticks on really well
let's find it quite hard placing
their design on to
onto the piece of cards so you can see here I'm trying to measure a sacculus
Lee so that I can get it century on to the best of part we see
this bells rely on your card being very accurate and Lucy
during measurements being accurate you can see here I wasn't happy with the original alignment
but you can just take it up again and then I replied it
double check for measurements one so happy with it I then pressed it on firmer
then need my rotary cutter
neatly around the edges
give it another press down and that's pretty much it