hello today I'm going to show you how I rethread my overlocker from scratch other way
that you like this video I'd like to see more please don't forget to like unsubscribe
if you haven't already as I mentioned before I have the singer fourteen FH seven five
for model which is a budget range of a locker the easiest way to refresh your
overlook it is to do the tion method where you tie the old threads to your
new colored thread and pull it through with attention this to zero however I'm now going
to show you how to read read it from scratch it's really important to know how
to do this because it can result a lot of issues for you if there are
some reason it's just not playing for with you a key way to result that is
to rethread the machine it could be that is either gone wrong somewhere so there's a
bit where it should be hooked on that it isn't him or it could be another
reason where rethreading would just resolve the matter for you it's definitely one of the things
to consider if you just can't get attention right is to just right rethreading it it
might actually resolve the problem for you the doxie times you have to do it as
well for example if a thread snaps and which again prophecy could be attention issue but
you do have to to thread your machine in a particular order so if you don't
rethread the one that's broken it could actually mess up the whole system and then it
won't overlock as it's designed to so it's always best to if it's
the first regiment to thread you've got to redo all of them theoretically okay so on
my next project I want to use this black threat so I'm going to take you
how to thread its first thing to do is to open up the
and then I can see all the different
areas that I will need to thread the machine so on mine I've got this very
useful gauge which is very handy and so it tells me that I need to thread
the red and colocated one first which is this one here and then I need to
move over to the next Luke reference and finally I do the needles at the top
but even the needles are actually labeled three and four so I'm just going to follow
the exact order to be safe something you do need to remember and before you start
completely because you are returning it from scratch you don't have to actually set your attention
this to zero you can if you want to but you do need to remember to
put it back up to the correct tension so you can just leave it for example
and I'm going to put mine to three next because I need to work out the
correct tension for my new project
so I'm gonna put it out there for now just because I'm nice again another thing
you need to do is make sure the press of it is up because this will
disengage those tension size so just check
okay so my precedents already up the last line and Kate so first things first I'm
going to just quickly Loti's onto the school's at the back
as I mentioned the first one that I need to threat is this one so I'm
just going to loosely put it into the guide at the top
and then going to attach it
there's a little hook at the top that it needs to leap around
so I've just added it there you need to make sure it goes straight through the
attention to scare nice and cleanly so it's always good to essentially help up and talk
about the thread thought just make sure it's sandwich likely into the tension lisk the the
hook lower down one this machine so you need to make sure that that's that you're
thread it is hooked in there
and then you continue down there still so
as I mentioned before you can see exactly where you need to Fred on this machine
there's also colocated dots so I'm just going to cook it on to all those bits
the final destination for this set of red is to go through
lupa so that's the needle it comes across on your fabric that I'm going to give
my tweezers here
I put the bread at the front corner just because I've been talked previously to put
the lever threats towards the front to start with and then the needle threats towards the
back and option what about the house but apparently back and
get rid of potential issues as well so the next one only to thread is the
other leap at witches to my machine the yellow color-code so again and will put it
around the glide
touch of the top here
make sure it's sandwich nicely in the attention
and as the attached
make sure it's leaped
underneath is
now this is possibly the worst thread that you have to threaten so you start off
nicely
so again you got a nice collar code system that's all simple just make sure it's
snapped into those sections then it starts to get over a tricky
so that one is not too bad
then as you can see on
on the diagram here then has to leap up behind
a section of the machine so the needle that is eventually going to loop through you
have to draw up behind that
and then it hooks on a bit at the corner
and then you threat it through the eye of the legal so this is definitely the
worst part and on other models you can undo this section of the machine and you
can see the other side then although it can get thus to that model of machine
it's too much easier to read at this point so yeah this is definitely that I
got frustrated but so is gonna do my best
they have just managed to get it around the back of that needle and I'm just
going to
hold on to this section and not it with
with my tweezers
until it attaches to that little hook at the end
okay by fluking house sauces in place just then I would move it around a little
bit with the dial if it's not quite in the right position it is then and
there that was easier for catching it on the corner I know need to move it
to be able to Trent the eye of the needle
again I'm going to use the pleases that came with the machine
and threat that through
case once more I've got the loop of thread at the front okay so the next
thread to threaten is number three which is green on my machine which is less tension
dial
to find the end of this one
hip on the guide once more and touch it the back
make sure it goes through the tension desk so on the green thread
you need to
has guided on the diagram
there are two books that goes through and then it goes up on this topless again
is colocated on this machine which helps
and you need to throw it on to needle
an excellent rounds and the five and then again these teasers are really useful for threading
the needle
so with the
needle threats I going to pull them towards the back corner finally I'm going to read
the final needles rent again up over the guide
across that bit at the top
talks through their now on the blue thread that you do need to move that again
on the same one at the second hook that the green threat is also one but
it goes through its own guide in this section
and you loop that true for needle be
and once more
the needle
know that the machine is fully threaded I'm going to put the process it down
through all this right together towards the back
I can close that I see if you did leave the tension this is zero you
can now ruddles the tension and although I haven't got any public air on just going
to test that the machine is running smoothly so
switched on
so that looks like it's all threaded up fine it's coming out in this sort of
strange
for thread chain which is normal for this machine so the next step I do is
to get a track piece of the fabric I want to use and how to go
ahead and start adjusting and fine-tuning the tension so that it's perfect for that project Hey
that's it for this time thanks for watching