hello today I'm going stream how I made this
as always did like this video and like to see more please don't forget to light
and subscribe if you haven't already so this was originally a perfect my mom patches from
a charity shop and I think she'd been holding on to it for a bit and
one time of this to her she asked whether I'd like to cover it so originally
had this saw a pinkish up history fabric over it as it turned out it was
within another cover
so originally it was a leather purse but that stuck boarding all over the outside anyway
I'll let you watch the highlights of making it it was a very long makes so
I will have edited it down quite substantially and then I'll give some feedback on how
I felt it went at the end
to begin with I unpicked the cover that was on the fifth as he can see
in the footage it was quite a simple task actually I was quite surprised at how
easy it was to unpick us
and it probably took me about half an hour in total I did externally ripped the
top peace and I didn't if it's just because the fabric was old or maybe I
was a bit harsh with it
I did retrieve the
I'm called out of it as well I originally thought I was going to use it
in the project but in the end I didn't end up using it the next I
measured the pieces from the original from cover to give me an idea on a template
so I measured to get a refined there and then I transferred this onto paper
to get some paper pattern pieces
you can see how I've used a simple ceramic bowl to make the curved edges once
I got the main template I then added a seam allowance around the edge
for the sides I made one long narrow strip so I for the past in peace
I did half the length just to save on paper
for the cover I decided to use some simple calicoes so I had quite a bit
at home anyway
and to be honest this first covered and take an awful lot of calico anyway
it will be a nice plain base material for us
so I saw the two short ends together for the side panel peace and then I
cut in little notches into one of the bases
as you can see here I'm trying to pin it together but
I realized that the measurements didn't work out properly together or they weren't the the original
measurements weren't uniform enough so it wouldn't fit on properly so why I ended up doing
was fitting it around the first taking in the side panel a little bit more because
I hadn't done it twice enough and then I pinned the base peace all the way
round
killing it by I just gave it a much tight of it
once I was happy with how I'd pinned it I then tact that into place
once tucked in place I went to the sewing machine and soda and place
once own in place I then put their cover back on to see how it fitted
and I was pretty happy with that and then I tucked in the top raw edge
of the exposed side just again idea of how it would sit level
once I was happy with that I put a couple of pins and to keep it
into place and then took the cover or I pressed into place and then I trimmed
the raw edge just so it was a bit more even although it wouldn't be on
a show I thought it might show slightly
through the fabric once trimmed I then put the top piece
into place and started pinning it round but this time I couldn't do it and with
it inside out I needed to do it the right way up
I noticed on the
that pinkish and fifty cover that I unpicked from it though one panel peace had been
stitched in by hand and I realized that and that was the only way that I'd
be able to do it so that's why I did next I then hand-stitched all the
way round did a simple slip stitch and gradually secured in place the whole way around
once the whole of the base cover with an eye then made a cover over the
top of this so you can see her I'm pinning my original person template into place
and I folded it under to try and mold it to the new shape of the
one side have you that I took it off
then I went about to cut to pieces also wanted the top and a base passing
piece from this however I needed to add a seam allowance on to this I say
seam allowance just them there him all the way around so I added two centimeters to
the outside of it and with the talk and
then pressed one sent me to in on the edges and then a further one centimeters
and stitch that in place to Nathan the edges
I cut out the cat piece from the other fabric I had
so I tried to
have it barely centered in the panel that I cut out I then measured the peace
that I'd cut out and went about to find a nice central place on the top
of the earth they used a fabric pen to mark out the rectangle ready for having
it as reverse plicae
so to start with I stitched along the fabric pen line just to reinforce the rectangle
next I
marked I think it was about one centimeter in from that stitching line in order to
cut out a bit of the calico and then clipped the corners
and impend the cats that fabric into place then moved up to the so machine and
stitched it in place close to the edge of the rectangular opening
with the top and bottom pieces ready for the outer layer of the path
then marked holds to add blanket stitch to the top and bottom pieces
so I decided to leave one sent me to gap between each hole and I'm using
an all to poke a hole into it
so I go a bit carried away here as you might be able to see so
I got a done needle out and just tested what it would look like before I
pissed all the other holes say I
looked like I did a a fair few stitches just to see what it looked like
and then when I was happy with it I carried on and poked the rest of
the holes
around the edges
so I needed to poke holes into both the top and bottom pieces because this is
how I was going to add my side panels and
by koshering
one side packed all the holes through the fabric by then carried on with my blanket
stitch adding blanket search the edge of both the top and bottom pieces
blanket stitch was around the top and bottom pieces I could add the
side panel
so I creatures the sides for this cover anyone who's seen my the three that's on
my sofa will know that these are the same square design and also some of the
same Yun's that have used for this just so it will tie and nicely with the
lounge so what I'm doing here as I'm double koshering the crocheted square panel to the
base piece of the cover so I'm using the blanket stitch edge in order to double
Croatia up to the edge of those squares and essentially is why did I attach the
base peace the whole way round with double crochet and then I flipped it over and
added the top peace in exactly the same way
okay so that's the summary of how I made this but this to recap I obviously
it made a face cover and that's all in calico which I had at home so
originally I did use templates but because it was such a strange shape obviously because it
is an old person and it's probably gilded distorted by the time I ended up having
to just winger and pen at once I've made the base layer I then made a
talk piece of base peace and by crochets the side panels these approaches words are the
ones that I have come the throw in my lunch on the safer so originally I
approached twenty forswears because I thought that would be enough and then I realized once I
don't see any course was that it needed a little bit more so I approach it
another for the fabric on the fault is from the purse that I already had so
that's a much larger one which I recovered with my mom years ago and this was
just a remnant so I didn't have an awful lot of the fabric left it used
to be I think it was an ikea Kherson anyway was quite a small panel and
was obviously centered the only giant cat on this panel for the other Pathak so on
this one I only had one cats left and it's one of the smaller cats so
it's quite nice is and so it not towards the other pursed as equally it's got
a small the cat to go proportion with the smaller poeticize because I didn't have enough
fabric I wanted to allocate on to the top originally I was just going to be
around the outline and that I realized a much better way to do it wants to
essential to reverse of the hay and and create this window which I'm really happy with
and had even all to go and controls to do blanket stitch desiccants I received on
a double Pam on here and it was why hard to puncture a blunt needle into
the calico so my reflections after making it I'm really happy with it it's come out
just as I imagined actually which is great I am a little bit concerned that this
caligo might not be substantial enough I'm not sure how long that will last and but
saying that you know Zuma's I look after hopefully of all lost by a long time
one issue is that you can't take the cover off and or you need to recruit
sure echo and which would take a long time and I'm sure I would be that
make collated so what I have done and this was went on the suggestion as well
as I put some rain and stain protector and so it protects materials so I think
I put this at the same the market at some point I actually bet on the
show the bag or made the Debbie show of this back
and because that's kind of made out of the needle cord and I was worried right
again the rocky so I have I did spring back with this as well don't just
put it all over and hopefully that will give it a fair resistance disdains and getting
McKee yeah they were I'm really happy I think it's a lovely besides that which is
the reason why I wanted to recover it in the first place obviously if you don't
have one to cover yourself or redesign what you can do is to seven managements so
like he did that the start when I made the Paston I mean I could use
those pieces to make them almost a replica of this it would just be a lot
more uniform in shape if that makes sense it in this is quite nice sides actually
for if you're into meditation as well because it's not too high off the ground but
just enough to and elevate your hips above your feet and sometimes I quite like to
and sit closer to the ground work is why we still do you have a chronic
back health issue and I find it really beneficial just set more in a meditative pose
because it can help improve my posture or at least I hope it does any way
by that it for this time I hope you enjoy that uncertainly happy lot of was
a new bit of they call in my house it sit for this time thanks for
watching