today I'm going to show you how you can read your overlocker with the tight on
methods as always that you like this video it might seem or please don't forget to
like and subscribe if you haven't already as I mentioned before I've got the singer fourteen
as to age seven five for model this is a budget overlocker machine and I thought
it might be quite useful just to show how you can thread the overlocker so there
are two methods there's the I'm try on method when you cut this I'm your current
threats you tie your new color on and then you put it through the machine and
then there is the other version where you read it completely from scratch so today I'm
going to show you the tire methods I do only have three overlooker sense in here
at the moment I'm missing one of the needles but that's fine it's so it's the
same method if you had for you just have an additional needle thread so for this
you will need some scissors so I've just got my embroidery ones just because they're the
supersharp and I quite like using him and for some tweezers preferably the ones that came
with your overlocker or once designed for an oval are that just because they're the right
shape if that makes them quickly before you start changing the threads on your overlocker be
sure to make sure that it is switched off to first thing I'm going to do
is I'm going to move all of the dials to zero
so I'm the needle for the blue thread on my machine that ones already on zero
because I don't have the left needle in place of the moment
but I'm going to move the other ones and a good tip for this is to
take a photo of your current tension settings now east will still need to test your
attention when you
have the new threats in place and it will always depend on what fabric you got
but it is really still to do that because it could be that
you know the tension is still fine and then at least you know what settings you
had originally so when mine I've got the best for three three I'm not actually in
the noted down this time because I was testing out a wrong man and that to
happen to use it as a road hand this time
so I'm just going to put it to zero and then I'll probably just put it
to the standard settings for this machine which is to put all of the tension disks
to three
it's not their own on zero or a plastic line on this case you then need
to cut your threats at the top so I'm just gonna cut them about halfway
and then you can remove them
I'm going to add my new threats so I'm just going to do a simple double
not
but I will just make sure
it's tight enough so that white undy when I fall the registry
case now I've put all of my black thread tied onto the end of the white
threads that were in there I've got the attention just to zero so that there won't
be any friction when they moved through and just games a check that the at all
open this man
and this against it that the needle is up properly so it's fully up so that
won't get in the way either
now all I've got left to do is to draw and thread through Oh I need
to move the oppressor but up as well
as that would get it in the way so what you do is
you find the end
and you just
carefully through
so might they might be about a fraction at the top when it goes through the
the little metal guides at the top sometimes that can affect a
case of the lower loopers will just come Terry nicely
and then you just cut off the excess you have to be a bit careful with
the needle threat just because you can't get the not through the eye of the needle
what you'll need to than once you've cut off the end of the white red
you will then need to put it out of the needle and then cut the loss
off
and then you can use your Keyes's to rethread that back in place
so something I got tourte is to have your
lupa's reds and at the front here and you put your
needle threads towards back and before you put your press of it back down finally so
you can close that up
but the next thing you need to do is to put your attention disks back up
to and whatever something you did have previously or in my case I'm going to put
it to three so that I can then when I got money fabric an I can
make out what the correct tension into the particular fabric so you haven't that's definitely the
simplest way to rethread your overlocker it's not less painful than rethreading it from stretch if
you can do that if the tensions completely finally haven't snapped any of the threats this
is the method I've definitely recommend however if you are having issues for tension or any
other problems with your opa-locka I would definitely recommend rethreading its and scratches that can at
least emit some of the potential problems you're having that's it for this time thanks for
watching