today I'm going to discuss my sewing plans for July as always if you like this
video like Seymour please don't forget to lighten subscribe if you haven't already I don't normally
do this sort of video which is quite a typical sewing blogger one mainly because I'm
really bad at commencing to the plans I make so I'm very good at going yeah
I want to create this and then I just don't get it achieved but especially within
a month however I had a change of heart recently and I thought why not give
it a go for July as I have quite few things I'd really like to achieve
I'm feeling a bit more motivated serving wise and I've picked some quite carefully planned makes
which I'm hoping we'll get achieved due to the nature of them spoke the first one
I want to share with you is that I'm looking at completing another of my twenty-twenty
mate line makes which is the various Wester so I want to do the one with
the marks neck line but I want it to be elbow life now originally I had
actually used the fabric eyeball Celeste it was the white fabric I used for my Juno
short pajamas I used that fabric for the t-shirt because I thought we were really well
with that so I did end up using that fabric there is some of it left
over I don't know if there is enough to make another talk maybe there's enough to
make a patchwork top eventually but I can't find the remnants for the life of me
I'm not sure where I'd visit so what I'm going to do is I'm going to
use the remnant fabric that I used to make my journey dress reason in choosing this
fabric is because it's got a decent amount stretching it it's quite solid it wasn't it
doesn't I'm
stretcher and losers
color is that makes sense some subunit fabrics kind of go a bit faded if they
get stretched too much because it is the next of keys in the Freya sweater I
wouldn't want I'm but I'm color distortion to show when it was stretched so I think
I've got enough here I'm pretty confident I do
so hopefully you can see where I cut it out Hey I'm hoping that this will
turn into the talk because it will go nicely underneath and the upcycle denim to Oh
I made the other years and it will probably go over
from we go under a couple of other pantoufles I've got as well although it is
a passant fabric I think it's on a nice simple design which will be quite versatile
before I get round to my make line project for this month I'm probably going to
finish off a different projects so
I've mentioned this in different Instagram challenges before this is a very unbrokenly tried and tested
passen of mine which is the mickles seven six seven five and its to make some
shorts so I clearly got this at some point or someone has got it for me
from a charity shop the pass inside is perfect for me I've made it before to
make the drama shorts regulations and it turns out it I had already caught out this
project so I think I got this out about two years I originally this fabric is
from some pajama shorts to I made for my partner built and I thought I'd break
myself a matching that and
you can tell I got to the casting stage and never actually go around to finishing
them up so this product is ultimately ready to go which is why I think it's
really the first one I'm going to make this one I haven't caught out pockets yet
actually but I might add some in team pockets just because it's always nice to have
progress I freely went out the patch pockets
but the grubbing will be there short shorts because I don't think I've got any more
of this fabric kicking around to as the little
extra bit of length on that so says fabric might have been really suitable to use
with amber get it got stripes ever we could have done I go out UI I
was there won't be quite the same effect because these aren't standard stripes and but I'm
working with the remnants of caught hair and I must have cut this out two years
ago and never around to it so I might do a pattern review of this one
before ever mentioned I have made this passing up a few times I haven't done it
in at least unit but it would be good to document my false on it another
plan of potentially got for July is to make a swimsuits now it's not that I
particularly need one and obviously at the moment the pools aren't open around where we live
I'm not sure if that in a change soon or whether will want to go and
we do live right by a beach but because it's the ocean it it's freezing cold
and I am probably more in trying to go into the sea in a wet sepal
at least more and more covered up the one seat than the one I'm going to
show you that the reason I want to make this is I do have some fabric
which will bring me what for it and it is a pattern I've got in my
stash which looks quite straightforward to make to be honest now that I've got a bit
more familiarity using stretch Roberts so it's in these style three three four six you can
tell it's been so really take that
time soon on greasy someone's I'm trying to look after it beforehand but it looks like
I'm I must have got it from a tiny shop again for someone else got up
on my behalf so yeah it is the begin in which I wouldn't say I'm a
huge bikini van but it's quite like the designed so for Paul to neck talk it's
elasticated at the back for the backstrap and what you do is there's a tie of
the front so you just do it not at the front of the bikini top and
even with the briefs its Scots and and last you you create case things for the
elastic so you're not even stitching the elastic and having to be careful with gauging how
much you stretch the but recall that you are literally just applying the past plastic and
you are literally applying the elastic after you've done a casing and then ceiling it up
and securing it so I think that might be quite a fun project so the fabric
of gods
as she got when I did the course and it was them they were peering out
there fabric supplies of stuff they weren't likely to use for the sort project they did
that so it is this interesting for design I think it might be quite challenging to
cut out but saying that I've got such a limited amount of it I'm just going
to have to cut it and whichever way it fits on and which away the pass
and pieces spit on the fabric so I'm pretty sure it's suitable swimmer that broke really
quite good at the gym's up as well I'm not sure if I will get around
to this one but I've got it that ready and waiting and as I say it's
fairly straightforward I think one of the most challenging parts will be coming the pieces out
of the start moving on to some gift making so both of my niece's their birthdays
are coming up shortly so I want to get some get sorted for them so the
first one is my younger nice and I'm just waiting for some measurements actually for my
sister but I would quite like to make this a little romper dressed for them so
I'd really like to give this after let go and but I do feel like because
there is such as well window for them to merits I'm not sure whether it will
be a suitable choice so well there would like to make I'm at this month I'm
not sure I will and I was only to choose the fabric but I'm sure but
something somewhere in my search but I'm gonna wait for the measurements first then about broad
time I would and try to make that being on to my other nice and I
did get our request to make a Unocal dress so I purchased this uniform and fabric
from fabric land last time I visited so it's a
simple cotton fabric but I thought that would fit the bill of the main request I
got and because I want to show off the pattern I've come for quite a simple
dress design I think possibly changed my mind on this but it is a really nice
simple design pattern this is actually from prima and it as she comes with a lady's
Dressel well I'm going for the girl dress which has showed a size at the top
to essentially quiet front in fact attach it together create a casing at the top of
the front and back pieces and then you gather through I'm some fabric ribbons you make
and you can reach out tie up the boats which will then fall on each stronger
I think this would look quite nice and this fabric I mean possibly do the tides
in a different fabric possibly even just white or I'll see what other fabrics I've got
I'm hanging around at home but ye can I'll be quite a fun enjoyable simple make
which who pollution appreciate I've already mentioned quite a lot of makes by this point and
that's kind of my my core make goals for July and I'm not even expecting this
as I really to finish all of that I'd like to get the gifts definitely done
and I get the shorter pretty much a certain I'm else's the phrase I said and
the swimsuits more of a bonus make but I do have two additional Poulos makes which
I would like to make this one I'd like to make some more talks that can
go on to the different killable as I have I'm sure of lots people who have
jumped to the pinnacle bandor again and made all the doubly different plants to pentacles you
can in the sewing twenty will realize quite seen that use and lots find suitable talks
to go underneath them so I'm going to rectify that I'm also using a fabric that
I got from my last fabric land shop so I have these two tea shirting fabrics
as this one here which I think you might still be up to get on the
other landwards like and this one here so I think both of these will go quite
nicely underneath the different pinafores I have one of them I quite like to make into
another Frankie t-shirts and thinking possibly this yellow but I might drink my mind the other
one I'd like to make into a tub of the teacher so I do have this
white gripping fabric it doesn't quite match the them whites color on these consistence a bit
more cream I'd say and but it's the closest thing that I have so which everyone
says turning to the top of the t-shirts and will have this for the I'm going
to do the version with the cuff bands so I'll do that and for the cups
as well as the neckband so I was gonna say that's it for my plans makes
but it's obviously quite a lot so that's what I'm hoping to achieve this month will
see how much I actually get through
I hope you enjoyed this and I'll see you next time thanks for watching