and welcome back I just thought I do a quick catch up for this week as
I haven't really made anything but I won't say what I have been doing and what
I planned to do over the next week a partisan failed my fellow social distant single
body national she was before now that we're not that were promising but living together before
the event and
yes I honestly as were from the same household we can be this place yeah there
I've made me been doing about well exacting missing but I've been sewing up some listed
squabs because I finished the other products are you doing I would share it but as
it to get of one Terrence and not for a while anyway and but yeah I
have got another one make mine completed the call of that collapsed and yet so what
we've done to you and onion waste project which is this are missing through which
I saw it absolutely years ago
for you is probably like at least a definite hope it's one of those city things
yeah where they give you
the magazine every week the board of world you meant to make a sweat and you
think you know and then gradually and bring to make this very minute to just keep
local bowl aside and it never gets done so it's been to be made out of
line it was the times at how about she made over half of them I just
haven't
asked me so I called down the other heart I have kept kept all all the
wall I don't think about the instructions for the knights of life now
I'll just make them out for just a small part to cedrus looking stage where you
will have only by frantic adjust your rouble night but yes if this week I managed
to sew up some of the priest and some of this one's together so that the
a bit more manageable it actually takes us uprising like a planter so up nine slides
with backstitch
so see I've done the best lock of mine
and
I just finished the second block of mines well
so another thing mentions I have been missing the flares in the warder I get so
I've got
probably like say why ever have missed it up first I can't make
sense of mine I call it all up story away for it is I need to
finish some of the other squares because I've been just getting their fancy don't not masses
you know I'm tired of stuffing such are going to I'm going to do one of
the chainstitch heart and and sent
I guess the ones I for about the most so ones where you're doing a person
so
like on this one to missing up the treat
this somehow again the words to that so
yeah it's been a very slowly and so this is a hand like wavy leather stitched
and going on know
that yet we I don't know it's one of those but I like the ones where
you don't have to change the young color and you doing a bit pattern so isn't
she that when I was making this originally I started just prioritising with those so-called as
of what I time as Delawares to make now but I kind of feel like now
is a good time as I need to finally get up onto this and I would
quite like to put this time in the end on the answer was quiet and let
that you live in front of the agreement at the moment at the cooler
heaven and so it might replace the green through all my also to you got time
of the terror munching on the left surrounded it you say that but I'm still of
the work remaining niggaz tree and you start a new job so for the company has
its usual prevailing yeah I'm all they saying like you haven't been in Europe for that
but I know to his long a few months
now working extra days is idolizes for
so
it's exhausting
if I hadn't happened right here it's mainly due to patentable the about work than that
let's make sure that they can work mostly
shuttle June anabolic systems which
haven't been testing the Sobibor to us all new territory under so because I'm you things
well we're both using
this kind of misero so I got a craft Romans and so for a corner of
this room where did have a death and so he's using Mr thanks there at the
movements and feverously I've had to use the room as well to work remotely so it's
kind of encouraged of my right normally so
many quite particular but having the your special so in space use the element of the
intrusion to the manage to
you know I guess the trouble is
over seeking way I see some face and we don't have to commute to the moment
which is fancy but I'm so not getting grounds are just clearing of the table of
wine the saliva news is you you no trace and that our passengers I'm just finding
that part because I've been back much of my mind Oh great again after that little
up again in the morning and and especially ribbon you know we're free long sleeping this
world and for that stretchable was given so
getting up to that later below to trinity so I don't really want to be setting
out and this munting it continually it's just nice to have out there really came from
it like having a craftly that's the one to tell you were gonna take notice the
table in our living area of the minute but what I'm going to do leaving for
it is tracing the patent I want to do to the next to you projects and
how the fabrics overly do that in the next day also yet with the stuff cut
out the projects now you know to the moment or so far on that and then
hopefully you know when I am on my laundry before another work I can just take
after their and still it is said that I get it up the family bring forward
some you can ever work and I am making project from that and to Boston make
it some will use we shall give you a guide on the time spruced-up so I
think my last video is that our stated going to with the olive pinnacle or disappear
dungaree next however I shall change my mind it is some gripping Babatunde of and in
the the grave of sweet so now I'm thinking I might make the genome Germans but
breathing treat the short sension but the teachers the duchy the side of the teachers other
so I just think they will be and deceit the game from the the book it
stated that
kind of like need to sit with to make to wait me and don't think and
I get used to of neurotically going to wind down a side of work
with you you so you see what the UK government currently it's obviously this can change
by the time I report at the time I had it and publish this video at
the amendment the UK government is an allowing people to go out their homes to buy
a central such as I'm food and to pick up medication and you can also go
out for this fact size once today look so I went for a run this morning
so I've had my allowance how last time but of the one that can be used
to wait to the commission to you again cilices came to Dr where the will to
appoint a point of all under the stress so the hay introducing solacing with the jewel
assumption that one another character I got quite a nighting furmity I mean I do like
the body to keep things but it's actually a pretty decent you see and I'd say
that's one of the your back the moans of all the curtains on the one other
once again he's being the paint by a lot today
yes
muddy thing that I want lots of training and putting out is truly the thought and
of what leader and Emily nation medicine somatically the at that age I am a redisplays
contenta really slow it cutting out
and projects another it might take me the whole weekend also you something very contented they
came from one any other any other ways that you have from the unwind do I
got my crown help us to give up what you got
any transphysical to interested only in the round cylindrical super hope so when I put it
was it anything I know about again the just pass that the text
the extra clothes
so very use a low wall and but when we have to come ashore and were
all day watching and there is not waiting for water now half-a-million you which is Disney
mortices
and say watching at a friend the ocean would that have to confront you know yet
the hunting that turned up this week so I got the railing coverage for some of
the projects that things and he forgot you three the only the prize we are truly
does so this is expensive of
this is the great British sewing these the tangles title but and which hippie means that
the new series will be handing it mean that that might give this to distraction and
the soul present day by to consider this is what I really recorded it
yes this discuss the castle and follow the ranch I wonder if they're going to stagger
the you know to spread out the new content really so that
it bites I think this one day things where you know that some of the projects
might be in the production so you didn't know who would really have a proper look
at me and they might spoil the surprise and I'm saying that the three the three
different changes on them in the program so they'd probably looking out of everything in this
book anyway know you can be safer to get for the other the nice surprise of
the enemy stand up but it is critical and reason but somehow I didn't remember Aldrin
it was to been a long point back string to free yeah maybe a few the
feeling certain we gave for it to be work when you're happy with actually been sitting
and agree I make everything out that said that was like twenty seven project or to
go
every day
and there's white fancy dress all the back here in which
I didn't about any occasion to where you know this one a dress up in the
planet
careful times
they say for all yeah and hopefully next week I'll need something and I'll be unsure
thanks for watching I