I know today we're going to do a quick catch up to say what we've been
up to him may as always if you like this video and light Seymour please I
forget to like unsubscribe if you haven't already and a call this episode we try the
lockdown I need a haircut I think you're trying to
tempt me and to get in your hand
a little bit wary about it it's not that I'm too concerned it away because you
know your halver is really quite unit you wish this get a razor and I just
share it off with a saying that you do look quite one when you have it
cut pretty holding
on to avoid the earth about the selection you lost a journal I guess when you
have a shorter her style it obviously starts to get out of shape a bit quicker
which cut into my use
you could have a guest ensure that ladle you to stay besides not casting our hair
actually yuccas I think did I cut my friends every money yeah I got that really
sure it's actually grown out okay but that was pretty about two weeks where it was
invariably short and I just get trying to flatten it down with a head and the
finally what to a point where I can live with it again I haven't done much
garment making I don't know why I'm having a real block with sewing
during this look down the delicious yeah sure I found listing and cratering a lot easier
I think it's good like and just sit down and watch something and they've also been
quite simple projects so I've been listening the art netting through which I think I worked
out I got in possibly two thousand and six
so it's a very standing project and it's obviously taken me over ten years to complete
and I finally made it which is amazing so we watched a lot of marble film
for more like veena missing away at it I finally get all this was done and
then what you do is once you've saved them all up see you so then brooks
and line
and then so those books and I together once you finally got all of them sooner
you then double kosher around in one color and then do an outer color as well
and then that's it so this is the final
yeah hasn't been blocks which you probably tell that but I kind of figured it's probably
gonna go on a chair and get crushed anyway
so yeah it's been quite a from project I had to make up a couple of
the square there's a square down here it was one of that seventy-something squares and obviously
last the issue which told you how to make it it's got this sort of ilet
panel on it but
I just worked out how to do in the end I looked at the picture I
had like this tiny long inch he know Richard was an inch big this square showing
because I had the instructions on the order of how to sew up the bottom panel
but I didn't have the instructions for the smile but I did have a preview of
the square so I used that to work out how many stitches passed on and how
to
then make this particular square the answer it's finally done in Tibet and diplomatic actually finishing
up well just been going on for so long and then I think to be honest
because I was really ecstatic when I finished the toilets on our sofa which is all
the random array of colors it's all the same square it's a crocheted through
but I think it is felt a bit more individual
know where is this feels very I mean we see it still quite random all of
the square already different and it is nice but I guess
if I designed that it probably wouldn't have let like this when I think this is
also help give you going guarantee locked down so he was more TV in films for
making this and when he came to enter like cardinals didn't pay attention was inside yeah
I got to the end of their stead my and then it will say coincided with
had a couple of days of work right by the bank holiday and then it got
to Tuesday after the bank holiday I'd finished this the night before
there was a lot of work going on at work and I just completely lost the
plot
a very stressful day they picked up after that but I did so many projects
yes that's that so I'm really happy that's finally done and yet it's just a big
achievement I've never knitted hole through
that's creation
so what as we did that for as Bihari camera we're gonna promising him that we
mentioned in the last video yet we've ever done that just isn't any gang as though
it's an we just need to point up on the ceiling and get a new and
memory Collot which had a larger capacity I get some of the SD card and I
claimed to the SD card that was in it and put it across the time to
try to gigabytes great
downside to that was the camera the white let my camera to the pie was loose
and it managed to short-circuit the camera adl some of this in the back because the
senses been added Amadou and and get her basement and
probably just a faulty unit he probably shunner done that
woops isn't ready to get one to the Camry in the desert I have no to
be a week
ago feels quite disappointed with that after having such a success for that getting it working
when he had some issues with their cunning and then yeah we're back to waiting for
a new Campbell all the yes as we do another tech maintenance at home on a
day off from smiling an ID there's something I have finally created which has been on
my to-do list for absolutely ages and not sure which catch up I brought it up
in before my brought it up in a couple of gadgets it might be in life
everyone and in its in one from months again I don't remember when I took custody
of this
to say back-story even that really said it later times when I've mentioned it before going
yeah I'm going to recover it I got this path from my mom he got it
from a charity shop and she intended to recover it she hadn't go around to it
so she went Hey do you want to do and I went yeah sure and she
tucked in a couple of different fabrics with her and if I went back to call
more with this person and it sat one on the floor and our flat in various
places but absolutely agents in front of her yes so I finally got around to it
was it last week and Yep so it was kind of in tandem with you making
the camera
and had so I made it so it used to be the sort of like that
deep color in a whole new Hamrick the road around it yeah I had a with
bit of group stringing stuff but then it was to have some cord around it
and I'll do a full video on it but in short if I am picked him
essentially it's an old leather purse there when they'd stockholding over it and then recovered it
themselves not to future
yes he does I undid I was like wow I want to create a cover so
I never have to see the underneath of this ever again I mean was perfectly fine
it's just old and augustly quanti pickling that way but anyway long story she finally got
up recovered so
here's a bit from a pretty furnace
main problem with ease and calicoes than its showing up any doubt on our floor but
here it is
and it's got the slide panel of precious where's which go with the grocer's through did
the cattle that front goes without a low purr and we've got a much bigger on
which I also got from mom Atchley
so I just I just take him
to summon
yeah and but anyway so she had to I think it was an old iki across
them and we've got a larger but larger so of this cat on the other person
so we focused on the giant cat of the only one large account on this time
of
cotton fabric because it wasn't that big so we faced on getting it central on the
other path and this was a number of years ago I wanted to add another cat
for this one but it turns out we only has
we only had one full cats left on the panel of fabric which was this one
but I think the fabric cut off maybe I'll pale that so I can have used
it to cover the whole of the top it so I reversed the piquet a little
window here to show it but underneath this so I've got a family at the top
and a panel in at the bottom
and then I've got the crew shirt squares though I've crocin it ineffectively but underneath I
have created a whole cover in calico
as I say I never have to look at me in its of it ever again
so yeah so that was a big achievement and yet I'll explain a bit more about
the construction probably in the next video they I'm really happy that this is only done
and it makes me very happy so a bit different to the throne because I do
for like this is very this is a lot more personal and a bit but unique
start moving on to what I'm fixing on so I was doing a textiles course before
three pandemic and obviously that kind of got canceled so I haven't really based on an
awful up because I'm there's been an awful up the things to do what was when
quite tired but I'm doing a bit ico printing without the water and share a bit
of that soon the other project I was also doing a garment making false the mist
which will say your canceled technically that one would have finished by now but I again
I haven't got around to make in the garment I got there I got a bit
and flustered on a particular instruction and I wasn't sure how to continue the project because
I was lining the dress I think I have mentioned it before in a video but
I'm not sure of showing the person there just in case I haven't I got it
here
so it is the NCIC very one three new look and it looks like it came
with so magazine so I'll make the dress and I'm making it else of
this is what we see a bit I've got left over so it drapes really nicely
time but it does mean it's quite a tricky fabric to work with its quite slippery
so I finally got around to having a go up making it again and I managed
to snag one of the sleeves so I managed to
make an error on one of the sleeves I had to report it so this is
the original sleep which I had to replace and basically what happened is I didn't realize
that the tip of my sewing machine needle had snapped off a little when this happened
or whether it happened just then but what is done is because it was obviously stabbing
a blunt but a metal down into the fabric it caused all these drug lines through
the fabric and it just didn't look good I'd ever see it was already impairing wishes
and its you say
to you so I promptly changed the air so much she needed I finally worked out
where I was stuck it's just I guess there's an extra element trying to think about
how it works with the lining
but it brought me with her the entity anyway some persevering without having to share that
soon so let me be up to and the final day of that to recently is
I've been doing a little bit of weaving so as we mentioned had a hello moment
when I finished the throat and needed something else that I could do I am well
sitting on the sofa so I picked up because I've got lead to you know when
you get magazine and then you get the free gift and then you go here that
free gifts great I'll do that at some point and then you never get around to
it so I've got three Ziploc bags full of thanks sort of projects so I thought
I'd have a look in one of those and pick our project because I'm I think
I mentioned in my make line so the unknitting three is one of I make nine
and the shawl I made my mom was the second young based project so of actually
done both your own based
hand waste products
so they're all done and I didn't actually really have an agenda and what the next
one is there are lots things I want to make but there was nothing I was
starting yeah so which one is this from so this is from issue fifty eight which
is probably years ago because I only got Molly makes for a brief well
I never quite a while ago it's a little weaving loom
and you kind of makeup she go along so it it gives you a starting point
she quit the tassels that was some and told you have to make the first section
of gray but then it kind of days just to know make it up now one
say that's what I've been doing so I've added another testily section
for he carried on for a little bit then add a couple of other colors and
then essentially go to the top you put it on a little wooden doubt apparently it
came with one in the kick but it's not in that so obviously I got this
she skips so I got really complain and it was a every guest anyway and yeah
and then you can hang it someone much so much I found this really therapeutic it's
quite nice to do something where I haven't got a big plan and it's not it's
not for anyone it's just yeah exactly so it's been really enjoyable to have that and
again it's something that I can just do as we watch something on TV say this
one has been a nice the break between more intense projects and so what are your
plans for June
survive some items Britain you in which
well I guess what Ilan's for June it is to get the cameras that was the
among your premises will be above all the energy right say my plans for Jean Oh
yes all your friends for June Sri my plans are to get that rest on your
sootily in the next couple of days it is it's been doing me on a bed
so I want to finish my yellow dress I've probably finished the weaving loom thing because
I can imagine I've got quite a bit so far and it's only been the last
few days so I can imagine that that will probably get completed alike as they didn't
have a set target with that I'm probably going to decide on my next young based
project possibly like a bully Philip box and left a be on from my black cardigan
closer
and also because it's the summer it's easier to neck with black young man is the
light levels develop Oh yeah the selling weekender
so that's in a couple of weeks which I might do and so yeah if you
haven't seen that the fold line have advertised it so this is the demon on my
best one so as many people can sign up as they want to
say and all the proxy's go to charity
event Bradamante
just not see you that it sounds like what could I dig cineole we can't focus
the you basically set up your computer set up your sewing machine and then you attend
sessions online and get on with the project which is essentially what they do at the
in-person events that because it's looking unlikely that is going to go ahead they've decided to
push it forward and make it remote the that might be on the cards a couple
weeks
and see you are probably choose another garment to make
but agrees to make
nice
day that's it for this week so hopefully next week I will have edited or the
footage for the path to explain how I make that is Carl nodded Yep a lot
of little that's it this time Frank fortune