when you've mended this one
rattily fine
to me hi this is Phillips arbitrations have a very close in to discussing bending close
in fact she's got a focus on how to repair
one of her dresses okay so thank you to fill their his introduction and so yes
I am fixing this dress it's been in my repair file for a while part of
my twenty twenty goals sewing wise is to actually repair ice and the clothings and accessories
which need fixing and this is one of them so this is a sort of tunic
dress something I shot but many years ago and it's made in a net fabric but
the problem I have is that the hems come away at the bottom it looks like
they used a blind hemstitch so instead of trying to do a zigzag stitch or twin
needle or I do have a cover stitch Mr scene which would probably be the most
professional looking finish but there was never any stitching really visible in the outside when
the original stitching walls present there's a tiny bit of it left which is how I've
worked out how they did it and here you can't see the stitching on the outside
so what I'm going to do is actually learn how to use the blind hemstitch on
my regular sewing machine and I thought I'd share that in today's video now it's worth
bearing in mind that I am using black threads and this garment is predominantly black though
it may not show that well so perhaps I'll add in some clips of how to
use the blind hamfat with a contrast fabric just to show how the stitch works because
theoretically you shouldn't be able to say all this because I'm mending it as always if
you like this video please don't forget to like and subscribe if you haven't already I
have my machine Peri threaded his so I've got black thread in the bobbin I've got
black thread in the school at the top and I've put what I believe to be
the blind hamfat on so it's got a little gauge at the side which you can
move with this style and on the right hand side so I've moved it to where
I think it should work okay see the advantage with this short but item is that
it's got a very distinctly pressed him already so that hasn't disappeared
so I don't need to go to my iron and press that
in order to
create this line ten what I'm going to do
is with the inside of the dress showing so I can see all the scenes on
the inside I'm then going to
flip the press him
over
so that I'm
I've now got a fold
but I'm going to leave enough
of that
actual edge showing
on the side so the overlocked edge is still there then I've got a bit of
fabric and then I've got the folded edge
next to it so I'm pretty gonna start a bit over from
that seem that because I might find that a bit too tricky to get over
and I'm gonna leave a little gap just because I'm worried that if I
don't leave enough
of an edge hear the stitch you might go off the side and I want it
to still pick up on the machine so for my machine I've got the soup teens
thirty for on this machine it is
a its number nine that essentially you're creating a line or stitching which will be on
this single layer of fabric here
but then the odd stitch will just catch on to the folded bit of fabric to
secure it and then you do a couple more stitches on this bit then it will
catch again
which will theoretically give it a blind him but you do need to make sure that
only just catches on the fold of the fabric so that's where I might need to
test it and it may be a bit of trial and error I put quite wide
stitch length on her so I've put is nearly three or my machine just because it
is a fairly thick net fabric but I'm going to see how it goes it might
be that this is a to wider stitch I can't adjust the width on my machine
for this so
hope that it should be fine
and care about a quick go I think it might be a bit too
far over so I'm going to roll so that this gauge meeds a bit over so
so they should push this fabric so it's not as far over
which should mean that
the stitch isn't so far in and should not be as visible on the other side
so I've gone all the way around now I'm really happy with that him results
it's funny because I've never really thought about using a blind him on a net fabric
but having had a look up it looks like it is a good alternative if you
don't want a visible him and especially with this sort of fabric it you know even
this light stitch doesn't show through but even when I haven't done it
even when I've done it so that it's a bit more visible because I'm still learning
how to do the stitch on this it's very forgiving because it's such a busy pattern
and but that's great so that should secure it now I should be able to wear
it again and because that was all that was stopping me wearing this so I'm going
to give it a quick press just to press it back down properly but
it looks like it's nice and secure again just in case you couldn't see what I
was doing I've got a bit of the scrap of the red Terry cloth that's going
absolutely everyone so so this was the him so if I pressed up that amount so
I've got my folded up him here but I want it as a blind him I
did then press that bit
underneath but have a bit of a bit of that raw edge showing
will then line this folded section
where that gauge is if you've got this otherwise I guess you just put it fairly
in the middle
and then yeah if you've got it on the blind hemstitch it should then
so you can see it's visible on the inside
it's a bit hard to tell on the start loss to be honest and you can
see it where I've stitched it with it folded over but on the outside it's not
really was bored or you can see the odd catch and that is because I have
used a black thread on purpose to show so depending how much that little I'm sigs
like stitch juts out into your fabric will determine how long the blind him shows how
long that stitch shows on the outside okay so that's my dress or repaired so as
you can see the hem those look pretty much invisible you can kind of see us
like indent where and the stitches have been added but it's probably where they were once
where
I've stitched a bit too far over into that fold and I think with time and
practice I could make much better job of this but because this fabric is so busy
I'm not going to undo it on this occasion but perhaps next time there him goes
I will be a lot better at it so you have just given a better pressed
so I've never used the blind ten-foot or used the blind him function at all on
my machine and I'm pleased to say it wasn't as difficult as I thought it would
be so I would recommend it and it looks like it does work quite well with
nets as well which I wasn't aware of that looking online it does look like it
is a good option if you
do want to use it for that so that's it for this week thanks for watching