hello today I'm doing some simple back mending as the ways if you like this video
and want to see more please don't forget to life and subscribe if you haven't already
so today I've got a couple of different repairs so the first one is this demon
bag and that I made a while ago as you can see I've made it from
an old pair of jeans just literally cut a bit below
the top section ditch it together and yet just essentially
him the bottom and I've used an old about that was broken just cut off a
bit and added that just to gather around a bit and with some of the length
of the rest of the genes made a handle I can use this back the agents
just because it has been damaged on an early to repair it it's not actually that
bad I've only got this very small section to repair to know maybe two three inches
and it's just where the hand-stitching has come away now one of the reasons it might
keep breaking is because I'm using a vertical hemstitch I just looked at for the book
I didn't know that this particular Heming method was called fascicle hostage but they come it
might be there a different stitch would reinforce it a lot better however I'm going to
stick the versicle hemstitch for now just because I like the finish you can't really see
the stitches or they're not that obvious on the inside and I can't really stitch all
the way through unless I want it to show although saying that the felt those hide
up and I could potentially get the stitching close to the top stitching on the outside
so actually saying that maybe in future I might repair it a different way but for
this time I'm just going to do a simple versicle hemstitch the other one that I
need to repair is a shot ball back it's these sea salt bags so I've got
to you here but I can't actually see the problem with one of them I wasn't
sure what the problem is would this one but then I saw that I'd put some
closing clips to secure one of the handles here so I sent you were going to
do on this one is machine stitch it back in place but I might also do
a bit of overlocking because as you might notice if you've got one of these facts
yourselves and it just praise so much because the back doesn't come overlocked
none of the seems a hand that they are turned over at the top but yes
this sort of starts happening with these bags and I really get back there really useful
their very substantial and it's a really thick waited fabric but it's completely fall apart quite
quickly because I think the stitches are quite wide and there's no overlooking in it so
I'm going to begin with hand-stitching the bag that made I might trying to secure off
the end that has fallen away so I sent that's just about enough
of a niche here
I'm just gonna
go in and trying
not to if I can
just try and do the second time to reinforce it
the original one should not take in
just about
red threaten from recent projects
let's begin with I'm just going to
cut a shortish length no longer than why I'm merely saying that I were quite alone
said
priedieu shorter just I'm
not in one and
so just attached it so
with vertical Hansard you
starting from the fabric and you catch the top section and because this is really their
promise I don't need to catch it to say but if you were having a garment
and you don't want to to show the
front side you are to just catch a bit of it so they won't show then
I'm going along
I'm going along the bits and go about down to the lining drawing it through then
going back up
to the denim side and repeating so just
then the and get this was a short little vertical stitch which I guess it's called
vertical hand stitch and so it's just that tiny bit that's on display
and the stitch
the diagonal stitch down is hidden
see it's just one of those
tasks that I just haven't got round to and it is so simple really pretty gonna
take me what ten minutes so as which she should realize how little it was to
fix it
for you just checked the rest of the bag in the second I'm just in case
I have missed something else in case it was the reason you see I have got
away too much to enter to that section
I'm pretty much done so what I'm gonna do is just sleep it
all bad I've wasted that that perhaps I can use it something and just check around
the rest
but it turned out that that was a really quick sex so that's my first drop
them ready to be used again okay so for fixing my sea-salt take backs I've just
gone over to the sewing machine and the firstly I'm going to do is I'm going
to remove any topstitching that's really close to the strap that I'm going to fix most
of it has come away already and that's why it's not attached at the moment but
there's the odd bit that might be slightly in my way for vexing and I'm just
going to remove
its only really a couple of stitches either and
and what I'll do is all replace those later on so it's very simple I'm going
to do here I'm just going to
used a couple of quoting pegs to pay get into place which I think they've been
over
maybe I thought a convenient crease line already and where it's been folded before so I'm
just lining that up with the group which marks the center and all my machine remain
to keep them for input my sentence between to run through on my machine because it's
quite a good material but I do want the stitches quite place together so that at
last a bit longer them just being simple straight stitch from going to backtack at the
front and end and I'm just going to go right over I replace the stitches that
I'm missing
so that's the handle back on
check the other handles
seem to be on okay I'm going to reading the topstitching next so I'm going to
do it from the outside but I might just go around the whole bag I'll put
it up to three
they could be going round and doing the topstitching gun might extend the life of the
other
parts of the handle where it touches to the back
make it last bit longer so what are probably do next is get my overlocker out
and just overlook any ends I can I'm not going to undo any seems on that
just to access the raw edges easier so as you can see because of the top
stitching that isn't as much
of an overlap here but I could probably still get the overlook around it to be
honest to still enough of an end and then I will go to get right up
into the corners with the overlocker but what I will be able to do it's just
overlook them enough so that it's not fraying quite as much and I'll probably do that
to the other Cecil bag of got here which I can't see
where it's broken about from that I think it is literally this one's just spraying a
lot more so that be the final thing I'll do and then my bag repairs for
now L complete so for the overlooking the end I'm going to use my overlocker I've
just changed machine but obviously could use an overlooking stitch on your sewing machine that would
work just as well so I've just turned the bag inside out and I'm just going
to
be around all the raw edges really that I can access for as far as I
can access and that will just help it last longer you can see in this part
the stitching is really close to the rule air chair and that's just because so much
of the fabric hands freight so it'll be good to secure this end it might just
make it
so found this top section the bit at the top is essentially almost like are facing
on the inside of the bag
at the top where the handles are as their sandwiched in between I found that this
is a bit too
tight the road him that I can see her so what I'm just gonna do is
just trimming the really frayed edges but because there is that topstitched slides
that should prevent it from completely disintegrating however obviously what you could do is you could
unpick on the top stitching
then overlock the ends
that would be the best thing to do but see I don't really want to undo
it too much
I want to get it back in you as soon as possible but I think
that will be enough overlocking on it anyway to
get a lot of use out of that
then perhaps when I do with a bit more time I can always come back to
it and
work on that section
pretty happy with that
is another end
will be inside seems at the bag and now eval ox because the self don't do
that
one of them done I'm just going to
put the other one down here are just going to
overlook the ends and this one as well
there we go the second season sorted out it's certainly worth overlooking those raw edges if
you do have a bag like this where they haven't finished the marquis just means that
those seems will hopefully be a bit more reenforced today you have it a couple of
simple fragmenting options thanks for watching