now today is a quick video I thought I'd show you my rejig of the craft
room so at work I got this desk chair which is brilliant so I did one
of those to the display screen equipment assessment I'm as I hadn't done one instance I'm
working remote leader I am during this current pandemic and yeah the response was my place
of work anyway Oh in either nuchae will send you on which was brilliant and the
main problem with that obviously was that this room isn't huge and I do share it
with my partner fell and saying he's got desk over there but I won't shoot her
because it's a complete mess and snakes cleaning up but the rest of the rumors but
on the microbe an area but gusli it's all so now and my work and space
as well and it does it be work full time I'm using during the week days
for don't leave for work so yeah I just thought I'd share this space with you
today so at the moment by me I've got my sewing machine space sat up for
doing my hundred-day projects so today I've got a llama to stitch so I'll be setting
us up shortly yet so I've got to studio like to so I recently got these
led lights which or ever seeing a lot more compact and the big and that furtively
much cheaper and studio lights that kind of a the like a big which you can
like a big umbrella slow and and they've got the much larger bones in the side
and so this setup works a lot better in this space
so I've moved my dress form tucked away in the corner and and this just works
a lot better because we tend to Pompeian to the transform a lot of always intended
I used to store it right by the doorway which oversee was a brilliant so it's
a lot saying for that this table that I've got my sewing machine on is a
traditional so machine table and normally I have it so that it's um it's got a
flat so awesome two-thirds of it goes that way and then there's a little ledge on
the other side if you open it out fully and longly I have apparently out to
full capacity but I realized for the persistence of a hundred-day projects I don't actually need
it completely out and it did make that I could put the draft form next to
it and I mean even saying that I can move it slightly out and put it
expanded fully if I wanted to use it and with this layout but obviously I don't
need to most the time so I've compacted that there for now so the glass table
has been moved over to the corner of the rooms originally I had my computer workstation
in the corner of the room however I bit the glass table there now this is
because I needed enough space for this desk chair to be able to actually sit in
front of the computer vexation and it couldn't
slop down the side between the glass table and when the workstation was and because it
was right next to the wall stay underneath the last table of but what's called the
sonnet table and he was from a cafe and somewhere else sweets to live that we
bought the number of years ago now probably about eight years ago and it's just an
old ikea table it's too combined together but the bottom one had the legs hacked off
and I'm we were going to get rid of it but it is the only thing
I have available that the cover stitch machine will find out and because the come a
stitch machine is massive and there's no house to put out the moment so
we've kept the solid table for now I'm I do love the solid table but it
just doesn't fit in our living area which is the same but it is just too
big for us
I've got one of those homograft trollies and that's really useful to hold all of the
different threats I've got some other nations and haberdashery it's also got the odd bit of
fabric on there as well finally I've got my new computer don't man so and this
tower is what they've been working on over the last day or so so he decided
that I needed an upgrade because I think my laptop was getting all of it in
years and he felt that it wasn't after the challenge of editing of these videos so
he's created a speck which apparently will make this a lot easier to do
and then yes so next to the tower is my computer workstation and so it's quite
small I'm to be honest I didn't purchase it with the idea I'd be working
home of my hours from home so it was just more about and I'm just gonna
use of the odd creative project and then I'm not actually going to even switch on
my Qaboos and most things but I'm obviously now the situation is quite different and even
moving forwards I think there's gonna be a lot more homeworking then they would have been
in my dog so that's why spoke that's pretty much ever this week so not an
awful lot of sounds being going on since I finished my dress last weekend I do
have some fabric dying I'm hoping to do I'm probably tomorrow now because it's quite late
in the day and I still need to do my hundred-day projects and oversee edit this
and the hundred-day project video another reason I haven't got on with an awful aircraft recently
is because I have had a bit of a flare up with my chronic bonus so
I found it very challenging to be able to do an awful lot during locked down
I found a quite hard to servant general I'm even though enjoy wifing from home and
to be honest I'm not the most outgoing person anyway so I quite enjoy doing activities
around the house and staying in any way I'm but I probably had more of a
preference towards yon based projects that have been doing local of war listing and and a
mansion finished placed my I'm make time projects for the sheer which are young best which
I don't know leading that even listening I found really challenging to compare at the moment
I've just been frotting an awful lot
yeah so I think I'm still recovering that from that so having however I'm really pleased
but I managed to get the restoration to reject this room I think there's a lot
more floor space which is probably by an obvious one for us anyway or the layouts
a bit more practical crusta both working all they say that the computers right in the
door so
it doesn't leave much of an entrance into the room
it's going to mean that my videos will have a slightly different approach because I used
to piss and this camera one side of the last table and then I'd sit behind
it obviously with this layer I want you have to do that I might just do
a few more videos where if I'm showing it to to real or time last to
something I'm doing I might just do it over head shots instead say I think that's
it for this time I'm not sure what I'm going to be reporting next week color
of got the motivation to complete something I really need to do some hand dying actually
say that might reach up and although might be a tutorial I'm not completely sure thanks
for watching