hello its Clary from copper creations I just thought I'd show with you some of the
ice and I purchase today I had a few gift vouchers to use locally at across
the store and so I brought a few things but I wouldn't normally
so the first thing and I decided by and was this wolf I've got lots of
young and which is why I've chosen the stash bust it by making a giant through
which you might have seen if you follow me on Instagram and this through need three
hundred seventy well I'm about
around two hundred twenty square complete and then of receivers all the I'm showing all crocheting
it up together to do at the end and with this I noticed that unless I've
got the more yellow yarner I'd
not have much yellow in it and as it's my favorite color I decided that we
best to
avoid that scenario and get a little bit more yarn just to even out the colors
at the end so with this through it is going to be a whole random range
I am going to use up lots of the oddments I've got in my own collection
but hopefully it will still look nice as well
be that the first three purchases
another iseum I decided to get I were these pencil brushes so and they are designed
for and when you have paints through a sense of however I'll probably use it more
for any text our work I do so I quite like and having a go at
some textile pieces I'm using fabric paint
you know different items to print on to fabric as well as the block printing and
so
that you probably just use these and to to dab paint on without a stencil as
well so yeah so I'd give those ago
another eyes are my goal was this some small bag of
plastic darning needle so in here there's five darning needles I just thought this would be
quite useful because
only can never have too many
they're quite good but if you're traveling because you know they're definitely I mean Nishant you
shouldn't have a problem bringing a muscle blunt darning needle on a plane anyway but at
least I'm
you know you definitely won't have a problem with these and see you there just and
basically they'll help me
we've been all the least end of my croche where's and any other cratering or I'm
going project that's are coming up so that that
the second last item I'm going to show no the third to laugh is this I'm
home for maker there I've already got if you Pompeian makers I've got
these clover ones and where
they essentially they come out and the to have you want wrap the wall around them
and then you put them back into the circle
anywhere I'm sure and some of you've seen these before and so this is just a
different design I thought I'd see whether I'm it was a bit easier to use perhaps
or you know
if it was any different at all so you can make a five cents meter dire
Mr one and three cents meter one
it looks similar concepts to and have seen online where people use a fork make compounds
and so is essentially the same concept but I'm branded as a Pombal maker
okay so next I've got these
textile paints I've never seen this particular
brand before it's just called textile color
so I've got three just to see what they're like so I've got a neon-yellow and
the own green and an orange I've already got some other fabric pinks in my collection
and little
trying to think what's the branded they might be dialogue
but yeah I just thought I'd see what these are like I'm
as with other fabric paints you fix them by acetum
on the fabric with an iron and then they say that their washable I'm up to
forty degrees
portative resources
my final purchase that I'm going to show is these texel painter pens so
the thing I liked about these is that
they're quite narrow there one to millimeter and lines that they draw
you get a range colors we've got black greens blue
red and yellow
just to be interesting to see what they're like whether it's a bit easier to create
the fine blind and
and like the fabric paints again you wait for it to drive this Davis and take
about an hour and then you iron-on at the three minutes without using team and then
it should be fixed on to your fabric and then again you can wash apparently the
fabric a pretty degrees
okay that's all of my purchases from today so just a small little collection of random
textile lightens they hopefully I'll be able to use them scenes
and you know trial them out to see whether they're worth well and that there now
that's it