today I'm going to do a review of my sewing machine as a way that you
like this video and flight see more please I forget to like unsubscribe if you haven't
already the main sewing wishing and I use is the Toyota supervenes thirsty for which is
hip on my serving table they tell you to do three different super jeans models or
other their two main models and then there's a different
option for one of the models as the soup teams fifteen which is a slightly more
basic model than this one you can I think it's a J seventeen essentially it's the
Sufyan fifteen model but the extension table from a standard and this model the safety in
spectacle is the one that has a few more features its other common an extension table
but obviously you can buy it separately which I have done so the thirty-four refers to
how many different stitches that does and which you can see on the side over here
so the Sifton fifteen has less stitches that how to steen variations a few other differences
with it is that you can change the press'd pit pressure so there's a dying off
at the top there another thing that during me to this model rather than the other
one is that you can change the stitch length so I go be useful to do
a phone machine review of this particular machine because I'm Toyota isn't as renowned as other
makes such as generally hosannah
half dukey honor and there are all sorts and I guess like the Leo generally are
ones that makes commonly
I'm sort of in the sewing community in the UK anyway it's quite easy to get
a toy use a sewing machine as a regular
department store for example you could get this machine or you could get the suitings fifteen
version anyway that someone like our loss or hobby craft one key advantage of this machine
would be that it's pretty recently priced for what it does it's also by the name
super jeans it is a heavy duty machine which means that it can get through some
very sick materials they claim before the sleeper dooms machines is that it can get through
I think it's up to twelve layers of denim I'm not sure I've actually tried this
possibly my clear plentiful
may have had several ways
but I'm not even sure then I got quite to that caliber restes old anyway it
has managed to do everything I've asked that to do and I have done a range
of projects from doing simple free machine embroidery to doing much more up host rebased projects
or like the clear using different thick layers of denim but also have used final fabrics
and it does cope with us as well so it's hard to compare with I'm some
of the bigger brandings and then some machine worlds I have east mother and bottles probably
been leading me actually so my man's of machine which my mom currently has is a
generally new home and it is lovely to work with that is when it's working so
you do have to maintain it quite a lot you have to make to you oil
it rapidly and clean as ontically but saying that when you have maintained it beautifully it
stitches lovely it's pretty quiet to be honest and we have just stitches lovely I've been
to like about education courses locally and they have generally machines as well which mechanical ones
like this machine and again they're pretty substantial it's a bit hard to say with the
ones that you use that because obviously lots of people
use the machines so I think they do that about more worn out than your machine
at home went away the only one prudently using it I will certainly do just get
familiar with your ring machine because you use that one the most out of any sewing
machine it does mean that you do get a preference towards it so although I have
no problem with the machines or use that class I do prefer using my own so
machine just because I'm very used to it so another key feature for this machine is
that it comes with a glide effort which
this line of it is part of the selling point for the sections model and I
presume how it's supposed to get through upswell layers of denim but to be honest I
hadn't really used that
much at all I think I've had it on the old time but I had to
find it's really hard to use because it's a solid metal fit you can't really see
where you're going with it and it's a bit bigger than a regular fit
I go like this anyway so I find it really clunky to use so haven't actually
used it but other mentions just use in the regular for all using a walking fit
I find it perfectly find to use but the projects I've done so far so moving
on to why I like this model so firstly it gets through an awful lot as
I mentioned I've made different up post realisms I made some unburies with this machine I
need much thicker garment such as that to know benefit upcycled from to pass of denim
jeans I've done an awful of free machine embroidery and that is something I do like
that you can drop the dog teeth on it so that's a very useful feature if
you do some free machine embroidery because although you can get the models and my other
sewing machine which is so rettore you've set but it's a bit more basic you put
on in place over the top but it does mean that you been elevated your work
and I find that sometimes that doesn't work very well I mentioned that Toyota is more
of a budget machine series so it does mean that if you do need to be
additional feet there normally cheaper than other brandings obviously it it can vary but I find
that you can get the machine feet for this model and a pretty good price it's
just a little extra pulse I like but I do really like that it's got a
giant backstitch sleeper and it's very easy to use it has a good range of stitches
and boast stretch and for wave and fabric or just decorative there is an inbuilt threader
the head which I don't use an awful lot but it does come in use if
you're really struggling to threat the machine the machine itself oiling so you don't need to
worry about making do you oil at every so often I would take quite like that
it is a manual mechanical machine rather than a computer rights one I don't know why
I just don't like I've got a little more control labor it it also means that
it doesn't reset when you switch out on enough I know some computer models probably do
remember what last stitch you were using but obviously on this unless you change it it
stays to the last nothing you had that can be a downside as well because if
you say for example I was doing my hundred day project so I was doing three
machine broidery and then I decided to say something else I'm did a regular sewing project
I accidentally left this stitch length on zero or very close to zero and couldn't understand
why the fabric was of beating through the machine even though it put the dog to
that was overly could look at the stitch length that such a short like that it
just was a really so the drawbacks for this machine personally for me is that you
can't change the stitch with so it's great that you can change the lengths which you
do with this great I go here which is not available Suakin fifteen it's a feature
that some of thirty for however you can't change the switch with which you can on
other machines and other drawbacks for this machine which is quite a big one really is
that it's really loud so perhaps I'll add a clip on how loud is because a
lot of the videos I do I ever cut out the sound of the machine or
it it's time-lapsed anyway so I've got rid of the sound anyway but it is immensely
loud and a lot of the time I do with noise-canceling headphones with it if I
won't do listen something else while I'm working this isn't always the drawback by guess if
you live and share the commination that might be a problem so if you just don't
like the noise so it probably has trying but we buy if you are concerned about
the noise level it it's quite loud another issue is that because it's light weight or
fairly lightweight for a sewing machine it does mean that it can start dancing if you're
during a heavy duty midst of so so sometimes I feel like I'm almost dancing with
the machine I think you do get used to it so as I said before you
get used to using your machine but it testily that it does feel like you're moving
with the machine at that point it's something that I think my lands old generally wouldn't
do because it is really heavy and it's quite her to move around but once it's
sat down where you want to it doesn't really move it's a bit more reassuring in
that sense because it doesn't feel like you're going to be wrong because it's dancing on
the table so yeah it's quite bouncy it's so does the heavy duty work but I
think that's the main drawback of it being so that the heavy duty machine when it's
such a lightweight one as well because it kind of needs a bit of weight to
stop it dancing around the next row back it's kind of just a personal note and
it's probably when you can result by just buying any both but it don't have an
old light bulb in it so it's kind of got a sort of yellow orange glow
whereas probably people know a model you to get an led light visit in the I
will say how to run before the first spoke I had in here he kept them
unscrewing I think because I was doing some heavy duty work it just kept it kept
listening when the ball was and it will mayst came out a couple of times I
felt like I have replaced it now and actually this once said I'm fine so maybe
the first hope was out of heaven issue so again you can only get a replacement
mbd both but as far as I'm aware because I've got this machine about five years
ago so I'm not sure if newer versions of it comes with an eddy bulb that
this one obviously did and similarly another drawback might be I'm not too fast with this
but it might be in a sheaf of someone else is that the fact it is
black it might be a bit problematic with lysing issues because I guess the kind of
absorbs the light rather than helping light bounce on to your work but I'm not really
sure how much of an issue that would be if someone is ever really been an
issue for me I already mentioned the glider fence which can be a bit of an
issue because it's so big that I haven't really used that and finally I wanted to
point out that it is a forset button-holes so if you do prepare one set button-hole
that would be something to consider before purchasing this machine so my verdict is that I
would recommend this machine particularly if you're on a tight budget and you need something that
is step up from the entry level sewing machines because it does have those extra features
that does mean you can get it through a much wider range of projects then you
can from a basic sewing machine it is a substantial machine and it hasn't let me
down currently it is a good model and it does have all these great features but
obviously daily to be aware of those potential drawbacks if they could affect you that's it
for this time thanks for watching