now today's video is going to be slightly different Phyllis going to be leading on the
video as he's going to be talking about a recent project he's just completed
this is related to use your stuff and one of the challenges you've had is so
film in what the down
at the moment we have a tripod soft hasn't the banished and we do so
it's fairly good on what it does it's quite hard to get to it and the
reason I use the window so it's because this is actually a really tiny romance that
smallest Romanov that and I used to have only other side of the table when sometimes
I still do but it does mean that it's a bit harder to get in and
out of the room it is the doors for that no the camera their camera here
a few steps around him like some things yes you quite limited space to work or
exactly and also with I'm working from home it's been a bit more challenging to set
up for doing certain videos particularly ones where I'm trying to show you what I'm doing
and such as tutorials and
I just don't be easier if we had something that was a bit more out of
the way and slightly more prevalent as well because obviously I can't always I do actually
end up leaving the triple that law that obviously it's really hard to clean the windowsill
is hard to open a close the window it's hard to open place the blind and
say yeah there's all sorts of issues with her
so that's the solution
we will consider unpaying something want to receive it and one of things I do have
line around its marble or ask me pass so I'm really it as we pay it
is a computer
normally mmf besides that a credit card this is a high zero so it seems small
turn and what I've done is attached a camera module to it and a small case
of again to fit it to the scene and so it was nice walk down to
you on the table
I haven't actually worked out how we're going to fix it to the ceiling the next
say I mean it's one thing to mention is that it is really light so it's
not going to be a huge issue working out how to attach it but it still
will be something to think about to cheat project as well as replies sell for things
that he could for prices
but again I got that sit around for about a year
not really don't much
project
really know it has discomfits quite it's quite low-powered and my grassy pie three was just
a family but library high holger's never quite unblock in
until you suffer round with high three for quite a lot
but this is very specific use case in it this is perfect for really deep but
I'm not raining if that makes
me think it easefully and this is accessible by a web browser
on any you're connected to our own little network
which means advantage to this is curry just needs to go on to any computer even
a think and it hit to start the course gismos options use take pictures you can
record video you do time lapse
the software we use in actually can be used for a ratty thing so too can
stuff like commission sensors so any records from the text mission which is the news for
us but so are very scared to come for example perfect
play ideally this will replace our parent tribals
approach this will just civil singing either by folks I'm not so we could probably have
it speed work or how far down that needs to be is
so we haven't actually tried what it looks like a play out its kind of being
sitting in our lounge while he's been testing it and but yes we want it up
there but we do have a light fitting up there as well someone to make sure
that that's not in short obviously I could assume in when I edit the footage but
I'd have to remember doing that every time and also it will reduce the quality because
the more easy him in the more picks laces and blood the quality is well they
say that along this I will just speed up or these the time lapse function because
it we really useful to those bits when I am just I'm cutting something out because
ever see it's quite boring to watch someone cut or hand say something in real time
it's the law it's a lot I'm more effective to speed up the footage which is
obviously what I've done in many videos before now so he was just makes it easier
the advantage of using this is that it gets saved direct on to the server the
difference so if I use my camcorder or my de SLR I have to save the
footage and also with my DSL a it can only say it can only am record
up to thirty minutes it's only twenty thirty minutes at a time so then you have
to stop and start it again whereas obviously if I'm koshering something I could be sitting
down for a long time so it would be quite gets have something that will just
enjoy being switched on and reporting that potentially hours well yes so really invitation we had
with this is tequilas the video files it saves to empty for but does this locally
which essentially means it needs some memory on here I'm it save simply fall straight to
the server so they can be to the of this really quickly afterwards and I've begun
by for web browsers well
but does mean that one thing to write it up is I'm gonna have to clone
the SD card this was the memory on the swings of his nasty glance
I am Guinness converse and this is a sixteen gigabyte SD card not just off and
rich went shaking out the ovens and twenty eight gigabytes will be fine is only a
lot of a lot of devices called take much more than that that someone that's kind
of the limit at the moment and oversee that's quite a good budget capacity as well
as though you know done the cost too much at that storage level I run the
numbers of to nati piece of switch your looking about to answer for recording time yeah
we don't believe I probably wouldn't be there listing for more than twelve hours straight sometimes
I do leave them they can call it what it up on that try but I
do leave out running because it is quite hard to get to the stop-start button and
so I will just leave it running sometimes obviously twelve hours of crafting in the day
is by a lot I mean I probably do that some days but to yeah yeah
tonight's being quite following were just like with he stopped to do this video but I'm
ready to carry on since the other will be I'm a video of me re-covering the
puffy but there's an awful lot footage because I managed to fill up one and memory
cuts completely and I'm not really sure why I guess my disallows higher quality for that
is high quality yeah
so it's very gonna save me a while to edit it over repeat this week or
next week maybe the week after maybe in a couple weeks and so yes so that
won't feature this particular camera which is a shame but I'm really excited that we have
rollable rolling with this is when but she talked about it for a while and I
think when I first voiced the frustration with the current setup and what I'd ideally like
I don't think you were a place with your playing around with Ross replies that you
would about confident to do different time is done to me I mean that took me
warm three for us to trouble cheeks as it wasn't saving broke me and it was
a and say she's a she meant roughly a good day and you know building it
setting up just and testing it and I'm saying a daily see like maybe twice you
know social
you started yesterday and you have finished today
and
yes they I'm not actually sure when we will start using it properly in its final
destination Billy soon we will get that set up but it was been a bit different
Ficino's into the genus yeah so um yeah received you know someone he's into
but what what would you call this hobby
tech okay if you know someone whose into tech and can do this sort of thing
honestly it's very useful and but you can say uses you said the security cameras yes
I'm and also is it like if you wanted to be a wildlife camera you can
be things all the what did you can put it so that and it's a tax
emotions are only records when the sensor yeah notes to something meeting there's a Thomas sentence
on this will software we use which was just Nagant use from this case
you can set times on sometimes they saw not work you can set it to second-nature
the record
as nice time and date so
tragically on this default
of course moved the Trussell the first record is
right so that's it for this week oversee will be back with another video next week
possibly a catch up not shall have to see what about she's done in the last
month well done you you like us is ripe for more rapid high content
so I was about yes I'm happy if you gonna create more technology that can make
my life easier than to the document my make small that's brilliant