hello today I'm going to talk about my overlocker other ways if you like the studio
and Clyde timore please don't forget to like unsubscribe if you haven't already so my overlocker
is the singer fourteen as H seven five for this is a budget overlocker machines so
I think I spent about two hundred pounds on it that was the sale price and
but I think it was fairly frequently on the same I'm not sure if it's quite
the same as the one that frequently appears in little I bought this a bars possibly
seven or eight years ago so it's I've had it quite a while now and I
thought I felt like I've had enough experience with that now to share my opinion of
it and the first thing I guess when discussing overlook is a key question of someone
without one would be do you need an overlocker I would say that since having the
overlocker I have already looked back it is a complete game changer to your sewing if
your dress-making it makes it so much work or because you can just finish off those
things superquick and oversee if you're serving with nets it's even faster you can definitely make
a nice pop in a very short space of time however saying that it is quite
the financial cost still even if you're buying a budget machine like this it's still too
into found out of your pocket it's a whole other machine to hole somewhere in your
home the main role of the block is to finish off scenes and you can obviously
do that with your regular social machine you can do is it a stitch you can
do an overgod stitch you can sometimes get and special feet for your sewing machine and
this job as a job as well and it just it normally takes a bit more
time but I oracy depends how good your time vagina's as well there are quite a
few models of overlookers out in the market so as I mentioned to render fans probably
the the lower end of how much you spend on an overlocker I think you can
get the single model that the little for possibly violet cheaper the land saying that but
also they can go right up to quite a hefty amounts more around a thousand pounds
or more and a lot of these machines do have a special features so for example
they can do things like and little answer is technology so it's a lot easier to
throw the machine which I will go through I'm sweating the machine with this one but
anyway the air Fred technologies meant to be absolutely amazing and anyone who felt have an
overlocker will know that it can be a right pain if I'm you know something goes
wrong and you have to rethread the whole machine it can take quite a long time
another thing to fun stood out when you're buying an overlocker is how many threats it
can overlock with so at this particular model you can decide whether to
use it with two trips or for so currently I have got three threats threaded up
in the machine this is because I was trying to do a rolled him
for the last grass I made and if the hands isn't actually use it so I
quite liked the fact that you can decide how many friends she wants it's a really
good idea to use the for thread overlook if you are saying with nets and not
using the sewing machine to undo the seams initially because then you've brought them good reinforcement
you might want use the three stitch overlock for I'm finishing off the seams if you
were to use this own machine and straight stitch first so you don't need quite the
security of a for threat o'clock search muds you still oracy need to finish off the
road edges and then oversee as two threads overlock is very useful you can do much
more delicate stitches and as a mentions you can do a roll down here so if
you are looking for an overlocker you may want to review the different types of stitches
you can do on the machine because this could affect your choice I really briefly mentioned
about threading machines and I'd say as far as this one goes that it is quite
a challenge to threat although I think anyone who's going opa-locka unless it's one of those
really high-end air threating machines would say that it is the challenge to thread and overlocker
so it is the slot in it but
my machine so you threats the lower lupa's you through its down one to hear which
is fine but then
for which one is it so it's the yellow threat on my machine so the second
one you threads which is actually it goes through this style
you have to hook it on to this little arm mechanism and it's really challenging to
do this some overlookers you can actually open up this light
and and it helps you to get the friend three where is this one you really
have to kind of
happily ease it into the position so I would say that is a slight drawback drawback
with the design and anyone might tell you with changing perirectal need locker provided that
you haven't and you know that threatened snapped you could just cut the thread at the
top and then tie on your new color then you settle detention loves the zero and
then you can feed it through carefully this is a much break away of grief and
changing the color will be alter it on on your overlocker but we see you can't
always a point
actually manually rethreading the whole machine if you know I'm Uther it had snapped or something
else has happened and a lot of the time if the attention is right or it's
not working correctly and you will say this bet is to take all the threats out
and rethread it from scratch because a lot the time that does a result the issues
you have to come from us that I do quite like this color coded system and
it is really nice that it does have a guide ottenere so I don't need to
look at the manual whenever I want to rethread it so this guide on the right-hand
side I'm in slide the own locker is really useful for rethreading say how can you
step for a while and you can't quite remember which order you should threats the machine
and it shows you here so it sits
what will they need to thread the machine and three down brands of Wasim are really
useful because and they can help you adjust attention on your machine it's always valuable to
have your manual to and because it will have the right on how to adjust to
the tension there and it was a in a fit if it looks like this then
you need to tighten attention dial for this one but loosen it for another one but
yeah this is a really good quick reference if you know you don't have it all
overlock man you to hand so I do really like this little panel here it's very
useful and and even less recently when I was playing around with the wrong time option
and this is released will just to bind you how to attach the road him the
sun attachment thing what it's called it does have us depicting actually I'm talking about rolled
hands it does have a specific setting so it's a little I'm dial on the inside
which you switch from the s which is to the search and and then you can
move over to the offer road
so and I think it's us the surgeon might actually just the standard overlocking so yeah
normally I'll have it only as mode but then you can move it to our if
you need to do a roll him and this just helps make these digital more refined
you come to a just how far away the upper cutting blades is there's a little
dying on the inside as well so it just adjusts how
thick you're making your overlocked edge which comes in handy
and there's also a differential seaters so it just gives you the opportunity to either create
gathers or ruffles depending what you're trying to achieve and oversee year so if you've got
up on the side of well you can change the stitch length which is tickly handy
if you are trying to a general them so you'll want to and put the number
right down or you can oversee and make it larger
if you are working with much thicker fabric and you live once one of the city
bunched up this regime also has a free arm options so I just
kind of love you
this section
so
that can be really useful as well not a central but quite useful and that as
you can see so on some models you can then actually see the other side and
that can help with trending if it is exposed but then oversee it helps prevent any
dust another land and turning the machine if you have a model that's a bit more
like that's the final thing to mention is that there is a little through at the
top which you can use to adjust the press of it so you can receive just
attending how fine or thick your fabric is that could also help with your machine and
I think it's definitely worth highlighting that I've done a video recently help the same a
locker and in that video I discussed how I wanted to change the blade and it
turned out that one of the overlock obliques Cruz was really jammed it was the lower
blade and and this obviously was an idea what I had to take it to him
somewhere to get it repaired and for them to at the new blade they did say
this and the course for it was because it's not a brilliant quality machine and so
I mean that could be because it's a budget machine it could be that this particular
model by fluke had a fault it's one of those things where I receive board it
years ago I'd never changed the blade which is quite chainfall really considering how you used
it and how much fabric or probably cut with the original plates but yes something that
obviously wasn't identified during its warrantee
so I probably would recommend if you do get any blocker to check how long the
warranty is perhaps try changing the plates before the end of the warranting just in case
you have an issue like my does because at least then you can get someone to
repair it for you are from that I don't really had any huge issues with it
like I say it's complete game changer at the time I definitely wouldn't have been in
a position to buy a much more expensive overlocker so this really suited my budget it
suited the purpose I wouldn't really dissuade someone necessarily from a budget machine like this and
some people I know with some possibly even cheap models in this have had issues with
threading I'm on the quality of the stitching but sometimes that is due to the threat
that you're using so it's always good to get a bit like with this ocean get
good quality through us it's much more likely to be through better and so that's always
worth checking before you discard the whole machine it is obviously great if you can try
out the machine before this is the sort of machine that isn't necessarily going to be
enough in a showroom place where you can try to pull by
but obviously you do get a warrant till you know you get some protection as a
purchaser so obviously do give it a good test want to and much of that and
that at least you can find out whether it works for you but I would definitely
make sure that the to do got up to scratch and yeah you've just got to
be really patient with running Lacan's as well how once you have got the tension so
it is and it works swimmingly and it really does speed up and it can really
produce a professional finish I would still recommend that argosy if you do have more money
why not go for a better model if you know you're willing to spend that that's
it the this time oversee if you do what we say and training all these how
about this particular model let me know and I'm trying to help out with that and
such as shown in some of the different stitches you can use how you adjust attention
or I can just simply show how you surround the machine
but yeah that's it to this time thanks for watching