jumped up and with you on house fix never looked to tell you the story of
our overlook the disaster we had planned to you today is a quick video on how
to do some maintenance terrible lucky machine today I wanted to bring a video to you
on how to change the blades on your overlocker however we had a few issues during
this
say a few one big as she reversed itself is quite using you unscrew the blades
you but the new blatant
as I mentioned a reason update the dear I wanted to change the blade of my
overlocker I probably have this machine about it yes now you
probably guess
so oversee it's why a long time to go without changing the blade so if anyone
does know how often you to change the Blakey's what you know I have eased the
overlocker increasingly over the last years as well know it's probably
they probably worn out more in recent years that when I first courted you have been
used the more birds also felt that you work it wasn't putting quite as was it
used to know and then I had that big what's needle where it bent I will
shape that didn't stop and disaster have you riesco which I think may have been caught
by a lot of lives as well as potentially that needle was wearing out anyway Oh
and I also a pair cap'n through and you and that probably blunted the and lakes
as well so anyway the laid replacement was well over do so the first laid the
upper blades which like the first went back to the fine I've even got some cities
of that one you can see it's just staring swimmingly there was a bit of resistance
you know what if they have tight in this were quite a lot so you know
and he did you know needed a bit of
yeah I needed a bit of them just to get that one listens but once the
descent it came off nicely replaced with the knee blade and their son perfect
the lower blaze doesn't get quite the whole thing of this machine that is you don't
have a huge man room to get a full-size reprover in nicer its top frowned
it's after on the corner
and although you can bring the part of the case out it don't love will give
you much more room to work with so I don't think I've got a vestige of
the initial attempts to Mr this in the low but but obviously after a while is
getting quite frustrated probably had ever feeling going on and I decided to stop recording with
my right studio like we did try
what few different methods will try to get so we tried various screwdrivers we got our
whole collection which has grown since for me in the last company and that I mean
this openly not the next amazing the regatta said we go your little that you have
a working with technology you so
we had the not so tools available that hopefully would we not to do the jobs
we even got out of rust am which I didn't really think it had trusted but
that may be a bit of something they began it might have helped listen this truth
yes and at that then why why they're trying to increase resistance is a nasty bound
Oh yeah like the trick where some it and have lost the thread on the dock
and you the praise demons for and that abandoned but I think the last time we
had was this old there was just breaking anyway and it wasn't quite enough and then
I was looking in are covered of June so basically we have one main covers in
our class which is chockablock and the right nightmare to guarantee was
not the tickets to be honest if I didn't have such mixed that shit what we
would be such a horrible covered true but obviously it's it's like having have ever been
well but it does come at a cost so yeah I went in there to find
my overlocker bag and go or maybe there's like a special through a special screwdriver for
it but then I looked in there there wasn't any special screwdriver just a regular once
you get with the sewing machine so that that waste a lot a time as a
while and then I also got rid of a couple of other bits from the machine
so I unscrewed a couple of other bits to see can you get to it better
there I just ended up chipping off at aplastic which I'm really not happy with
and so there is a slight bit of plastic missing on the top yeah I mean
it's mainly but design know it's missing and it obviously made a horrible noise
and it doesn't affect the functionality of to I don't even think fabric with the catch
on it it's literally on the edge and it will be on the broken of had
taken off the other but then I know I can't get that and willows the machine
this Lottie well it road in front of the use of the machine
and I made down to sharing photos of the interview with my mum and she and
ten said the votives with my granddad and his opinion was to take it to an
expert there's a machine repair place fairly local to us which obviously at the moment with
lockdown we caught traveled that far so say based right next to a supermarket as well
so it meant that we could tie him with an essential journey it was a little
strange rere an
ice-cream
yes so essentially because the social distance sing a hand to drop off the machine step
back
called their number day then came out with gloves and a mass
had to look at it for asked the description wrote a note on it check the
head on my details then took it away so yeah that's quite a surreal experience and
over and amused than before as well stay
because the door was closed it was
a shed on an industrial estate best way to destroy but yes I went to the
garage side door just start with his there were a couple of regular doctor they just
said old just them go out like you know foot outside the door and then the
step away and cool ups and will come out that I wasn't sure which door to
leave out and he plumped to the front door but if I went to one of
the more garage style doors
and because they're the logo was on top of that door and it wasn't only others
but it turned out that actually they meant a regular to all the lodo stuff was
inside of all Susan about the one I had like bars done that were something though
the reason you can really see it which are we seeing if they were fully open
that they probably had the door
yes so it went away fair
about a week and a half and I thought I wouldn't miss it as much as
I did actually but I did miss it quite a lot people of product buiten well
I wanted to make something to my sister birthday and it would be infinitely easier on
an overlock replicate it was being made out of the net fabric it was a cardigan
the bursar Cardin so I got out this card again and every day was like all
that it might be ready so I'll just can hold out
anyway so it turned out I think it was we got a phone call on the
Friday and my sister birthday was on the Tuesday in order to get it there in
time in the post I needed to pick it up on the Saturday morning we picked
it up at lunchtime on the Friday and then stay off the where protest who had
stopped this card again in the probably the fastest I've ever done it they still not
the same god times there in the book for making about the cardigan in the Chilean
buttons look so I'm still wait slower than intend the people who tested these patterns that
anyway I managed to get it done that evening wrapped up and posted which was brilliant
moving on to what went wrong so my theory is that these through was Tyson too
much in the manufacturing process possibly because it just wouldn't budge any we completely mangled this
crude and we will know and I don't think we could have ever what I mean
without any expert help so the theory of the boy who repaired the machine is that
is a rubbish machine
not the best customer service now I mean I can see I guess they obviously repaired
on to defer machines and they also do so machines postindustrial and domestic one is no
and a lot of places to do specializing that don't tend to get these models I
think I got this from answer originally
and it's a singer model it's the vaulting as each seven five for and it still
cost me a couple of and and I think I was on so protesting eight years
but you know it Augusti doesn't have the same reputation as a a enemy
or a dukey model one of the things and store substantial rest of the time for
you know exactly and it's obviously servilely brilliantly over the last eight years and I do
find it interesting they soapy it's a rubbish machine after repairing it and charging me I
could ever see if it was that by the machine he could have asked whether I
wanted to just get a new one
is
fine now and I've been able to use that yes this is the shame will happen
sublates yeah so there you have it there's the story of changing the overlock of lakes
and obviously if someone doesn't know how often you should change the plate at me
like
that said for this week thanks for watching