today I'm reviewing the shorty pajamas by to the in the button if you like this
video and would like to see more please they forget to like unsubscribe if you haven't
already so this person is from that make it simple back which is their most recent
of it at that time of recording so I went for the short sleeved Germans because
I thought we're getting toward the summer I thought they'd be nice to make another key
waiting was that I had only just about enough of this yellow fabric to makes the
short so you might recognize this fabric from when I made to be kinda cardigan so
if I made it out with the remnants from that and I just about have enough
which was fabulous spoke for the shorts you have to create the person yourself or rather
adapted from the trouser version of the Juno pajamas so for this you essentially just I'm
hacker and cut up at the length you want so I have done an inside like
seem of twelve centimeters within the book I think it
she did six monthly to so I don't double the book just because I'm more comfortable
with this length at the top it's actually the Tabatha t-shirt in the book but there
shortly pajamas and that shone in the book they've just on the road Atisha but I
have added to variation on the top of the way you add up and sleep cuffs
it's also worth noting that I made a size for about the top and the bottom
over he mentions the fabric I used for the autumns for the top I got this
fabric from trader which is one of my local fabric triggers boys interesting is a hit
amiss and sometimes so-called backs of good stuff other times it's really hard to find anything
useful in the job but I already went on a good day and it's actually a
really nice fabric it feels really soft and it's a single ordinate fabric so it's quite
thin
and it does mean that it's a bit more chundering to work with just because the
ends color but it feels really nice to wear and I'm hoping it will wash nicely
as well for their rubbing I brought this especially from I believe it's my fabrics the
online source so mighty relays don't exactly match but all it would be nice to have
a bit of coordination between the top or bottom and times a difficulty I'd say it's
good for a constant beginner it's a nice simple make and it came together really well
I did not still any unpicking I think the main thing that a beginner might find
challenging beyond the usual challenges you go with a knit fabric would be adding the neckbands
because if you do have an issue with the size of the next fountaining lying flat
and that can think of it frustrating and but saying that the instructions and I sent
clear and you guide you on that something I did do on this and which probably
added all of it a time is I did machine tack the neck found one first
just to make sure that it was the right size just because I tend to use
my overlocker
after that when I want I'm happy with the bits and it would be a lot
harder to unpick if it wasn't correct in the same like the waist bands and is
attached similar to the neckbands in the sense to you
identify that you you know you quarter the elastic and then you much up with the
scenes on the shorts and then you need to stretch are generally to attach with these
as well you then fold over to encase the elastic on the inside and then you
have to stretch it that you then do is in battle and to enable it to
stitch it in place and that could be a bit changes well I was a bit
concerned well that's H doing it evenly but I'm quite pleased with promise to end up
the clarity of instructions I think I said it every single time I've reviewed the to
the Orson's passing which has been quite a few now it's really clear and nice to
read so in this book you do have a checklist of instructions which is a much
more shorthand version and you also have the much more detailed long hands instruction for with
the trousers I actually falling to the longhand instructions but for the top I volleyed the
checklist both worth nice to follow that the checklist version with the top I did every
now and look at the more detailed insurrection just don't wish I promise doing everything and
the way I thought I should add that was useful to design and fit I'm pretty
happy with that's because it tells you how to measure out the elastic for your own
measurements it will receive means that you get a nice comfortable for thalassic for these will
find so that seems to work on the track as your drafting the shorts you get
so choose the length so that worked out nicely so I've cut these at length which
uncomfortable with and also that I could get out of the fabric moment I have already
like the
I'm caught found on here actually I think it just some other mentioned it as a
bit of pondered to this of always quiet white t-shirt and it goes in nicely with
the short beyond that to say this is quite a simple plain teacher so it's a
good staple what you like wearing t-shirts it's quite similar to the peak t-shirts that I
made recently when I make my you can stop both are quite good in the sense
that you can use them as a blank canvas to then embellish or make your own
we've match the shorts they're based about an inch below your waist so and which is
quite a nice level particularly of pajamas so other mentioned they seem fine and I think
it'll that's quite well the time taken as a book suggests this the minutes for casting
out including drafting the pattern for the short
for me it took more like an hour and a half I have mentioned before I'm
quite slow at cutting out one thing that might have made it a bit longer for
me was because I was using a run-in piece of fabric I couldn't cut on the
phone for the shorts I had to cut each piece separately again ever read and taking
an extra forty minutes to do that I think that is just I'm slower than the
average speed of those who decided on the time for the book the serving time it
suggests two hours it took me three hours I did at the
cuff and on here so I guess that added but trying potentially although the snow look
up to him press stuck and switch the hand so I'm not sure how much time
would have really added I did asked that extra step of attacking the neck found on
as well so attention that might earth as it on a bit of time again I
don't think it really all about it quite as much time again I don't think it's
quite a whole extra hour or so I think it's just that I'm a lot slower
and suggests that a as I mentioned before my birth particle review it might be that
you get the quicker their more time to make up for these persons the overall I'm
really happy with these I haven't yet worn these as pajamas so I guess that will
be
the promise of us on how ductile they are but because they're me now than that
fabric I'm expecting them to be pretty nice to where I'm thinking of adding a bit
of handed broidery to the top just had a bit more detail from making this top
for the bananas I think I would have another go at it or making just a
t-shirt to where every day as well as I mentioned both is of the peak teacher
a really good ones for you know creating your own top that's it for today thanks
for watching