today I'm reviewing the birth the guard again as always that you might this video and
what Seymour please don't forget the like to subscribe if you haven't already so today I'm
wearing the birth their cars again which is in the new tulu one book and by
to the the Boston this is the book care to make it simple easy speeding sewing
projects to stitch up in an afternoon this is my first project from the book I
do plan to make several projects from the book just so I can review the book
more comprehensively I decided to start with the best cardigan more tactically because I thought it
would be the quickest might take the pastor details other mentioned it's called better
the variation I've done is the plane version so I haven't added any pockets I haven't
been any book color are designing or anything like that and I haven't added the samples
in the cup which is another option that you can do the design houses to be
in the button from this book and finally the side I've made it is a street
plies for but the fabric I biggest this is the fabric that but mentally my mammographic
an album which I've mentioned before thinking my kindergarten review and also the reviewer made all
the baby pitiful essentially I used the wrong fabric that both red fabrics and I wanted
this one for the kinda card again for my Nan ended up cutting a thicker fabric
for that one so I have to rethink why was doing with the other fabric that
the remnants of anyway and I have this left over my static and he said as
a mansion its thinner than the fabric that I ended up making the publican into my
name it's a single nets so you can see is I'm essentially if you're netizen like
stocking such so there's the whole side on the back and the net side on the
front it's a nice greatly fabric actually so if I take it off you can see
it behind nicely
it is a thin fabric but I do actually find it quite worn when I'm wearing
it can't remember where he got this fabric actually it's been in my smash for a
while I decided to use this fabric because first later with a myself it meant I
won't have to spend any more money and second I really like the color of the
fabric and I thought it would be quite good to dress up and down so I
could wear it to work for example for serving with this hybrid it will find this
over I didn't have any major problems I did have trouble cutting out though so when
I was putting it out I did actually have to recast a couple of the pieces
because I realized I had actually laid out completely flat and it was it was then
going to hang about walking so I did report of events in times of difficulty it's
a nice simple quick make as with a lot to summon the buttons passed and they
do have begin at the mind and especially for this book because that is make it
simple they're trying to make their own simplest projects that can I forget you're so go
back or if you're a beginner it's a nice one that you don't have to worry
too much about fits or to have too many complicated construction techniques in it I feel
that doesn't is the case in this instance it's got more passive pieces than other simple
pattens for example or cocoa dress it's very simple of got running back these and then
you can and cuffs that you want and the extra color peace but essentially you could
just make out of a couple of happen pieces this you've got the two front pieces
of the back peace the cuts the a neckband and you've also got the headband here
as well however do not decided by having to cut all those least about it's definitely
a fun project to make and you don't have to worry about pressing up the hem
because you got the hand and there and likewise the cuffs and the met around it
all finishes off those edges for you to crises instructions I found the nice and clear
or eyes it was lit at the checklist so in this book in cross a checklist
that each person so unless the other things they got what they call short cut steps
and it's a nice little checklist what you can
barons so that economically with your time as possible so it put everything to confess that
the things I don't see him in everything will go then it was you what you
can stitch or at the same time what you can turn then it goes back so
we can enter after you've done all those steps so I didn't follow the checklist rather
than going for them along hands of version but I did to look back at the
instructions the more detailed instructions when I was a look that confused on the part sir
if I just wanted to double-check that I was doing it correct me so I still
use them but it was why nice to just have a really simple and checklist to
look through and I think that did speed up the time to for the bits that
I did check over which were a few bits I found like with my previous experience
with telling the Boston pattern it was nice and straightforward clear and understandable from the images
and to the text it design unfit I think it's a really nice pattern that didn't
time for this to be a gun I could wear to work and I think it's
still in I am a little bit
I don't know I felt like it was it looks quite casual so I will need
to have to think about what to wear it with very likely neck and become down
at side and I like the handbound as well I do think next time I might
possibly had a bit more night on to the sleeves it was spent fine but I
think ever wearing it over the day it probably will creep up my arm would say
next time I would possibly add not too much at mayst an inch or two but
that's just the I quite like
long sleeves so you know and but say that you know this length is for to
be fine for me it's just my preference would be forcibly at it and
it's all my hands a bit more just isn't a bit easier it's worth noting that
I did make this pretty much slowly on the overlocker because I have one and I
thought I'd take advantage the block is so quick to be honest and that definitely spent
me up the only bit that I had to do on the sewing machine would you
do a couple of securing stitches at the autumn on the handbound this is just to
make sure that the same for the
neckband doesn't end up and picking out at the bottom at the only reason I had
to thread up the sewing machine but everything else was done on the overlocker one thing
I have noticed is that the cuff him keeps funding over towards the cuff rather than
to the slave and possibly a for topstitch that it would result it is up to
say in instructions but depending on your fabric you might want stiva I did press it
in place that is just not staying and it does bought me a little bit but
I mean it's a really tiny
things that obviously had a result really easily by just adding some by the exact stitch
or and to needle on that the time take then I was very intrigued to find
out how long it take me just because this book does give you some guide time
so you for this project it says that the cutting side is fortunate and some time
as an hour last five so cutting fine forty minutes it's definitely took me longer but
I would say that I am quite a slow Costa say it and also this fabric
was so hard to lay out and as I mentioned that did it wrong so it
definitely take me probably more like an hour to consult however if you use an easier
fabric or just within the need to probably will take in a verbal two minutes but
setting time I would think it took me about two hours twenty where is the book
same an hour thirty five the younger is anything in a life feet that should designed
it similar to a recipe book where you have a good time for the prep time
and cooking time which is because then it means that like you're keeping you can find
your sewing accordingly I think in that same light it's a bit like said recipe books
where you know don't take you a bit longer sometimes especially if it is the first
time you've done a rescue so obviously this is the first time I've made it so
I'll be interested if I make another one whether I managed maker in a much faster
time I checked not to our pockets because I wanted it to look very smart for
what just person reference but I just felt like the pocket it's my own attracted from
the knife simple and the good design of this version of that makes sense to conclude
I really enjoyed making this project I think it was really interesting to quite strictly trapped
my time to see how it compared with the book and I are not quite fun
and a bit of a challenge the other thing to mention actually with the time bring
is that I should have been a lot more prepared to get it up because I
probably did waste time go Oh I can't find this particular tool or item more you
know what the long didn't have the heiling board set up all the time so I'd
have to quickly ditali birds and then I'm trying to find my press inkle so that
I wouldn't burn the fabric but be able to get a much better press illness fabric
so there are lots insist me to help so perhaps if I like leaving a bit
more organized with my tools I might have made this a lot recommend it I was
twenty several I'm really happy with this make I would make it again have imagined might
add a bit link to the sleeves it family is something you could make in an
afternoon because that's laisser it took me less muttering a half hours and took them to
make the whole thing so during how hours it's definitely the problem of an afternoon and
yeah I look forward to you trying out some more of the mix in the book
that's it to today thanks for watching