hello today I'm reviewing the fray address which is in the book stretch by to be
one if you like this video and want to see more content please don't forget to
life and subscribe so just a few details on the pattern the other mentioned is the
friar dress in the book stretch I've made it a dress version but there's also a
sweater version
I will take all of the variation of having a Conor because as you can see
so there's also a mock neck time one which I think all the other variations feature
in the book also I made a size for think the fabric of used for this
is actually from the fabric land in the UK so I think I got this
is no at least a couple of his go if not more so it's been sitting
in my stash for quite a while I was actually going to make the cocoa Drustan
its which is quite a similar I'm person to this one and Billy and I I
concede the hannett feature ever we would go well with this fabric its fabric so yeah
it's quite a stretching it actually and I think of it stretched too much it might
be a bit
transform but apart from that I really like it I think the drapes nicely
and it's one that's really nice to lay up with type so in the book stretch
they designed the patterns in the order of difficulties so you start off with a BB
scare and which I've reviewed well I reviewed the pinnacle version and and there's also the
Frankie t-shirt which I previewed as well in the past and this one's a few patterns
on so it is a bit more challenging than those two and but I still wouldn't
say it's it's not achievable so as mentioned it it's quite like the cocoa dress in
the sense that it's a nice
it's a similar shape or resee the comic is a different feature but I wouldn't say
it's actually that difficult could you just stitch the two bits together
and it shows on quite easily on to the neckline which I'm having a neckbands probably
a lot more challenging than adding this helmet so no sure making some more connect funds
father I'll have to give it go and find out I won't they mentioned in previous
reviews on telling the buttons patterns that really nice and straightforward it's like was holding your
hands as you go through the process so yeah it's really
nice pattern to follow so the design and fit
again it is similar to the cocoa dress so if you like that design you're probably
like this Paston as well I did find it probably as short as the cocoa dress
so that kind of gone for a sort of sixties him if that makes sense so
and it's probably shorter than I normally like because I didn't actually length the littleness which
normally I would I'm not sure wise in this time but saying that I think it's
fine with types I think crossed to get you sat there abridges one where but I
was lighter than its long sleep so I'm very likely to wear it when it's cold
I really like this a comeback if it's a really nice long one
I think it at the really nice detail preview really nice and a playing fabric as
well well they say that I do like to live them more connect phones now which
I think would go really nicely with the pitiful layering up again in the winter it's
difficult to gauge the time taken just because it had that she been a bit of
time since I made it but I don't think it took more than a day to
make I did wait to him low because I felt that this fabric needed to rest
so I left it a couple of days just to settle and then I double-checked the
him and stitched it which I'm really glad I did everyone really pleased with this dress
it's one that I probably will only wear when it is really cold outside because I
get hot quite easily and in Cornwall it's quite mild where we live so I don't
often where a lot of long sleeve so in that sense it's probably not as
as good as some of the other person's that have made from the book discuss I
don't think I'm gonna wear it as much to say the Frankie t-shirt or the baby
plentiful but saying that you know if you love someone that's a lot colder this was
gonna be a lovely dress or sou'wester if you make the sweater version and yes just
rocket warm when it's cold outside or cold inside and then we hootings like I found
it enjoyable to make as well which is always a bonus that said the today thanks
for watching