today I'm reviewing a free pattern on the line it's so so easy surges scrap pacha
I think that's what it's called in it as a ways if you like this video
and what Seymour don't forget to life into scribe okay so as I mentioned it's a
free person in line if you want to the so so easy website which I will
link in the description if you go on to the website you can view it on
a blog post or you can download the PDF I believe and that you can print
out I did print it out by ended up looking at the what vergine as well
just because I printed out in greyscale and was quite hard to understand some of the
photos because of that so there aren't any variations oversee it's one simple person however they
do advise on how you could adjust this Matt so that it in case your overlocker
is vastly different to the one that they used to face these measurements on I ended
up following the exact measurements because I had a quick look and I thought it should
fit so it's already worth noting as well I have made this as a gift so
I will not be using it myself and so I can't really count on the practicalities
of it and whether it is useful with a scrap patcher however I can unreceived review
how the person was to make the fabric I've used it is probably a place to
quoting cotton wait I use us to make my partner about for carrying his marking when
he used to teach and I had some of it left over and I thought we
would be patted for this project so it's the Sudley Emmett I've got it in two
colourways so and it's this to can fabric and then you conceived a contrast fabric underneath
them
and it's also inside in the pockets as well for the edging of just used and
shot ports bias finding so I think it must be just by a wide length I
think when it's folded over it's about one point to some smiters in terms of difficulty
I parents this person relatively challenging to be honest it's quite simple it's all squares and
rectangles so in that respect it's quite easy but there is an awful of bias finding
and although I don't need like to to the machine stitched the first slide and then
hand so the second sighed I used the machine to topstitch and I just found that
it dragged quite a bit his public as I don't do it that often I haven't
practiced enough to get a really nice finish but I did find that challenging moving once
clarity I did find that the instructions were quite challenging to follow I I don't think
I was in the best from the mind when I was making it to be honest
he could just be my interpretation at the time however I did find aspects I wasn't
sure what I was doing
I think part of it was because you're meant to quote the pieces and I haven't
I have eased fusible place so I have got a bit of having in there but
I think what they've done in the past Amoz they had quoted the outer and lion
pieces together
and as I didn't do that
I was looking at ways where I could hide the seams if that makes sense so
I kind of made it more complicated for myself than it should have been there I'm
not really sure whether it's just I had my own agenda so I was conflicting with
the instructions or whether it was that they were quite difficult to follow there are some
reviews on the blog post and and they were really positive so he should just be
able them in the right framer mind or I was so determined to hide all of
the raw edges that I ended up doing my own thing for the design and fit
as you can see it it's my overlocker anyway perfectly and fleet will fit the overlooker
of the recipients as well but I think their family landed the sides of people occurring
fingers crossed it well yeah so it fits I'm very nicely on here I've actually got
it on the table wethers a slope on the side and which normally haven't use my
locker on this table and so it's not sitting quite as nice to was that normally
would so if I had it on the table which didn't have this step edge I
would have the overlocker right up to the edge and then that would allow the excess
fabric that was being cast of to fall nicely into the pockets I really liked the
design I like that is very generous though if you know you don't regularly empty your
scrap capture that's okay cause you got loads of rum they're also I guess if they
had been a bit smaller it might have known it might missed it I'm not sure
that's yeah it works really well I'm very happy with it I am thinking that if
I did make another one I would possibly look at lining the pockets with a
different fabric so one that I guess it's easier to scoop the remnants out of because
I just think that might be you know older fluffy lets you end up getting when
you I'm overlock likely a few gossipers of them fasting awarding
you've got the issue that you might not ever be able to completely get all the
stuff out of the the pocket section so possibly I might do something like you know
a bit more of a plastically fabric will and Waterbury fabric gone will to resist of
one I'm just kiss then it'll be a locks me there or I guess you could
use that final that stuff you can iron on to make your fabric have that so
flaxy sheen so you could do that as well and it might be easier to scoop
out your fabric the time taken it is actually quite a quick make so if you
did want to make it as a gift possibly for Christmas and for serving friend it
would work quite well firstly I'm doing it all project like this I find cutting up
all the bits takes the longest second I'd say it's all the bias finding so that
is quite a lot of bias finding but it's definitely want it so Avril I'm kind
of happy with the pattern I did get quite frustrated with it and and I guess
maybe I just had a slightly different view of how it was meant to work out
I think also it's not the easiest past him to follow if you are a beginner
however I think most people who are going to be making I'm a mess and scrap
catchable their own overlocker if they've got a noble aka likably have done enough serving to
be able to make the mat anyway they grew I would recommend it because it is
a good size and you just might want to
be a bit more creative when you're looking at the instructions on how you want to
the final finish to look like to say I think I did deviate from it and
side of it because I didn't want to see the rule seems within the poppets if
I made it again I'm definitely going to
look at this person but I might look at the way in which I can
tweak it a bit to sleep my own need that that makes sense so see I
mean it's amazing it's a free pass to the Dougherty someone's were tired on that and
shared and there in time and efforts but I would have a look and you know
don't be afraid to adjust it if you want to that's it for today thanks for
watching