hello today I'm reviewing this dress as the ways that you like this video I would
like to see more please don't forget to like unsubscribe if you haven't already like this
dress is the new look sick zero one tree which I fortunately had two copies of
so I cut direct from the pattern pieces for a change normally I traced my passions
just in case I want to make a different sides for someone else or it goes
horribly wrong and I need to cut it in a different side I despised it's very
handy to
safeguard our passions that way but to see it does take a lot more time to
do that so it really was and how much time before so this address is a
view would do on the pattern which is the dress I'm so in this pattern you
can also make a jacket or blazer
and there are different variations on that actually you can with make a sort of waste
kept and there are some trousers as well which you can create so for this person
I made the size courtin the fabric of uses from pound fabrics I bought it a
couple of years ago so I'm not completely sure on the content I'm not sure he
would actually advertise that but I'm pretty sure at the polyester and it's quite lightweight and
drapey so it's really nice for addressed but I wasn't too sure because of how lightweight
it was and also the how
how we pick it was so why did do was I got some ivory antistatic lining
from a much more local shock to me truly fabrics and so I have minded with
that which should hope please stop it from catching or rising up prophecy there is a
risk with polyester that it will become quite static the to cleave that additional layer will
support it and as they make sure that you know it's definitely okay thick this fabric
was early challenging to work with I did have to be quite careful I think the
first
bits of stitching such as the thoughts I did taxes but then I go a bit
more reckless near the end and you really get in times of difficulty I think this
is quite a beginner friendly project you can obviously make it more challenging I think adding
aligning like I did definitely leveled it up significantly if you use a much more stable
fabric than I did that would make it easier I think the fabric choice and the
fact that I traced a line it made it a much more challenging make for me
personally and it has taken me quite a word to complete it but saying that I
think that the fact that is got Ragland sleeves it's probably quite good for a beginner
it's a lot easier to fit regular sleeves than it is to fit in set and
sleeves you don't have to worry about easing into the shoulder moving on to the design
and it's the reason I chose this person is because I really do like regular sleeps
I think it's quite a nice classic style so it's but I start to but it's
also got and does but low as well on the waist and it's got that at
the fact so it shapes nicely but it's quite and it's quite I'm the least fell
me anyway I'm it's got a reasonable amount of ease obviously you could adjust that if
you'd prefer a more fitted garments so I didn't adjust the length of this
dress however I think I probably didn't leave a bit of length when I'm I got
my Fondor to help me level up to him before I hand it I said it's
pretty much dead on I'm knee level for me which I quite like I don't like
wearing really short dresses so this is a suitable length for me to just a job
it and this topstitching is optional so you don't need to add that I did add
it mainly because I forgot to unstitch the under stitching and I was worried about the
facing peeping out so I thought the best thing to do would be and to have
that topstitching which are things about maybe two centimeters away from the edge
it does had a very nice detail what I don't think this is a really this
fabric needed it so the way I lined it I have actually lined everything so I'd
like the sleeves as well I did get really confused and the reason I probably left
it but about a month or so it's because I couldn't work out how to
line the sleeves
and him the CD part and attach it all together now I look back I can't
actually room but how I did this even though I only did this a week ago
this part of the pattern
but yet so I got stored on this section and
after leaving it for quite a number of weeks I then went back to it and
then managed to do what I was trying to avoid and which was twisted so that
you couldn't learn tell it right side out so I end up doing that I had
to unpick it anyway and then I worked out how to
line it properly so I have actually I wonder stitch the
the sleep him so I did stitch
the sleeve pieces together at the him
at the point in the instructions other boys to hammer
but then I did manage to still stitch
the sleeves onto the main piece of the lining and the main favorite pieces and to
the main fabric sleep he says if that makes sense is any I found lining the
dress very confusing and I like done it because I think I'm gonna wear a lot
more because I would get frustrated with it I'm going in staticky but it was very
confusing and I did find that that holds me up quite a long in the process
which brings me I'm quite nicely to time taken so I started this in February and
initiatives and day so that's about mid-June so it's taken me quite a long time to
get it done obviously I did get stalled and I was in future I was doing
at one point so that helped me up quite a lot I think if you made
it in a much more stable fabric and you didn't have to line it you could
definitely don't in a weekend I do some people are superquick so is like for me
down in the day but I think using a much more interesting fabric like this where
it does move around quite a lot and if you're not used to lining dresses and
you want to Billy line it like I have it could take you a bit longer
saying that it probably wouldn't take me as long as it has this time now that
I've modeled my boy through once even though I can't quite ruler that how I managed
to
finish off the lining I'm sure I could do a lot like the next time another
thing that I did which I wish I hadn't was that my machine stitched the lining
and facing while attaching the zip to the main bit of the fabric so in the
pattern using ordinaries it and it meant to the last sip at the back and we
don't know who to but I put had invisible second
so the invisible sip I felt was a lot easier to insert and elapses because I
was that really confused on the instructions they have a fairly decent trunk of instructions for
the zip that is only a couple of diagrams and I was getting really confused so
in the end I thought I'm gonna cut my losses
I can't be dealing with this and I think I could have done it if I
hadn't added a lining but because I needed to add the lining bear and I really
couldn't work out how to incorporate that with the lobster I thought it's gonna be easier
to add an invisible did so what do you wish I had done differently I don't
regret the invisible did I think it suits this dress quite well anyway more than potentially
a lapse it would have it's particularly with this fabric I think it might the fabric
Mike direct quite a lot when I stitched in place but I do wish I'd hand-stitched
the lining and the facing because at the top where I've got the
facing stitched in on the zip it's just a bit too close to the teeth so
he does go up fine but it is a bit of a challenge to throw it
up it always kind of stop sundews woke and you have to carefully then not it
along to sit right up to the top I mean at least it still works and
I didn't have to one pick it but in a way I probably should have one
pictor and then again just because it would be so much easy to sit up and
down so overrule I do recommend this person I really like it I think it's a
nice her class address the necklines quite less as well I think that early flattering I
think I would potentially make this again I'm not to make it any time singing and
I'd be quite interested to try with a slightly easier fabric maybe of the linen blend
might be quite nice here for now I'm looking forward to wearing this out of it
and seeing how much I like it but I think next time I make it I
may double check the fist at the front I'm not sure and the dots are in
the right place or I might need to take it in slightly I think at the
middle which oracy by the time I realized it was too late to do on this
one and silver see something I'd have to
adjust at the cutting stage but also I think possibly with a different fabric it wouldn't
be an issue I think it might just be consiste fabrics so drapey that might have
been an issue with it all I'm happy with it and I think I will get
some good you sense of its that's it for this time thanks for watching