hello today I'm reviewing the Breton tea from the great British sewing be book from stitch
to style as always if you like this video would like to see more like this
please don't forget to like unsubscribe if you haven't already so the yellow someone wearing today
is the Breton tea as I mentioned it's from this book from the stitch to style
one of several great British sewing the books and a novel nyo
so
it's from the base pass in the Breton top so there's a long sleeved version of
this essentially it's pretty much the same as this but you have an additional sleeve peace
that you attach
so
I fancied making the short-sleeve version as I've mentioned many times it's quite mild down here
in Carmel so I thought I'd do a short-sleeved copy and I quite like the look
of the short steel of one as well
it's got grown sleeves as you can see
so the side I made I'm pretty sure it's the size twelve and I found that
the sizing was quite generous so I went with that rather than my usual size fourteen
moving on to the fabric so I've used a lemony yellow I guess you'd call it
a fabric it is straightforward it feels like a cotton net fabric I'm not entirely sure
where I got it from now it's been my stash for a while
I'd say it it doesn't feel brilliant quality and it definitely doesn't have any lasting in
it so I'm not sure how long his top is going to survive it it doesn't
feel like it will recover it stretches and I am a bit concerned that it's gradually
going to stretch not even like
this way I think it's going to horizontally stretch
and but anyway so
the fabric wasn't the best I mean saying that you know it's been a good me
to try out this person and see whether I like it or not so I guess
that helps in terms of difficulty I think this is a fairly straightforward passen and if
you're confident with nets that is the main thing I'd say which is a bit different
to pass some other knit patterns is that it's a simple I think yes the facing
on the top so so basically there are four pattern pieces for this variation you've got
the front peace you've put the back peace and then you've got to the front facing
and the back to so so rather than
a passing where you put and neck Bandon
you're just putting a facing on a bit like you do with a lot of wave
and base persons so in that sense am it's not too difficult however another difference with
it to other ones is its but this really nice feature where it's the little slip
it's a little slit in the side seam
and it's really nice feature
so I guess if you've started sewing with nets and you want to add a few
more skills to your repertoire it's quite a good person and but yet it's slightly fiddly
doing the little sideslipped but not to of passing the clarity of instructions I found them
pretty straightforward so for this pattern you just followed the same for the Breton top you
just admit the step which I think something like step seven which is attaching the sleeve
peace onto
the main pieces I found both the illustrations and the written instructions helpful and easy to
follow their as I meant in there aren't too many steps to this for design and
fit I'm still on the pencil this one to be honest I'm not entirely convinced I
like the neckline so it's quite a wide
net line on this
and again it might be just the fabric hissing I'm just worried it's going to gradually
stretch out and drop off one shoulder
this is something I should have done with this particular
garment is maybe add something to stop the next line stretching out quite so much so
I have but some stay tape which is stitched I think from the neckline to about
there on the shoulder seams however I probably did need something with a slight more give
select the stretching its day tape equivalent I could have done without all the way around
the neck because I am concerned that it's going to gradually stretch out shape
apart from that I think it's quite a nice length normally I prevent him quite long
talks but I think this one is quite good when you don't want to talk to
be quite so long for example when you're wearing it with a card again or a
jumper and it's nice that the length of this one will actually sit with in
the length of the jumper regarda as I got a lot tops they're just fall below
the cart in length and I do like the little and side seam slips as well
which is a nice extra little design feature the time taken this is achievable within a
day quite easily so to complete I probably won't make this pattern again it's funny because
I was really tempted to make the dress hack version as well but now that I've
made it I'm not convinced that I'm that fond of this neckline even if I did
make it in a fabric with a lasting in it so that it recovered a lot
better and I put in some missions to make sure that it didn't stretch out too
much
I think comparably more likely to make another one of say the money dress by so
over it
but yeah probably won't make this one again although I do you think a lot of
the issues I have with it is because I've chosen a fabric which may have not
been best suited for it so that set for today thanks for watching