hello today I am reviewing simplicity pattern one three eight five which is a mixture of
lunch bags and Arkady's
I have made lunch bag Virginie and which is next to me here
now if you've seen my pattern review or time lapse of the market tote by Mikhoels
you will have noticed that I've used the exact same fabric combination I was going to
use a different fabric from my stash however the person who's going to receive this as
a gift saw the market tote and love the fabric on it so I decided to
use the remnants for this instead
so I've used to different fabrics but in the pattern it bites cutting out into three
sections there's the main fabric which is I'm this part and all the pockets
the contrast fabric which is underneath the pockets and on the face as well as the
strap and there's also the lining
which is inside so as you can see if I combined the contrast fabric and the
lining sections and purely at a preference but it would be quite good to make the
mining out of waterproof fabric if you have some as it would just make it a
bit more practical than lunch bag
other iceman's you need to complete this pattern is interlining and you need it for both
the exterior and interior sections of this project
and this just gives it a bit more stability and structure
you also need thermal wedding and this is to create insulation for the lunch bag so
it will help keep it cool in the summer
and this then awarding and you can use for example to make Aben gloves as well
the other thing you need is felt grow
as you can see you don't need to much about crows so I'm the stuff I've
used here am I got from the supermarket so you don't need to go you to
a haberdashery in particular and for this
fastening
I found this a simple pattern to follow and it's got lots of markers and notches
to ensure that you and place different elements such as the side pockets in the right
place
there's also a marker for placing the velcroed
I almost forgot to add the boat grow onto the main back section and but that
is complete oversight on my part it is in the instructions
and it also has the same announces printed on the fabric pieces I found this very
useful and in order to pattern match this front section with the front flap and just
that my the fox on the front came out well
you don't think I would say about the Velcro is and to watch out and for
the teeth side snagging on your sewing machine
in the past of had trouble with Velcro because I've seen too close to the teeth
section and its caught on the threads so just make sure you stitch on the very
edge of the teeth section to avoid this or attentively could hand stature if you're not
too often
the instructions are very clear and strode forward if I had no trouble whatsoever in making
this lunch bag
it did make the snap pouch well and for this I had a slight issue with
it
with this snap pouch and you had boat crew for the
fastenings
and it's not lined with thermal wedding by the way I'm it's just a simple
main fabric and aligning
with the Velcro I wasn't sure whether to place at a quarter of an inch or
a half inch from the raw edge and I believe it was probably half an inch
the same as for the side
as a result it means that I my topstitching has stitched into the Velcro pieces
it's not if you just you but it's something to bear in mind
with regards to the fist and design my compliment too much as it is a gift
however I would say it's the standard lunch bag size M is quite roomy so you
could get a decent pat lunch I really like the factor has the side pockets and
that night easy access to a Mac such as a serial bar old shop while
I think you could probably add
a couple of pocket inside as well which might be quite nice and you could either
add it to the center back as a patch pocket or you could mimic the outside
pockets and add pockets on the site in the lining
the anything I would say about the design I think it's really good
apart from the strap those get a bit and the way of opening the lunch bag
however I think this is something which will give a bit more over time
even now it's it seemed to be easier to get into
this took me a few hours to make and that's not including cutting out and attaching
the interlining
I thought it was quite a simple straightforward to make I would definitely make it again
and may even adapt it to make across over bag as it quite a nice design
and shape but we would need to do is length in this strap and so that
it can go round accordion over your shoulder