today I'm reviewing this to peer person as always if you like this video and would
like to see more please they forget to like and subscribe if you haven't already in
case so this is the Safiya pattern which is from the make it simple book by
talion button now I've done a bit of a mash-up out of two of the variations
so there is a dungarees variation of severe and there is a place you version what
I've done is I've used the top section of the numbers and the bottom section of
the place seat how of this is because I quite like the idea of the short
version for face sections I cut out the signs for it's probably quite obvious to some
of you that this is an old person I thought that will be good to use
an old bit of fabric from my stash because I wanted to show how this would
turn out and I don't want to read a nice about fabric in the process I
found this fabric really easy to work with its brightness picking cotton and it was a
dream to say with some for the difficulty of this pattern the most challenging part naturally
for me was to match the two variations together it does suggest during this variation in
the book but it doesn't give you the guidance on which sets to follow when I
mean it's not too difficult to do this because they do but each other really well
you don't have to you know breed apart us to fit into the short section it's
pretty straightforward however what I wasn't sure when was whether to go with the tie on
the waste or whether he is the elastic so I kind of made it at first
without the elastic but I oversleep still have the length with the waist band in there
so obviously if you did want to make the degrees version with the time version you
do need to remember to take out about for an hadland meters they rather than it
leaves that bit of fabric it is what really cut it out to have the way
to span section I just decided to give the elastic to go which I'm pretty happy
with and say the most challenging apart personally for me was making these little narrow straps
as essential part of the time maybe a good hour or so with me from him
to return the straps right side out normally I just you and I end up stitching
it Rome sides together and just for dinner this was even now inspired I thought I'm
gonna do it properly this time and I did get there eventually but it did take
a while there is a good tip in the book where you and have an extra
length of thread which you talk him so that it can help you turn your thrap
right side out it's worked with limited success for me so the first one if after
a fair bit of encouragement I managed to get it through the other one I managed
to snap pretty much Sri always you do have to be careful with that method but
with a bit about missing needle and one of those really don't know I'm told you
know they're no messages of the little you can that over the end I did manage
to get them broke through in the end as you can see the clarity of instructions
they are very clear as I mentioned the main struggle for me was just making sure
I matched up the two different patterns at the right time for the design of fit
I am quite happy with this they do think you need to be careful with your
measurements do very quite a lot you do need to keep a mindset you've got to
pull this dungaree Patton up over your hips so the opening of talk needs to be
big enough for that this wasn't a problem me I didn't feel a little it's not
when it gets to the habit action but that could be more an issue for someone
else do you do need to pay attention to the instructions where it seems that you
need to make sure I think you have to choose the past in possibly by your
hip size and even if your bus lines is a lot smaller they recommend not grading
if you do great do you need to add the fastening such as the sun I
do quite like the elastic version his so I think it looks quite nice it makes
it a lot more intense than it would have been I do think it would look
quite nice with the times well though so you could just and cut off about that
length not do that spans and then as the tie that is in the book for
the full next unburies version it's really difficult for me today how long this took me
and to be honest the book doesn't tell you how to make this particular variation because
it's not an official variation in the book it's just the suggestion to be honest I
lost track of time with this mainly prepares I did kind of make it without the
waistband but still have the length then I had to unpick in it then I created
the waist and it was the managed to because you know it's got a flat front
on this wasteland I managed to to
mark out the flat section I stand on the back not sure why anyway then I
had to research the back and pick the front reattach the elastic
but fortunately actually and stitch the elastically place when I put it back to front so
I just have to you take the pens out
but yeah I did a few gets wrong not sure that just because I'm tired or
I just want I'm paying attention so to complete I am really happy with these I
actually quite like this old curtain material or the fabric for this and I think it
looks really nice with a plain white t-shirt it's like sick it would actually go room
nicely with the tablet the teacher I made the last time which is part of my
pajama set and I've really tempted to just where I was a regular top from the
the of John atop I'd be lying them as my pajamas this week and they're really
company so I do recommend making Luhmann's John it's nice and company the elasticated waist I
think that's making it a bit more flattering one thing that is a shame is that
you can't use the pocket person on this I don't know if you could if you
made official a bit longer but it does want the slide seem Hawkins that you can
make the Scythia traceurs they are too long for making for the place in saying that
lot joy and a patch pocket either to this and firstly with this I guess the
person's just a bit is the anyway so it looks nice without it but I'm not
sure even if I put his pocket on here is quite nice just having a claim
to that it for this week I do have a hundred day product video of which
I'll be releasing later on today and I'll be carrying on with that but otherwise I'll
have another general throwing related video next week that's what chicken