today I'm revering the mickle stitch and save easy cotton and six for nine three at
which consists of two market food which you can make
I've made version a which is a more rectangular version it's got to wood and tells
for the handles the cardboard banks and exterior pockets
and this is the final result
there as you can see of used their medium-weight cousin dark fabric for both the exterior
and the interior lining
of used interfacing as well and which is suggested as optional but I recommend it as
even with the interfacing it's still
not hold it structure very well although there's nothing in it so it would obviously hold
better if I had a full of projects
so the doubt I cut myself I'm using a sore I got a big piece of
wooden down from a local still
and the base if I just take it out now and
oversee it's covered in the fabric I really like this feature that it has a separate
face
and this is actually not cardboard as suggested on the pattern I've used the back of
a picture frame
so just a cheap picture frame which had a glass front the glass front has broken
so this this was just a way of using up the rest of the frame
with the edit has to saw that and spies
in terms of difficulty I thought this was a my simple make its as its rectangular
I thought Boucher with these the other design on this pattern but and this one lots
of straight lines you have to tell at the corner but that's as complicated as it
gets and this made it a nice easy made
and the instructions very clear as well and they have the seam allowance printed on the
patterns which was taking useful to me have matching its Styria pocket on both sides
there all say lots of markers and options on the pattern to ensure this and you
get the pocket lined up correctly and other aspects of the bag one thing I would
highlighted it doesn't remind you to trim the seam allowance on the corner so and oversee
this is a good idea to make sure that it's it neatly regarding the fit and
design of this item I haven't used it myself as is a gift that I've made
its intended use is to be an issue approach a bag it's a decent size of
not a similar missing croche about myself it's a little bit longer than this one
however this one's wider probably always twice the width of the one my own so
in terms of its capacity it's probably can hold a lot more
however you would have to angle longer this needles to fit them in
I really like the fact it's got exterior pocket I think these are great feature and
extra storage I think that you could add the pocket to the inside as well it
doesn't have advisor on that but it would be a very simple adjustment to make and
then you've got extra sections
and other key points to note is there's no fastening at the top so it's completely
open an exposed and it depends what you're using it force if you are using it
as a market back and you may not wish to have a field
and but if you are using it for traveling say and you may wish to add
as it or even ties just to secure it a bit better
another feature I wasn't too sure about was how they attach the wooden door handles in
the pattern it suggests to glue them and I'm not very keen on the idea of
adding loose I haven't done it myself which means they are moving around a bit and
not even showed the blue would work that well anyway
what I have done is I've added some hand-stitching
just to secure it right up to the doubt the original machine stitching is right down
here so I've just hand stitch I decide on the edge to ensure there is a
bit more secure however on the design I've got
the the bag I've got that similar and they have actually soon the ends so that
it can't come off the side and I think also the fabrics a bit they go
on each side so it's not even likely to pop up the other way
is to seven and a half hours to make that's not including the time it took
me to
sort out the wooden doubt and the base
it does include cutting time it probably took me half of that time half of the
seven a half hours to cuts all the different pieces and attach the interfacing the rest
of the time was for actually construction and sewing it up
I would make this again it's a nice simple make I like a day they would
be a few adjustments such as adding focus to the mining and perhaps adjusting Halys
the
wooden handles work portably shaving a bit of the length of the dales just the right
and then so the edges down to secure the handle so they don't keep moving about
and so I don't have to use blue-eyed also consider perhaps adding is it and for
some other fast things just to make it a bit more secure as well