say I'm reviewing the shorts pattern from the calls nine great looks one easy happen which
is number seven six seven five as always that you like this video would like see
more please don't forget to like and describe with you had already so other mentioned this
is the Mikhoels passed in it is number seven six five I've done variation jail no
not exactly because I have a Dondi trimming on the hem and the side I've made
in the fourteen which I think on this person
Oh no I think it does come in other sizes but essentially just cart around the
pattern because I'm the size fourteen was the largest one and
it's actually a medium on here okay so mediums at twelve or fourteen is a lot
the one I've done maybe once the fabric this is a run of public ahead of
my stash I'd originally made my partners in pajamas or without this and I thought it
might be nice to make matching half myself out of the different chooks have to get
it is a Corso and woven fabric it's quite a lightweight one just des standard underside
cotton fabric and I believe I originally got it from a fabric land one of their
stores in times of difficulty this is a nice super easy pattern so if you have
an ancient the board it's definitely a good one to start with it's not too difficult
to make you cut out a front and back peace and these stitched together like you
only wood for shorts or trousers and then you've got this nice elasticated voice is so
it's very easy to sort out the it there are different variations on the past and
so you can make it and little bit woke up place if you want what you
can do except what I've done it and just make a simple Harry shorts without any
panels that the side or adding a panel of him or adding any trimming or a
bit of course at the front you can just literally have been like this all they
say that I have added the ensign pockets because it's nice to have a kiss it
was also have a variation we add patch pockets to the front as well but I
thought these would be as frangible for me the clarity of instructions they are super simple
clear instructions I had no problem with it although I thought to be honest I didn't
realize that the elasticated channel originally was to separatists elastic so you actually got to travel
with of elastica and I remember how white the last to confirm its half an enjoyed
so one point to some cases
the first couple of times I made a I just used I wanted vitalistic and just
created one big channel which is obviously fine but I actually quite like it with the
two channels nothing had some extra little diesel but as I say I don't think it's
really the passionate folks it's quite clear and and it does really states that there are
two channels sexual said do so I'm not sure how I miss that but it's differently
of me in terms of design and fits as I mentioned it is quite a casual
least bit design which is why I like making this one with the Germans beg you
could definitely where it just as shorts and the seven I really like the fact that
it's going option for inosine pockets and they are nice really once on their of what's
behind us I accidentally stick the seems so that they were pointing backwards to start with
so that's the reason it's only the longer to take these I don't have to one
ticket I do like the fact that gives you a few different variations to create so
I think it would look nice with a contrast panel especially to use a couple of
playing fabrics or playing of other to the main pieces and then maybe a proper pass
and fabric down the side I've made the variation when you add the panel at the
bottom as well of the shorts which looks nice especially infuse that a stroke to that
broke and do it that strikes the other way for the lower section I haven't tried
it with the lace and that I'm not sure what there I will but I keep
coming back to this passen and so few next the time take him and either leader
to I went wrong but I made this particular pair it's definitely one who could make
it an afternoon and someone who's really quick and so will probably do it within an
hour's foulest but yeah I've managed to accidentally I think I was thinking normally if you
search the scenes together at the side you press them towards the back peace and because
I had added the ensign pockets you can't do that you need to push them towards
the front so I managed to press it that way I did the elasticated pacing which
then secured the pockets facing backwards but obviously no were really that and the little get
some ways that that way it's not very comfortable and so I had the topic there
elasticated channel at the two sides enough to then flip the pockets the right way but
it does mean that because I know nothing all of the elasticated channel because I didn't
so I get it does mean that it looks quite messy were of research and so
I'm probably if I pause I'm going to wear this as the dramas I would have
unpicked it all done much need to read in the past it and it would look
better but because I'm just wearing these you invented the speed Ahriman's I don't really mind
that it doesn't completely line up at the slides so to conclude if you can find
this after that somewhere I don't know somewhere online or in a shop to shop I
recommended it is a nice and Cixous white make which is the reason why I decided
to come back to this particular projects I thought yellow light simple in the project or
they did manage to go wrong on it that's it for this time thanks for watching