hello today I'm reviewing the gable top why Jennifer Lauren handmade
I've chosen the view on the pattern where there is a long sleep version where there's
a different colored cough at the end so you have two sections for the sleeve only
I've emitted the second half of the sleeve so that its now elbow-length as I've mentioned
before not like you know long sleeve talks so this has made it a length the
I prefer a lot more and the size I've made I believe it's the size twelve
however it has come out quite tight and I don't know whether it's the fabric or
I did trace it a while ago and maybe my weights fluctuated I'm not sure that
the fabric of chosen I actually got as a remnant from west pointer Exeter when they
had the missing and stitching hobby craft show so I'm not completely sure on the content
it isn't it fabric and it's a lovely strike fabric
looks like a single net jersey apart from that though I'm not completely sure on the
content of it but it is a really nice quality and it feels really nice against
your skin
in terms of difficulty for this pattern it is a really nice simple make as with
on it as brooks you have to be careful about you know making sure that you
don't stretch the fat break so I'm not completely sure if I have stretched trick or
not because it has turned out really long
even for me and I normally like a nice them the length of tops but I
haven't let them this pattern so I'm not sure if that fabrics just stretched a bit
with me or whether it's just this life anyway I did get a little bit confused
on the neck band section I did have a look at the
does a YouTube video by Jennifer Lauren which did help me clarify that I've actually done
the topstitching very close to the top edge but you actually went to do it lower
down just catching
the bottom point of
the raw edge on the underside
in hindsight it probably would have been better if I had dipped down to follow where
that's raw edge
lays on the inside
but as long as when I put it on I just make sure it's flat down
that seems fine in terms of the fear as I already mentioned two or three times
it does seem quite fitted I don't think it's necessarily meant to be like that but
perhaps when I cut it out I was so busy trying to make sure that my
stripes went across properly I may have accidentally stretched the fabric and that might be why
it's it it snugger than anticipated however I do really like having these elbow-length sleeves the
sleeves aren't site to actually it's just more the torso section but it might just be
that I'm so used to wearing loose pick garments that
any closefitting garments freak me out regarding the design I really like the slash next style
at the top
again I like the oboe length of the sleeves not that it's technically a view but
I've seen other people do it and which is what encouraged me to do it myself
I do like it being really long as I say I probably would have liked it
but Lisa so if I do again I probably will go a size up just so
it
feels a bit come fear for me regarding time taken that this was a really quick
make he could probably do it and half a day it did take me a bit
longer just because I was trying to make sure that my stripes
matched as best as they could down the side
top to visit you are going to get striping fabric the small of the stripes it
means the more stripes you've got to match so that did take quite a bit of
time but I'm really glad I took the time and have the patience to do that
because I'm really happy with the result a rule I am really happy with this because
it will pair nicely with the ivy pinnacle which I've already made I think it will
look really nice I'm underneath that and other pinafores that I've made as well I think
also it will be a nice and make
to wear on top of you know skinny jeans or likings as well though it's definitely
a lovely person I love the style but I definitely do things differently next time thank
for watching