hello today I'm reviewing the bow blows bitterly and the buttons which came in simply sewing
magazine it actually came over to Ishii's so you got the pattern pieces in the first
issue along with the first part of the instructions and then the following issue had the
second half of the instructions so for this make I made a size for and I
didn't make any other adjustments to it the fabric I chose to use for this project
is a lovely purple crepe from fabric land I'm assuming it sir polyester or polyester blend
and but I did to get it couplers ago so I can't completely remember
the pattern suggests to use this type of fabric or you know a great machine or
something that drapes really well so this is actually quite a thick great fabric and but
it still drapes nicely in terms of discorsi I found this person to be quite challenging
personally firstly because of the fabric is quite slippery I did end up looking at the
silly and the buttons website at how to manage slippery fabrics so I followed their guidance
by spraying up with starch spray to make it a bit stiffer
and I pinned it all before I cast this out just to make sure it didn't
move the tool
but I'm really glad I spent extra time on the cutting stage as I think it
helped with the construction later on other difficulties with this pattern was the construction of the
collar and bow it is fairly simple but I never attached a collar to an item
before I'm really happy with it but I did get a bit confused I actually started
this passen about fifteen months ago and then I got confused at the collar stage I'm
not sure if it was just I couldn't
understand the instructions very well at the time but anyway I picked it back up again
a couple of weeks ago and it just only seemed a lot clearer and I managed
to get past that mental block so I don't know it's probably just me or you
know sometimes when you read instructions and it doesn't make sense for ages or in a
speech someone else and then it makes more sense I'm not really sure but I did
find that aspect challenging just a bit attaching it to the oddest peace reget with regards
to clarity most of the instructions were really clear as with all Tilly in the buttons
passions it does for like someone holding your hand as you go through the process or
they like I say I obviously just got to a mental block with adding the color
I also struggled a bit with inserting the sleeves but I'm not sure if because I
cut out the past and pieces about fifteen months ago and cut to the
inserting sleeves last week I'm not sure if it's just that I didn't add all of
the notches on to the past in pieces because I got quite confused and because though
they put these lovely gathers
I'm at the top of the sleeves and I'm not sure if I just
didn't have enough markings or something went a bit wrong with how I traced the markings
from the pattern on to the fabric but anyway I got past that as well I'm
and I think it looks fine now with the face it is designed as a loose-fitting
blouse which again I've said before I quite like loose-fitting clothing so is perfect for my
style I really like the design of this blows which is what drew me to making
this particular about Blau's compared to other patterns I've seen or I've acquired in my stash
I really like the bow detail at the front and the necklines really nice as well
you get a lot of V-shaped necklines and patterns for by browsers but I really like
this and gentle curves that you get with this one
the pleats at the front there a couple on each and sighed at the front
I mean there's also quite a nice box plate at the back as well
I do like I'm this section at the top
the bit of and gathering at the sleeves as well as also really nice and it's
a half sleeves though it kind of cuts off by your elbow
and again I'm not a big fan of long sleeves so this is pretty much as
low as my sleeves tend to go the hems a lovely detail as well so you
can see and there's side splits as well
and the front him is shorter than the back him it's very difficult to work out
how much time I spent on this project because I did start it about fifteen months
ago and finished it recently it did take me quite a long time so I would
say it's is not a quick make is all I can really say on that overall
I'm really happy with this make and I'm really surprised because I want to make another
one even though it does take a lot of time and there are some bits where
you need to be really accurate I'm actually really happy with the design at the end
and the finish all of the seams of French scenes which I've never done before and
but I think it's gonna make the garment lost a lot longer thanks for watching