hello today I'm revealing the new Meghan Nilsson pattern the jar a jumper
I was fortunate enough to be able to pass and test this so I made it
a few months ago and so I'm excited to be able to finally share it
just a quick disclaimer at the beginning if I'm squinting at all it's just because I've
got I wrote us at the moment in order to treat I write us you have
to take a couple of different eyedrops one of which for the first week or so
dilating ones so it means that I've got one people that's way bigger than the other
I'm not sure if I can show it
basically it means that
one eye is getting loads of light
into it and the other one other people's really small when its bright but yet just
one of the joys of the chronic illness I have
so now I'm just going to go through the pass and details so this is the
jarra pattern by Megan Nelson I made you a which is a simple jumper format of
the main details is that it's got ribbing on the neck the cut and also the
hem
there are some other interesting versions that you can do with this pattern there's a little
time not you can have them besides there's a high-low him version which is curved and
they also now released a funnel neck version which was a suggestion as the passant Esther
but they didn't have the pieces for it so and to be honest if I did
make it again I'd be very tempted to make that version
and finally the size that I made was the size ten
for this pattern I used charity shops finds for the whole of it and the end
this light gray ribbing that I've got here
I actually got this
years ago I think it's been a my stash but so long I only paid something
like fifty be a pond for it I still got lades a bit left and yes
so
I was hoping that I would be able to use up some mustache for this project
and the main fabric this talk of gray I got this from a charity shop
way more recently essentially I got the pattern
to test and then
I found this fabric the following weekend in a nearby charity shop on the way home
from a park run so that was
really useful because I didn't have any fabric or enough fabric and my stash and what
was required I'd say it it's a bit like a punter Roma it is a bit
of a slightly different texture on the inside but I'm not sure it's really
I don't think it really counts as sweatshirt fabric is not as thick as that they
would say it's more like a medium wait plenty to be honest
in terms of difficulty it's a really nice simple make him it's a loose fit so
you don't really need to worry about fitting and it's what these lovely dropped shoulders so
you don't have to certain the sleeves
and even having wise because I've gone with the option with the band
it wasn't that difficult to attach I did try out the twin needle on this make
so that's why it's kind of stretched a little bit and but it was a nice
opportunity to try it with a stable fabric second see I've done it over on the
neck line as well as the hem and on the cuffs so but
they're to needle
it has the clerisy on the instructions but I can't say on the other views but
the view I've done I found it really simple and straightforward to go through I did
make a bit of an error on the neck band it turns out there is a
particular way to at the neck band I was kind of used to I think I
did another neckband quite soon before I made this one and on that one you essentially
you joined up the short and so you have a little
circle for your neck fans you folded it in half and then
you pinned the quarters to attach it whereas this one did actually have notches and there
is a particular way to attach it so on this pattern you can see that they've
actually put the same for the neck brand on the left-hand side so it's a new
showed the same where is done quite used to
you be able to put the neckband wherever you want so typically I put it at
the back and but on this occasion I did realize my error but that's more than
I kind of caught a bit carried away it does actually saying the instructions so as
long as you
don't do what I didn't just go Oh I know what I'm doing now and then
you should be able to notice that because otherwise it doesn't quite fit round properly so
yet essentially it was all clear it's just you need to read through in terms of
the fit I made a straight size ten I use their measurements as a guides and
it fits fine it's designed to be at least but jumper so the wasn't anything I
needed to change really
I also am a big fan of loose fit items so
yeah it's perfectly fine to me regarding the design it wasn't too sure when I first
and finish this item
I guess I don't wear an awful lot of jumpers so I wasn't too sure whether
I firstly needed it
and also I wasn't too sure about the him especially because I've done it in a
contrast fabric I was a bit worried would look a bit to school jumpers that makes
sense and however I am really happy with it it's definitely grown on me
and yeah I like having the cup sleeves
I think if I made another one I would go for the final neck option next
time just because I don't need tons of jumper's like this
and it just looks really studly having the funnel neck time taken I can't really remember
how long it took me but I'm pretty sure I got this done within a day
as I mentioned it's quite a simple make there are a few pieces to cut if
you do this view so you've got took up the sleeves
and you've got to cut the cuffs
you've got the
the hem
and then you've obviously got the main front and back pieces as well as the next
band so there's a few more pieces then maybe a simpler pattern might have you know
you could probably make a jumper out of four pieces with some
designs that
like I said and take too much longer to cut out and then after that you
know I chose quite a stable fabric so it didn't take too long to
to pinnate or and use the clothing but
also their Pattersons designed with
one sent me to see me I want so if you're using an overlocker it's you
you know you haven't got is bigger seam allowance as you normally would see you won't
have to why the catheter or you know stitch
with the sewing machine to start with a then overlock so
and that was quite a nice features you feel like you're using a bit less fabric
if you are going straight for the overlocker so to complete I'm really happy with this
make it was a great experience it's the first time I've ever passed untested so it
was definitely a nice one to start with as well because it it wasn't too complicated
I felt like I could achieve it in the time that they specified
and the only thing was it was really hot in the UK at the time so
and it's only really just dropped in temperature now here so I haven't been able to
wear it quite am a lot and you might notice I don't know if I've cropped
my feet out of the photos but I am wearing sandals or flipflops just because it
was so hot so I just quickly like threw on some jeggings and took some photos
and then I had to quickly get out of it and get into shorts and a
t-shirt because it was just so all the time but now it's a lot lot colder
so I think it will be getting a lot of use now
and you like I mentioned it's quite good value this person because you've got those different
variations so I think you've got about four different ones
one thing to note is that in the pattern testing stage they had a long in
a cropped version for few a
and now they've just kept the cropped version so I think
the cropped version is about ten centimeters shorter than the version I've made so if you
did want to make it as long as I have you would need to add that
extra ten or eleven centimeters whether they're lengthened and shortened liners their means the long version
that I made it kind of goes down so that's about my hip
so it goes down to their so I mean the cropped version if it's ten sensory
stuff it probably
would hit my hip a bit I quite like having a
long jumper but they will we see if you did want to adapt the published pattern
what we need to do is add that extra ten or eleven centimeters where it says
length and all shorten on both your front and back pieces
that's all I've really got to stay on it and so yet I'd recommend the pattern
it's good value for money to get these different versions and I'll see you soon for
another video thanks for watching