hello today I'm reviewing the simple t-shirt in the great British sewing be book so your
own wardrobe as always if you like this video would like to see more please don't
forget to like unsubscribe if you haven't already so to start off with the details of
this pattern so it's called the simple tee shirt in this book and of I mentioned
it's the same rowing wardrobe book so at this point I think less several great riches
Tsering be books I've got a few of them but not all of them and I
think this might be one of the earlier on one's may be the second or third
not entirely show
and so I made the spice fourteen and there aren't any variations on this pattern so
if you look at the book it doesn't give you any hacks or the ways to
do it so I've just done it exactly as they said the fabric of used is
a polyester crate so the main reason that I created this top is because it was
left over fabric previously I've made a dress I feel like it's a so house so
in a pattern that anyway I've made a red dress in this fabric and I had
just enough to make this pattern so I thought I'd give it a go however I
would not recommend you soon his fabric for this pattern so if you look at the
book it suggests using a thin drapey fabric possibly a silk blend or anyway something like
create dasheen
the problem with this is is quite a thick polyester crepe and although it drapes nicely
so it's not a complete disaster it is quite thick and I ran into a number
of issues because of that saying that being on to the difficulty of it it's quite
a simple make
but their hardest part of it is the fabric because you've got to choose a fabric
which drapes well
and of I mentioned I did choose the best one I still had the challenges
of the ideal of fabric so and its it was quite slippery so you've got to
be really careful when your casting out
but in terms of the pieces you need to cut out you only have a front
peace and the backpiece so it's not too much casting out you do need to make
your unbiased finding so on the bottom
for the him on the sleeves and on the neckline it's all bias finding and it
shows you how to create that from your fabric so the books quite good in terms
of instructions but
as I mentioned because it was quite a thick polyester crate it then meant it really
bulked up here and that's why if you look if you see this top closer you
can see that there's a bit of a rippled effect where I've really had to wrestle
with the fabric to get it to lay flattish but yes so it's not perfect so
it's quite simple in some ways because there aren't many seems to sew up so what
the to shoulder seams and you've got the side seams and its effectively grow on sleeves
however there are quite a lot of curves to contend with again you've got that slippery
fabric and then you've got to attach a whole lot of bias finding on curves so
it's got high-low him so there's quite a bit you need to work with so it's
it's a bit of a deceptive pattern in terms of difficulty in terms of clarity I
found the instructions pretty clear it has a separate section to give you a master class
on working with bias finding how to create your own
how you can finish off both the visible and concealed method so
it does show you all of that it doesn't go into a huge amount of detail
on how you can finish it off nicely at the start an end which I guess
may have helped obviously there are lots of useful tutorials online as well which you can
look at to help you out and but yet that's my main criticism I guess is
that they could have possibly added a bit more detail on their but apart from that
as I mentioned there's not a huge amount of construction minus the vice finding say
there weren't too many instructions but the illustrations looked pretty clear in terms of design and
fit if I put aside the fact that I choose the wrong of fabric for this
particular project I really like the design of this talk so I quite like the neckline
it fits quite comfortably
I'm a fan of grown sleeves and it's obviously a lot easier to make as I
didn't need to stick to on the set for of sleeps well there will be see
video of separate sleeves sometimes you can fit it slightly better to yourself and I think
if you have the right fabric it would look at bulky at the sides it would
drink lord better
I really like the high low hum and it's quite nicely curved
and it's quite a good one that I can use both the home the casual wear
so I can wear it with jeggings like a dinner but I could also where it
if I need to take it to work or I could if I needed to look
smart somewhere I can just dress it up or down appropriately the time taken I think
for a confidence I missed you could easily do this in a day
because I went horrendously wrong I had to unpick the bias finding and then reattach it
as best as I could so it didn't take me a couple of days to then
break to buy it
but it definitely is one that if you're quite confident and happy with by his finding
you could just get on with it and make it easily in the day so to
complete and I really like the design of this top I'd quite like to make it
again in another fabric a thin fabric one that still drapes nicely but
won't come across the same issues that I did previously
even with this talk to be honest I think maybe if I just bought some thin
silk bias finding rather than creating some from the actual fabric it might have settled a
bit better and but it's just one of those things and to be honest I made
this a while ago and I have worn it tuns even though it has a really
properly neckline so it hasn't put me off which makes me think that it probably is
worth making another one and that one will hopefully be even better so that set for
this time thanks for watching