today I'm doing a pattern review of the journey dress by to the in the buttons
so this dress actually comes out of the last book stretch by to the wounds and
it's got a lovely range of passen so this is one of a few I've done
out of that book
I've made of signs for and the to do the button sizing it has made straight
for the whole way throughout and the variation I've done it is like done in the
short words
in case you first leave the fabric I've chosen this was actually something already in my
stash so I bought this at least one year ago possibly to and this is from
my local habitat sherry so anyone who lives in Carmel will know will trigger so I
got this from trago which is my little have ashery and
yeah so it's it's an it fabric it's pretty stretching and it's quite thin but it
drapes really well as you can tell I'm and it's quite substantial you know it's not
see through its and I really like the pattern and it was I didn't need that
much anything so that was handy know but it's a nice bit of detail on them
okay so regarding the difficulty of the person I think this is probably a good person
for confident beginners who already had a little devil with the net fabric so I mean
even going through the stretch book would be an excellent way to introduce yourself to nets
and which is the whole point of the book and could you start off with the
baby skirt which you start with a much stable and onto solnet and then you progressed
to the person's like this and that saying that I think this dress looks more complicated
than it actually is so obviously the main detail is this twist at the top to
be honest I actually followed satisfactions tutorial when it's rather than following the instructions I did
read that people have had a bit of trouble following the pattern and in the actual
book I'm not sure if this the case I might try following the instructions next time
it is kind of symmetry them that I saw you know so factions made a number
of them now I just thought I'd go ahead and to give that version echo and
done yet it's worked fine I think it was just them the way so is faction
shows you how to do it theoretically should be able to stitch so you don't have
as much of a whole and next to the twist and yeah I'm happy with how
it's turned out anyway so perhaps I will to stay with them the satisfaction instructions on
marshal
yes so in the book it tells you how to draft your own fled sleeves so
their persons for a more fitted virgin you know that just goes around but I decided
I really liked the flare to design so you do a bit of I guess Haston
directing or passing cussing and and it's really simple you basically draw I think about three
lines and you I'm slash and spread the sleeve peace and to give it that volume
and I think I get my put between the lines how how much I spread it
I think it was about ten cents Meese's I could be wrong with I think I
did the same as the book and said they did because I like to be about
the Florent and that was in the photo for the book so yeah I'm but saying
that it's a nice little introduction to minute placing or hacking persons which I think works
really well there it was an extra step I found it really easy to do and
which is always I'm Andy so yeah that then set me back to watch tool
but if I did chanting to work out how I was short to cut the sleeves
and but you know I'm happy with that I guess I could have done it it
will draw a longer I don't know if maybe next time I'll experiments a bit more
see yeah I'd say the most challenging party as it would be the twist it's probably
the most intricate part the saying that is done not too bad it's quite challenging I
guess serving on the
neck winding
I'm and also you elastic in the waist band
I guess just the it comes back into shape and them
so would say that's probably one of the more challenging aspects of the pattern but apart
from that I'd say it I'd say it looks more calm created than it actually as
to sew up in terms of clarity I think like with all of the other to
lay the buttons pattens that I've completed that really and explain everything so well then they're
very good for unit learning how to sew
like I say I've heard that people had issues with the twist front and as I
just kind of go off and find separate instructions just because I think I watched the
tutorial before even and started making the past an ally just below the I'll go back
to that tutorial so I can't really vouch for the instructions they didn't look too bad
when I read them
but I think basically if you want to get
close to finish I'm up to the twist so less of a whole you might want
to look at I'm satisfactions tutorial tend to design and fit I really like the design
of this grass which is why I decided to make it and I like the fact
that there's some volume in the dress
so it really works for you know a knit fabric like this which will unhang mostly
emmies ego but more volume than some other addresses and the twist the told lovely and
looks more completed than it actually is and yeah I really like the floods sleeves I
think there are a really nice touch but then I think also there fitted sleeps low
and the pattern starts off as already nice as well for a and its dress pattern
as well and quite a simple one it's all so nice because it is a bit
more fitted Salem forget people who are a bit more shapely and show off their figure
a bit more
with regards to fit and I didn't actually adjust anything I think if I made it
again I might possibly make a slight adjustment because I've got a bit of this way
back it doesn't really show because the net the I'm not the neckline the waistline is
about higher than most persons although saying that I from like it is quite place to
my natural waistline but maybe that's how the I'm fabric his stretched since I'm not sure
and it also has a subtle debt time anyway so well there have God's way back
I'm not sure it's that obvious in this net fabbro and with this particular pattern design
saying that though I think next time I may possibly just take a bit out of
the center back so because there is this team around the waist I think what I
might do next time as with the back but is peace perhaps agreed it off of
it you know possibly and into something or even just a centimeter Ratu just so that
the skirt ends up being up a little bit higher and and you know some I
might feel a bit more comfortable with that but it's saying that I think I can
get away with not adjusting it on this occasion
it's time taken it's quite difficult me to work out how long it took I took
a bit of a break so I cut out
and maybe I traced out the pieces and then I took a break because I was
learning how to pass and cut
all the basics of passing costing and then when I realized I had a swayback her
and so do I change it do I not and so that kind of
put it on the back burner for a bit
and then I was also a bit put off by the fact that I did need
to and slash and spread the sleeves and which was really searing kiss it didn't take
that long until and it was really simple I think I just thought it was more
complicated than it was so
it would take longer than a really simple that person like you know the cocoa dressed
that's really quick and making yourself I Wendy wards Walkley dressed as a really quick make
of you if you want a really quick Walland introduction but yeah it's it's not it
doesn't take that long and considering all the additional features you've got with the struck evil
I'm really happy with this dress I think I'm going to get a lot of use
out that it's just really easy to sling on and go out the door I think
I'm gonna make a lot of variations as well so I think I really want to
try make and storage version I bought some red stripey approx so that will probably be
the next person I make and to get over what I'm really happy and I really
recommend the pattern thanks for watching