hello and welcome to my review of the fray address which is on the tailor's dummy
next to me and the prey address is a pattern from the simply sewing magazine and
it came out this year and it's a lovely pinnacle pattern
it's got some great details on it which are listed on the front cover and for
example it's got a bitted Buddhist and a line skirts patch pocket and topstitch detail
the fabric I've used for this is from fabrics the law I got it as a
knitting unstitching showed last September
and it's lovely
it's a lovely pattern however it does mean that it things to type so
over see if you did want to wear in the winter it might be worth adding
a slip or lining the skirt section
I think if you made it in a plain fabric it would be a much easier
make because I had this happened fabric I had to take into account pattern matching the
different sections such as the waist band to the bodiced and the waistband to the skirt
see if you did it in a plain fabric you wouldn't have to worry about that
apart from that I'd say it's a relatively simple make although there is a concessive which
you need to insert and there's also button-holes to create
bit of cards to the instructions I thought they were very clear and I did look
up
on a video to see how to insert the concealed ship just because I wanted to
see and someone put one in themselves however there are in instructions within the directions for
the pattern and they look like they were fine see what necessarily have to look up
or videos like I did
with the fit I didn't really adjust anything
the only adjustments I made worth of the straps I've put them closer to the concealed
step whereas in the pattern I think which was only a guide they suggested put it
nearer to the bodice front
I think also
I've made them a bit shorter so the button holds a further up the straps
the other alteration I made was I added an inch to the bottom of the skirt
as I like to wear longer dresses and skirts and I didn't do a bigger him
I really like the design of this pinafore I think the A-line skirt provides a really
flattering look and also it only takes to me to the fabric if it had a
circle skirts you consume a lot more fabric
I really like the fact it has patch pockets I'm not sure about patch pockets
for this patent fabric as the meant that I had more pattern-matching issues
it might have been better with insieme pockets but obviously if you made it in a
plain fabric it would be a lovely decorative feature
the other adjustment I did make was I got rid of the center seem on the
skirts as this would have meant that I'd had to
taken into account the pattern matching again
so I just took out the seam allowance in the center and cut it on the
fold
again if you made it in a plain fabric it would be another lovely decorative feature
this project took me around twelve hours to complete and that's including cutting out the fabric
at the beginning
which I received took a bit of time as I haven't done a lot of or
any had a matching before so I was being really careful to make sure that I
was cutting the pieces out accurately
overall I think this is a fantastic project I highly recommend the patterns I can't really
think of any false and in fact I want to make another one and I'm eyeing
up some red denen capric once I can afford it