hello today I'm during a pattern review of the kinda cardigan by Wendy ward so you
can buy this pattern either as a PDF of her website or like me can get
it as part of her book
so this is the book stirring with knitted fabrics so I got gifted this by my
partner and and it's a really nice book I've only made the kindergarten Albert the moment
but I hope to make some of the other patterns soon
the size I've made is the second to smallest one so I think there's about five
different sizes and because it's early spit design
the size ranges are quite broad and just simply because that is the least the card
again
but I used my measurements to work out which one to do I have that she
made two of the kinda cardigan I made one of my nose for Christmas and so
I don't have that one to show and but with that one I did
the
there's a version that comes to your hip where is on this one I've made the
the long like version which I was planned to make for myself
so with this version I infused a sort of mustard-yellow Ponti which I got from fabric
land I did actually make this a little while ago and to be honest about the
fabric hasn't lived up to the test of time
and because it's got quite openly and I hadn't washed it yet and I think it's
just you know a Braden with all the fabrics just general wear and tear on it
and so I'm quite disappointed about that and but saying that it's good to trial it
in a cheaper fabric so obviously if I then wanted to make
another version and I found a suitable fabric that I could do that I'm but saying
that apart from that it's only that I can notice that up close like Marie's one
of these machines that get us rid of the barbels as well although we see I'm
away your removing fibers of the original fabric doing that
so I've done the pockets which is an option something to note in the pattern is
that if you want to make after variation
with pockets you need to go to the end of the pattern instructions the with pockets
version is after the instructions ceiling to go over there followed a bit for adding the
pockets and then go back to the without pockets version to follow the rest of the
instructions
and I destroyed rhyolitic the both occasions I made it I almost ran to at them
I've just got to a point where I hang on a sec I probably need to
add the pockets by now and then I've noticed my error and gone back to write
to buy it and I think those times I hadn't gone far enough that I had
to unpick it but and just something to bear in mind if you won't see the
pockets and to be honest in the contents page it does highlight what page number to
go for the pockets and I just obviously got carried away or I flicked through to
the page the right on their but so the pocket better news duty to go ahead
about father in terms of difficulty it is a relatively simple make because it's the least
with design you don't need to worry about the fits and because it is done with
a knitted fabric I guess that is challenging it away but and you can make it
out of a very stable knit fabric soap for example I've used a point aroma
said the main challenge was the topstitching around the edge
although I didn't have too much trouble whether if I just used a straight stitch and
it does say that any instructions I was only the impression that Mike had to use
this exact because it was a knit fabric but it's so stable and it doesn't stretch
at all that you can just use a straight a fairly moist straight stitch
so there are quite a few pieces to the pattern as well seagull the two sleeves
to pockets if you decide to do the pockets and there's the
and across the front and the neck which is into sections
and you've got the option whether you add cups or not so I've added crafts on
this version
so a few pieces to play around with again because it's
it is quite a simple design apart from that and but yeah there is a bit
casting out to do
with regards to the time taken I think the first one I made in a weekend
and that's not including casting out time
and I was having a lot of trouble with the so machine I was using sick
as I was using my mom's zone machine which
was mine as but it does require oiling and cleaning up every now and then because
it is a fairly old machine
so I did have issues with attention on that and I kept having to try and
and rectify the issues
also I was trying to make it within that weekend because it was for Christmas gift
and I know wasn't coming back into the area before Christmas with this version I did
actually make it and a much more relaxed pace over a week so
why not to gauge how long it actually takes in primitively quicker the second time just
because I was familiar with the patterns world but the instructions are really close you've got
lovely illustrations in the book as well
I think if I made this person again I'd be tempted to try a drapier fabric
and just to see how that would turn out as well I think it would have
a different effect which would be interesting to
see
I'm really happy with this make I really like the design I like big baggy clothes
and that a company to wear and it an easy go over a lot of garments
I've got as you can tell I like yellow a lot so it goes with other
stuff in my wardrobe and I loved that gigantic square pockets on here which is very
handy seek and you know if you need to cook leap up out to the shops
you can
you can shops things in your pockets or shove your hands in this plenty of room
and is that something I have noticed with some patterns the pockets or releasable and might
be apple really big hands and there's no problem at all with this
that's all I've really got to say all this and if you did once the a
written version I'll have a link to my blog post of the pattern review down below
in the description
but for now thanks for watching