today I'm reviewing the baby skirts
I can sing the baby skirt is part of the stretch book by Tilly ones or
have passing companies to the in the buttons so this is the first pattern in the
book
I made a size for and as you can say I've done the pinnacle variation
so my fabric choice was guided by a mishap on a previous project I think I
mentioned it in my kindergarten an pattern review I accidentally cut into the wrong fabric when
I made my Nana kinda cardigan as Christmas I meant to use a very similar color
but it was a drapier fabric and I meant to use that feather cardigan rather than
this which is a much more stable of it liquor and Ponting's that brick so anyway
was really wanted to start because I had this picked on the address which needed I'm
you know more meters because I had about three meters of it I'm but I managed
to turn around because it turns out that I had enough fabric to make the pinnacle
version of the baby and which is the one I wanted to make out of the
variations I don't wear an awful of skin so I felt that I wouldn't make the
baby has an otherwise although saying that now I've made it I made into my mind
on last so yet this fabrics really nice is actually from
haberdashery and to Mitton equal Albers
anyway to divert of town of Devon in the UK and yeah it's the luckily fabric
it hasn't bottle too much a tool I made it a little while ago so I've
had a bit find stepped out and
I do need to I'm this I do apologize for the creases or any to steam
it that's likely and just because it is a bit Greece I probably chapped it someone
without my no
yes so really happy with the fabric choice it works really well with this person in
terms of difficulty it's the very first person in the stretch book for a good reason
because it's the easiest use of a stable fabric of quantity or very thick not to
stretching fabric and yeah there's I'm for panel save for the front one there are two
sighed once energy of the back panel and then you've got
the waist band that the front and back amber also I think you have only inside
as well
so there are many pieces of talk when because they're quite so because they are panel
was it means that you can get it out of a relatively small bit of fabric
so it's a really good espousing you know introduction into its annoyed because you know you
don't have to worry about you know and even if it does go wrong at least
you haven't used too much of our break-ins that makes sense and but it's a it's
it's a very nice pattern to start with the feel beginning with it
because I did the pentacle variation that was very simple as well
so what we do with them there are two extra pattern pieces so you've got to
go out with the protection and these stress
but they are on the pattern sheet so you don't need to drop out yourself they're
all they're ready to hand
and yeah the instructions very close so it's very easy to
make this variation the as all telling on the buttons patterns like it mentioned because of
me quite a few to the Boston patterns the ship again it's like someone holding a
hand through the process it's really nice introduction internet fabrics and and yeah the instructions are
really clear
regarding the designer fit as I mentioned I wasn't really interested in this part of my
first ickle the book I saw you not sure about dele passion and looks more of
the other ones such as you know it's the j-j dress
even like a docking top to bottom until I was more into that than making this
I am a pattern however I'm really glad I did really nice to wear and the
great thing is I can wear it both at home and that work I feel like
it's especially the fabric of used it is smart enough to wear to work it's a
it's a decent length I didn't actually like them up as well I'm which sometimes I
do like to add a bit of length yes it's a good length for me anyway
yeah the fabrics nice I'm a nice color that would be suitable to go to work
in and it's really company so although it looks nice and fetich because it's a pencil
skirt designed but it doesn't
you know it doesn't still uncomfortable to where it's very static easy as well so we
really good one especially in in the autumn winter to work to work yes know what
I really thought about making a pencil skirt before so it's quite nice because it's made
in the net fabric you have to worry too much about the fit so it's very
good to the introduction to ancile set for following eps the only thing I would say
this you do need to have a bear stretching of fabric and to make sure you
stitch the waistband well because the only real issue I have sometimes is that I'm getting
it over my hips
because will receive the waistband delight to fit on your waist and both my hips are
wider so I do sometimes feel a bit know that's about how will have done the
stitching like and put this on
because there isn't as it all the dome other fastening it is literally just as a
long pitiful the time taken it's a really nice book make you can definitely do it
in the day I'd say you might want to let it hang but we you see
the him I'm not sure whether I didn't or now but yeah it's it's a really
quick make if you want something and I stuffed the quick steps I make my doesn't
Michael into this one so in rule I really really like this make and it did
surprise me but that wasn't too sure I do like a pinafored so that's why I
went to the pinnacle variation however I wasn't sure whether I'd really
like this design because I only ever guess it it wore a line I've never really
ever won and so scarce before but yeah I really like the shape it is nice
as a bit more fitted in some of my other place it goes well with them
apparently able top by Jensen or and canned things and but it also goes well with
the Frankie teacher so I liked by a lock with my our version I get someone's
a little bit more casual I probably the way of to work them to be had
and that you have the frankly teacher it's really I deliver it if you want a
slightly at the neckline way that still my eye and and to be ready have got
a decent mount Vernon said quite a few different to ships would go with it that's
a really good wardrobe staple I can see myself wearing at Thomas and and yet really
recommended so yeah the only but I did struggle on was sorting out the
where the struck to go so
you can't have to try it on and despite where you not them I feel like
I did a junk that a compass on the skin feels the back I have used
to last them
they looked like a covered places but I had them basically on my bottom job so
I was using up and of already had ever the fight life-size to use and serially
and I've done it quite close to the side seam then you can see I think
originally I did put it right up never so I'd seen but adjustment to that wind
so you might need to play around with that overall I'm really happy with this make
it it was a lot of fun to make and as really surprised and delighted that
I
liked the and results if that makes sense because it was unusual because it's not my
my natural choice I'm in a person so yeah I'd really recommend it and it's such
a good beginning to fasten I can recommend it more ready for that that reason alone
and even if you know you're quite comfortable with it fabrics it's just I'm quite and
I simple make
and it's not too many pieces
yeah thanks for watching