hello today I'm going to do a pattern review on a bag passion for a change
if you like this video don't forget to like and subscribe for more video content like
this so this is back in question it is from the Debbie shore book brilliant bags
this is called the office bag and I've just done the pattern as it is in
the book they do have a couple of variations as one where you could put some
unbuckle straps on to make it look a bit more like unsexual I just decided to
follow the person other it was for the first attempt the measurements I've used as well
off from the pattern so obviously if you want to make a different size you could
but you just have to make sure you adjusted all the parts of pieces correctly this
is these are the measurements that they give in the book so in terms of the
fabric last I abused so the one on the outside you may have noticed it's from
my prayer pinnacle which I reviewed a number of years ganar and its Ridgeley from fabrics
below I got it from the missing and stitching show which was at west point and
exercise and I obviously perched it a few years ago if I mean for a plentiful
then and so this was just made up with the remnants from that it is a
needle called fabric which I was a little bit concerned about using just because I wasn't
sure to be strong enough that the hardwearing use I'd put it through however what I've
done is I've put into facing on it just to give it a bit more structure
and reinforcements that it fully I don't end up taking hold a strict in terms of
the mining I had to use a nice simple bold yellow cotton twill but was actually
saving this fabric to make an apron so it's not technically a moment however I'm really
hoping that Apache still got enough fabric to make the apron as well it is I
still want to make that but I just couldn't resist using it for this past and
just because I thought it complimented the main fabric so well I've also used a bit
of bias finding so you can see about this little like marine marina red color and
I just happened to have a remnant of it and it was the perfect amount to
be honest and I've also got if she could see in him I'm I needed a
longish since it and so fortunately I had on which match the boys finding which helps
this battle so has some other items in each pictures so you need
this twist look at the front to Fastnet August if you did survive to do a
different variation of it if you did want to sparkle to need binos incense and you
also need to the reins feel
show disrupts you also need a swivel class I think it's called see anyone on either
side there are Karakorum an extra chain but on this one I was just because I
found it at home but and most that you by would just be connected like that
another thing you do need for this pattern is fusible fleece it's just I'm this nice
then stuff so it is not too noticeable but it does just give your bag an
extra better structure so in times of difficulty it's quite a simple make to be honest
I think it looks more complicated than it actually is personally for me I found the
eyes finding wasn't too bad and it was quite a nice detail to add I'm really
pleased with the result of it she's also got some really good instructions on how to
attach the vice finding in the book there's a cotton what it's called it is the
design tool-kit at the start so and she's got all the main
the main skills you need to learn at the start of the book for reference just
because I guess they overlapped on him various patterns in the book so I found that
yeah for the bias finding they had a couple of
bits of advice which I haven't actually used the force and I found that it really
did improve the finish so I was really happy with that the main part I found
challenging was just stitching in the corners of the lining peace just because it's squat and
and she wore two factions
in that so it was a bit challenging stitching some of the corner bits apart from
that though I'd say that it is really straightforward because you doing a lot of straight
lines I say the only real curve is actually the spear when you were using the
bias finding the other thing I found difficult was in the instructions it said to
that you needed to stitch
your strap and then turning turn it right sides out but you've actually looked both the
lining piece on the exterior peace that interfacer it's really difficult to do that I think
it was also made worse because I'm not sure I use the correct seem lances which
I'll explain that a bit more detail while talking about clarity the clarity of the instructions
wasn't great in my personal viewpoint but it might be because I'm just not used to
Debbie shore passes this and I don't do in a wallful lot of
I also don't do an awful lot of bag or accessory patterns I don't be either
just make them at myself or just don't do any I couldn't see anywhere in the
book where it said what the seam lances were and this might be assumed knowledge they
we show does a lot of quoting based projects and I guess most quoting based pattens
would use a court trivalent steam once so it might be that you're just assumed to
you the call to minutes seem land I'm not sure or perhaps you're meant to you
actually at the seam allowance in which his I've done this completely wrong I think it's
a real shame it doesn't specify that obviously if someone else has the look and I
have noticed where the alliance's specified please let me know which page and which paragraph because
I've had a look and I just can't see it anywhere and I generally don't know
if I've just completely overlooked it and just can't sense because I wasn't sure on the
seam allowance I went with half an inch just because other parts of the pattern asked
for half an inch which isn't the best way to do it and as a result
it did mean that my strikes were narrow his initiative in which might be why it
was so hard to turn amount as a result has made me wonder within the whole
bags half an inch smaller than it should be or you know if I've missed out
the same lands entrance unicum significant you know significantly smaller than it should be but
the main frustrating part was I had to source new
gnudi rings and the little class unfortunately I did find something at home basically it's the
reason why I brought a match slider
still the hearing and told us and the sort of rusty run colored twist look at
the front I was originally gonna have it all in this I'm the color of the
twist lock that they would just wait too big for the bag of the and so
I had to go for something a bit smaller I don't think the strap actually looks
that bad this thing but obviously it was just a shame I can use the items
that had brought to go with it that was what a mistake actually on what pieces
you cut so they got the lining based on the lining sides incorrect so I don't
have it's just someone doesn't pass and test
and double check everything is correct or you know it's just an error that just what
overlooked but anyway so watch out for that urgently I could just come off some pieces
and because I used a solid color on the inside and I wasn't too worried by
which way the constant will and diagnosed were going but obviously if you did have a
directional print you but we have to recut out those pieces again which is a bit
of a waste of fabric the book is really good because it has got lots of
images in it but I did feel like at times it did need a bit more
information it kind of felt like it to jump between instructions bets and again it might
just be because I'm not yeast making bags but I do feel like if you are
a beginner you might struggle with us to little just to show see you you can
see this there are some lovely instructions here but yeah I just felt that it
in some places it needed just a little more beiden the other part I found quite
unclear was that it didn't explain that well how you attach the the lock on the
back to the main outer bag section and it might just be me misinterpreting it I'm
not sure but I felt the end of results so he personally was that it looks
quite nesty only inside out what this I'm line him and where the top to chickens
and then there's obviously the same where the flap attaches to the main peace but I
feel like it hasn't come out that brilliantly in terms of the design of the bag
I'm really pleased with the end results and I really like the design I'm a big
fan of shoulder bags anyway so that is the main pattern out of the book which
appealed to me which is why I've done it first really like how the struck is
attached separately and that it's fully adjustable I really like the lining of this bag and
this is probably the main appeal to me now I didn't understand how the lining worked
out before I made it now I've made it I really like how she's designed the
inside the fat so if you have a look here of left time what cried and
in here just was itching how much you can fit in here and all so there
are two open sections
and there is a zit compartment in the middle
and actually this part of the instructions I did find quite place to understand
and I just really like it so as you can see you could easily but some
April documentation in one of the open spaces of added to walk a few a five
no books in here and Yakut Melia room as you know snapped up
extra shopping bags and put my glasses and then I can get more secure items in
the dip section obviously you could add some more pockets or compartments if you wanted you
know to keep your house keys in or that anejo phone and but actually I found
that this works really well for me all their might add more sections if I made
another one depending on the purpose of the bag I say you feel like it's quite
secure political that's it section in the middle but you also this time turn class on
the front works really well time taken is quite a tricky one to answer the longest
section by far is cutting out all of the pieces and like a dress-making pattern you
need to create what the pieces yourself do either need to draw out all the different
side for rectangles you need or you need to and draw them straight onto your fabric
you obviously got to be really careful that you know you draw those out accurately as
it will impact the final design you also need to make sure that you cut out
your sections the right way up so if you've got a directional prince like the one
I've got in the front and because this needle board has a slight nap to it
you need to make sure that you've got the pieces the right way up and that
the Paston is running the right way I say making up the actual bag is really
quick your stitching lots of straight lines so that makes it really fast so that's pretty
much overall I'm really happy with it although I just have issues with the pattern and
the fact that they did
make a couple of errors in the pattern probably because they don't get anyone to pass
and test it that was a shame however I feel that is also really careful with
the person and keep this in mind it is a brilliant end result and I really
like how she was a blind this bag so
agree with does get a thumbs up from me so inspired by making this bag and
to that she makes a couple of accessories to go with it I made this water
bottle carrier and just because I will bring a bottle water out with me when I'm
on the go and obviously it didn't fit in the main bag and sometimes I don't
want to store it in my main bag anyway just thinking you know I'm accidentally leeks
and ruin something in my main back I also made a little zipped couch or pass
to go with it just because I have a few small items and work related that
I need to bring with me to work I was always trying to find them in
my old bag so I thought if I made a little bit and passed it would
mean that they were kept together so with these two items I just made up my
own pattern but it did record the progress on making them so I hope to share
with you how I made these two over the next ablute I hope you enjoyed the
video and thanks for watching