today I'm reviewing this butter it dressing gown passion if you like this video and would
like to see more please don't forget to like and subscribe if you haven't already does
I mentioned this is a buttering pattern it is pattern of five one eight nine and
the path of the pact collis's of a dressing gown so that's trusting and there's no
other variations of the dressing gown and and also John Michelle there's also a lady's best
that you can make though I have actually made the pajama shorts on this pattern which
come out really well but today I'm going to focus on the dressing gown in particular
they pass and I've got it from a charity shop so I've only got two sizes
I've got the large and extra village and I've made it in the large so I
kind of
added a bit of extra padding to my address was to try and and show you
what it looks like as I don't have the model here to hand as it is
a gift which I'm giving away shortly okay so maybe hand to the fabric that I've
used so as you can see I'm used this sort of polyester vocate on the advice
and on the lining I've used this Terry cloth fabric so one thing that I did
encounter because the teraflops more than net fabric and the outside of women fabric I did
think to bear that in mind as I stitched other issues that brocades quite slippery sini
to be extra careful and I needed to be careful and passed a matching the pocket
skills to me to make sure that it doesn't go out of alignment when you're cutting
it so I spent quite a lot of time just laying out the fabric for a
cause the pieces out I didn't need to worry as much with Terry cloth because there
was no pattern however the Terry cloth gave absolutely everywhere and still finding bits of red
flush and all sorts of places yes there's a big cleanup mission after use ahistorical inside
nicely I got both of these at fabric lines I actually got it at the source
free store which is now close but they do have other branches and an online shop
in times of difficulty I'd say this is for a co-operative beginner depending on the fabric
you use can make it easier or harder for you I think that I've chosen quite
challenging fabrics personally but you know some people might love these potential of that breaks as
I mentioned that the raids really slippery and you've got to be careful with that it's
also not that forgiving and you need to be carefully to maggots with the Terry clock
again because it's Strachey you've got the challenge and make it sure that doesn't stretch out
of shape and all so that the materials and sit nicely together at the end though
I'd say that's why I wouldn't say it's a complete beginner because I get a lot
of people were going to choose a tanning of outbreak of some sort if you use
a regular toweling fabric without stretch it might be a bit easier but it depends how
thick it is because then you might encounter issues with your sewing machine color saying that
there's no real challenging fastenings on here there's a bit at the top where there is
a sharp corner which is quite challenging but say that's the most difficult part minus adding
patch once you know you don't have to add any Zim's no buttonhooks of fastenings the
only fastening you put is this time at the front which is them separately and it's
very simple ingested the bits together and turn right side out and slip-stitch at the turtle
wise it's very simple it's just whatever you choose the your fabric thing that does my
luck topstitching which can be quite challenging when you're a beginner but if you choose quite
busy pattern on the outside or it might just drown in the telling fabric if you
did time in on the applied so it's not necessarily too much of a problem in
terms of clarity I found the instructions to be really clear it is a nice person
to follow the only bit I found confusing and I didn't really get was how to
do that him so I just did my own thing to be honest what I did
was I trends to him so that it was level then I pressed up the Hamelin's
pinned it in place slip-stitch it all together and then topstitch to the bottom I'm not
sure that's what the instructions say though I write it numerous times that I just could
have understand it it might be if I ever made again I realized what I did
room but yeah that was the only with that kind of confused me maybe want to
design and fence I love the design of this person I'm not sure how much I
can really say about the fifth I have tried it on so that it is a
little bit big for me and so I guess so many build to tell when the
recipient tried it on and took to all that them all they saying that I am
a bit concerned it might be a little bit big for them as well I really
like this design and the reason I to that out of the other dressing down patterns
that I have in my stash is because I like the fact that it does have
a separate lining and exterior this color particulars reeling icy get to show off that riverside
it's our lovely roomy pocket and you got these lovely big cuffs which again turned up
the you get to show up that Terry cloth again hearing thing I would say is
it doesn't have any taps for attaching the time however this is quite a personal preference
and waited position it and I was thinking of making the loops that the times but
I will rumblingly to see how it hangs on the person because I don't want to
position it in the wrong place but it would be good to have something there are
the ways that going to have to put this in the pocket of the dressing old
or put its one side every time they wear it both if you had some belt
loops of the sides it would just keep it in place when you do take it
off the time taken I did this gradually over a few weeks so it's again a
bit tricky to work out I spent quite a bit of time cutting it out because
of the challenging fabrics and that was probably the most time-consuming part that construction was I
probably spend about three days on you definitely with this up in a few days and
possibly quicker with an easier fabric so I brought its the big comes up from me
I really enjoyed making it and if I could find this person in my own size
I definitely give it a go it's really nice I just like the overall
design of it I think it looks quite comfy and I hope the last night make
it more will enjoy it that's it for this time thanks for watching