hello today I'm reviewing the Frankie t-shirt which comes with the Tilly and the buttons book
stretch I've decided to go for the short sleep variation and I have made a size
for so the fabric I've used is actually one that I wanted to use as part
of my twenty eighteen make mine it's this wonderful
spotty dog tea shutting fabric which I got from fabric land is been sitting in my
stash for well over a year if not longer
and it just seemed perfect for this I'm not sure how well it will last over
time but hopefully if I look take good care of it it will last a while
in terms of clarity for the project and as many people have said the Tilly in
the buttons patterns are wonderfully clear I didn't really have any issues that I can think
of with this pattern everything seemed to work seamlessly
even with the neck band I found I didn't have any trouble I didn't need to
adjust to which I was surprised with I don't know if it's just cause it's quite
a small neck opening but anyway it worked fine
regarding the fit I found that this person fits me really well I guess with a
stretch you don't have to worry as much with adjusting the pattern with regard to do
you know and but starts or whether it goes over your hips as it has a
bit of give and take on it anyway but in terms of some typical adjustments I
make is more about the lengths of the garment as I like to wear quite long
items or I've got quite a long torso but this is actually quite a long top
anyway so it might be if if you've got a short at all so you may
want to shorten it
moving on to the design I think this is a wonderful design I'm a big fan
of Ragland sleeves and from being Anita
and I really love this curved and it's quite hard to tell on this fabric because
it does drape quite well but I really like this curved him and also it dips
a bit at the back
while I was making it I was trying to double check that it definitely did dip
in the end I concluded that it must be lower at the bottom
really like the short sleeves as I've mentioned before I prefer wearing short sleeve to long
sleeve just could buy living quiet a humid area of the UK also the neckline it's
got I really like the shaping on it and it is quite high up but personally
I like that detail
for time taken this probably only took me about half a day and that's even including
tracing all the past and pieces I can't have decided one Sunday afternoon just to start
another project after I finished another one and I ended up finishing at the same day
so it is a really quick make especially if you've already traced out the pieces overall
I'm really happy with this make I'm really happy with the fabric choice along with the
pattern design I will definitely make another Frankie t-shirt probably more short-sleeved ones although there are
variations and to make obviously ones with longest leaves
but I know I've definitely got some other fabric which will work with this as well
and I'd highly recommend it if you do want to make a t-shirt