hello today I'm reviewing the Molly dress the Molly dress is part of the ebook my
capsule wardrobe which you can buy off the so over at website I got my version
from the
crofter noon magazine which was published by Molly makes for comic relief last year and which
was twenty seventeen so as you can see I've gone for the dress variation the person
has boast addressing the top version I've also decided to admit the sleeve pieces so you
can add some sleeves to make a longer length however I'm as I live in quite
a mild area I thought I'm not really gonna have much use to use the long
sleeves and I'll just get too hot and not wear it that much so I've decided
to go without as it already has this sloped and sleeve option as part of the
main pattern pieces
the size I've made is the size twelve as well
the fabric I've used is quite a thick net fabric I got it from a shop
I came across in Hong Kong
and
I've got to say it did wash up nicely and it has worked fine on here
it is quite a thick so you know it will be lovely for the winter or
they saying that I have Warner and it is you know I wore in may and
it was fine
difficulty and I didn't find this person too difficult as with all nuts you have to
be careful so I use things such as I'm walking fit to make sure that it
evenly distributed I did find actually that my overlocker struggled with it I tried to adjust
the differential seeds and try and
make sure that it did feed through the same by found that it was quite challenging
and I ended up taking a lot of it on the sewing machine before putting it
through the overlocker and it hasn't made too much of a difference on the side but
you can see where it has
Mr lined a bit it could just be my stitching most but I think that is
because it's such a thick fabric is quite hard to make sure it evenly fit fed
through the overlocker
apart and that those the difficulty I say it's really simple because there aren't
many and seems that you need to sew up the neckbands and could have posed a
bit of an issue I almost did the wrong seam allowance omitted one half centimeters but
it's actually once and to meter and seam allowance when you attaches
but I found that fine to attach I didn't even need to adjust it although there
is a note in the instruction saying that you may need to and cut it down
or extend it depending on your fabric in terms of the clarity of the instructions I
found that it was very straightforward and clear I can't think of any point in the
person where I wasn't sure what they were talking about so um yeah I have no
complaints
in terms of the fifth it's quite a casual dress anyway so
I didn't have any issues with this I quite like wearing a relax style and
I found that I haven't had any issues it it doesn't feel too tight anywhere
and it's meant to be quite least fitting anyway so and it comes up for me
I have read on other reviews that and some people have complained about how tight the
arms are but as I haven't actually added the sleep bear I can't really comment on
this but I'm a bit of sleeve I do have that comes off the main dress
I haven't got any problems with that in terms of the design I've already said that
I've decided and to not use the long sleeve variation although I think it would work
very well with this fabric
I like a casual dress so I'm very happy and with the design of this dress
time taken this didn't take much time of tools and like I say due to the
thickness of the fabric that was probably my main issue it probably took me just over
a day and that's because I decided to leave the garment to hang overnight and and
it did actually drop a bit so I'm glad I did
weight that like the time before having it
overall I'm really happy with this make I think I'm going to get a lot of
where out of it I'd quite like to make another one as well so that's always
a good sign