hello and stays with you I'm reviewing this share puzzle if you like this video and
would like to see more please don't think it's a like unsubscribe take the shot that
I've done here is the new look six to three to and I have done variation
sea or place to to variation see the variation to this person has to share variations
from for
a woman's fitted shirt and then its course the men's old unisex shirts of this well
as a and be
so that was the reason I thought it I thought it might be with will best
style if I did want to make my foreigner
someone else a shirt I'm in a blur of options having a couple of different styles
I decided to the women's Shepperton on this occasion district I'm doing it is part of
course locally I felt that heavenly added dots the and that bestaat and backlots would be
quite interesting for is only men's version there is a box place of the back which
overseas an interesting element of world and by the walnuts occasion holding a woman's version of
fat and like a bitter as I went along in the but since I want to
have someone like though that but in future and then I've also got a man's version
one hand so I cast out a sizable team I did to a slight adjustment which
I'll explain later it's a for the fabric that I've used here I'd use this lovely
cotton Copeland fabric is a bus of light prints in the at work alway and I
think it's still available on the neighbor Kroft website so I will link it possibly in
my blog post if you do want to look at that fabric and I've added some
contrast of but some yellow here for the sleeve Blackett's of lines bearcats with this yellow
cotton Copland underneath the color is this is because the bottom and
you can see I've also done the
condor stand
in that Ellie fabric as well so just a quick night on the fabric I've never
actually used any fabric from the pneumograph before and but yeah I really like this possible
I print it looked slightly differently image on the screen one I was looking at it
but actually it's probably an even better color in person then what I thought it was
going to look like so I'm actually things with that results it's really nice to work
clear it's easy to press and it looks like a silly to wash and I have
prewashed it so that came out fine it it easy to iron afterwards and dental the
steps I've been able to oppressor where required same with the yellow fabrics so the yellow
fabric I've got much more likely to me so there's a shopful to fabrics which I
didn't go into an awful up because I've got so much fabric of my sash I
don't need to shop for fabric waste of time I just shot my stash I did
want fabric that would complement this botfly print and I didn't have one in a similar
wait I'm so it was quite nice because I had the bus of like recovered by
that point so I could bring it with me and try and find a yellow that
went lightly with them I did try to see if I could match any of the
other colors because I do typically elevate twenty-one I thought maybe I should you know branch
out me again orange to go with us and but I can find an orange so
I had to get a bit slimily and I had to go with my duffel of
having yellow which to be bad it's my favorite color place that's court and yeah I've
used a yellow blossoms one here as well and which were actually from my such which
is quite happy good Buster's are really expensive
in certain shops so great thing is it's all made up cause of buttons and I
think the watchman instructions of the things of both fabrics so it should be fine to
wash and gave them in terms of difficulty I found this very challenging make this is
probably the most complications make that I've ever done there is none saying that is there
are just so many elements to it's so it's a nice fabric to work with its
very stable as its the cotton woven fabric as I mentioned it's it's easy to press
the dtr about that it's not slippery or anything like that but there's just so many
elements to it so I had to do and the bus stops which actually his in
a bit by being patch pockets yeah there are patch pockets as well there's also these
I'm dots on the back which you have to stitch up as the yoke the L
d sermon sleeve Puckett's which were interesting to do there are the cups and and then
call she got the collar with this them top section as well and you've got the
front band not to mention I think this person has eleven button holds and the little
buttons living with it so
that was probably the better almost
wrecked all the work and the intubations it turns out I thought I wasn't about the
button house but when you've got eleven ahead of you it is quite daunting so yeah
this was a really child you make for me and did pick it on purpose because
I was doing it in a class and I wanted to learn on these techniques so
I felt like a really grown making the shirts as it is such a technical peace
esthetical garment and then how many mix you've made so far it's probably not want to
start straight away but saying that I'm really pleased with that I did pick on purpose
as I mentioned because of all the different techniques in its it's also got a calves
and comes to him at the bottom which is another challenging element so you could of
course get many share patterns which are just flat at the bottom and that would be
a lot easier to him but saying that I really like that it don't have
kept him so there's a lot of work in it but obviously if that's what you
want initial
you're gonna read the more one one sits on in times of clerisy thing instructions I
did not find the instructions with listening look Patton that supporter follow there were definitely a
couple of points in particular with and fitting the sleeves into the armfuls which just kind
of left you to it so there is a bit of a seemed knowledge it didn't
tell you had to fit the sleeve and say you know when you put a couple
ease of stitching and to you then and draw it in to gather slightly but not
enough so that you are visible gathers it's just to ease this into the armhole it
didn't tell you how to do that at all so that's something to bear in mind
to you know to do belabouring research there and all they saying that it didn't I
don't think even said about using it and it just literally said stitch it into the
our home and she definitely needed to hear it in so and if you want aware
of easing these Steventon aho that could throw you off of it and on that step
but saying that's when I had to follow the instructions for the sleep bucket I've never
done one of these are my lungs and I was really don't it by it but
actually the instructions and we're fine I just took it really slow really concentrated on each
step take it easy and it came out perfect that time so yeah it is a
mixed bag on clarity release some of it was quite there some of it knots and
it does tell you while at the end of our Larry's fissioning the button-holes if you
need to but it doesn't actually give you any guidance or advice on that so I
mean I adjusted my discuss and from researching online you can get a bit of a
date if you don't have a at Boston I'm right and along your boss voice so
I thought I better adjust that and then I had the logistical high Maratha interment reposition
the rest evenly so yeah my effective that added of it guidance on how to position
your buttons or to make sure the fit was correct but again perhaps they're just assuming
that you already know that you're so I found it interesting that law because I was
looking at a couple of reference books at home when I was doing this to work
out the position of the Aston's as well and so I would have a little bit
ever read up if you do have the past and white doesn't give you much guidance
on the button and I definitely like quite a lot I think I licked to three
different reference works in the end and yeah it's really useful in the design and fit
I kind of gone through a lot of the divine features there was a mentioned the
color deports there's that for and top button
it on the potter there's the front bands you've got the cuffs and there are two
buttons on the cuffs which is less you got a specific sleep bucket here which is
really nice and because submit that person's you just fault is over to fold over twice
and which is nice as well but I quite like this I'm design feature there's a
couple piece on each the what the front boss starts a couple of patch pockets gusli
could just put one on if you wanted and and yeah you got the good
you've got the two back dots as well and discount time so I did choose it
because I wanted its many show features as possible and as a mentioned on my make
nine I would like to make a shirt a man's shirt by the end of the
yet so this has been amazing practice for that in terms of fit the you pass
in fits really well in the class I was recommended to take it in a vantage
on either side which I have done but I don't think it would necessarily looked at
that birds if I had slept the extra women or perhaps I didn't need to take
up white so much as an inch but in the next time if I did make
myself another one I probably only take carpet and either side to the in inches quite
a lot I also decided to use French themes on the inside and I'm not sure
if I follow with that next time time taken as a really difficult one because I've
been gradually doing it over the last three and a half months it definitely take me
well to cut out that take me about three and a half hours so there are
quite a few pieces to cut out but then I am quite slow a meticulous at
that stage so and to someone who's a bit more confident that could probably do it
in a much all the time this person is a really good slow burner that makes
them so you could really take it into small sections if you did just want to
focus on a bit one week for you know one evening and you can really break
it down into sections so I'm as I mentioned it's very typical so you can just
gonna go what going to do this particular you know but you I'm going to do
the sleep packet's over the next day getting there are so many different little elements to
it it's quite a nice and project to do over a period of time and so
without have taken quite a bit of time it's been really nice to just keep rolling
on with it sometimes it's really tempting to just really bash their project or really quickly
whereas this one I have just taken my time and go through out other thing to
mention that this actually is that the sleeve spent me fine and sometimes I find that
I'm buying stuff in a store that this leaves the too short for me so it
might be there when someone else the sleeves that you don't bet that's by an easy
adjustment that you can make so overall I think it's a really nice captain if you
want all of these shirt features in there and bogusly if you do want to pick
and choose there might be a simple one out there for you and it was assume
a bit of prior knowledge so I wouldn't say it's a complete beginners guide your very
best going for a different shirt person that is designed for beginners or perhaps again a
few other projects and do about beforehand I'm not sure if I'd make another one again
just because I don't like a awful locksets I don't do a job which requires me
to be really smart and formal and to be on it in this fabric I'm not
a shorter it would even class but as this muncher again I do wine or flow
shirts in my free time either I think quite many own one other end it's way
more casual than this and that been really fun to make it and I do think
I will wear this one unlike my special chess and yeah I'm quite looking forward to
making one possibly fulfilled in the near future he did ask me to make him one
about certain years ago so it's a long time having but I really did enjoying making
it and I do like in the techniques involved in it so I think I'll enjoy
making water someone up to that's it for this week thanks for watching