today I'm repairing the pink t-shirt by Wendy would if you hurt this video and time
and already please don't forget to light and subscribe so here is my finished peak t-shirt
it is in Wendy wards book about net fabric items which is a beginner's guide to
sewing with knitted fabrics so the variation I made was the plane t-shirt and I actually
did
Lincoln between the short and the long version not intentionally I just got really confused with
the lines to tricks and didn't realize that I traced the short length but actually ended
up adding five cents a piece of anyway so it is longer than the prop length
but it's not out long and the longing so I think the long ride from me
go a little with further down
I made the second slice from the left the actual bust measurement between thirty foreign three
course an inch to thirty six and a quarter of an inch or eighty-eight ninety two
centimeters so it's worth noting that I am at the top end of that measurement so
the fabric I've used I have used a remnant fabric which was in my stash I
bought it as a remnant after fabric shop I feel like it may have been the
fabric show in to button and Devon it's called movers I think anyway I think it's
a palm to room a fabric or Stephanie quite thick them if I have to tell
I'm which side is which it looks pretty much the same of both sides and it's
quite thick fur in it so and it was very stable to work with if you
did see my video last week you will see me construct in this top and a
glimpse of the final result and because I added this toucan embellishment making the two can
teach it is all my make known for twenty twenty it was that might make from
twenty nineteen but he didn't get round to it and essentially I got this out from
a cheap through the see that I got all over and only wore one it's just
because I thought it might make a nice embellishment and I'm pretty people the results but
argosy if you want to see how I added that to this teacher pattern you can
guarantee last week vidian in terms of difficulty this was a nice beginners makes though I
did that protects a difficult this was a shirt which was very complicated in the technical
whereas this one felt a lot easier obviously it is with the net fabric so you
have to be especially careful and it's very easy to stretch out in fabric Wendy ward
does guide you about how to use Nitz appropriately and gives you some nice tips and
tricks along the way so although it is made in a net fabric and that brings
its own challenges it's only a thing or two three four by pattern pieces the hardest
part is probably adding the neckbands and because even with the sleeves there a lot easier
to attach in my own opinion then I'm with boys and fabric in terms of clarity
I found Wendy was instructions were nice and clear she's got lovely illustrations and to demonstrate
every point it's whites noting that I did just make the basic teacher so there are
other variations where you can use remnants of a brick you need to add some little
patches onto the front of your talk so I don't know how clear that is from
a glance they look fine but obviously you might want to check that out and still
the most confusing part to me although it probably is making my fault was tracing out
because I did slip up on that all of the patterns or colocated on the sheets
but some spill over to another sheet so you you have to trace a part of
the past in peace and then you have to find the other section of it line
up and then trace the other half of it so it's not the easiest one to
set yourself up for you do need to add that bit of time and really concentrate
when you do create your passive pieces at the beginning which obviously I slipped up one
by cutting the room side to the design and fit as you see it it's quite
a least fit t-shirts I mentioned earlier that I'm at the top range of the bus
measurement for the size I made I think if it's really well actually on my shoulders
so I'm really happy with that I'm not sure if I've been at the lower end
of the sighting whether that I would have found this a bit too baggy but actually
this this amount of Luke's fittedness is painfully anyway to like I really like wearing at
least for its anyway honestly if you're not a fan of least for items it might
not be the person for you but saying that if you don't wear clothes like this
out and about it would make a lovely pajama top which I'm very tempted to do
I didn't actually realize how high up the neckline was and but yeah I'm really surprised
actually a consensus of my collarbone I think and starts another thing to my mind know
a lot of people don't like a I'm the neckline has as high as this obversely
you might be able to cut it down if you like I know there's another person
in the book which is for a tank top you might be able to use the
neckline and that I'm not sure the time taken this is a nice quick satisfy makes
so I think it probably only took me and our two hours talks to cut it
obviously tracing it was a whole other matter again didn't take actually that long is just
obviously and that's not the longest part for me was obviously adding this toucan embellishment just
because I was I'm quite sure what I was doing because it was an immigrant mattering
me however the actual pattern was really quick I made practically all of it in one
evening after work and then I left it a day to hang which I'm really glad
I did because I did have to adjust the handle that so I did leave Heming
to another night so basically I did in three sitting technically you could have done it
in half the day but I would recommend leaving your covering to had just in case
it it don't drop of it so I roll I would recommend this pattern I think
it's a really nice basic teach out which is essentially a hook point of it she
didn't have some different hacks and variations in the bucket well if you wanted to just
it up a bit or make it into a draft I just think it's a really
nice quick sissified make and yeah I think it was making a meeting phenomenal I do
you think it's nice to you in fellowship if you have gotten fabric like mine or
other way to use a nice patterned fabric or do the patchwork design that she suggested
in the book I think that would just them give it a bit more interest I
came that's it for this week thanks for watching