so today's video is a bit of a catcher for Eddie so I'm going to show
you a few things that I've made recently when I say so I'm gonna add some
photos because they there were all gets so I've give them away and I probably get
a hold on to
a few of them for a bit longer but I just go there's on I'm going
to pace them officer that they arrived from time okay so the first one I'm going
to show you is the mickles seven seven eight three which I acquired recently from a
local charity shop it was published in the sixties nineteen sixty-five is the copyright so with
this one I made a view see which is a top and shorts because I thought
I would be nice for my niece I'm and also it's in the correct size for
her I did manage I think my mom managed to measure how briefly when she last
visited her so I did double check fats and the measurements matched her so yeah it's
actually a really interesting make because although it looks really simple and to be that probably
didn't take that long it's just that I did short burst of sewing so it is
so promptly took me at least a week of not to and I think why after
I'd cut it out I didn't actually make it for a world because other stuff was
on anyway got my ground to it and made it and I was really happy with
the results and actually it's a really good skill but does though and there are some
more common things Sinead facing to the neckline and the armholes you also it was a
really good to practice compare and thus in incensing is it
because he had to add once the back an interesting point and it actually is that
it's said to put the zip on of the added the facing at the back I
don't know if it's because you're working with such small pieces
or not I'm because lonely one eye on a pattern you only have this if you
brought a basic at the back you'd put it on over the lip so you know
those it wouldn't brush against your skin lord beyond show even the on the inside so
yeah I'm not completely sure about that but I'm I can only assume it's because
it's easier if it's only outside to the perhaps because it was quite the school's it
that might be wife and yes there again I said it's really simple but actually on
the shore it's got a really nice detail I didn't know
you can see are trying for the line drawing on it but
basically there are two pleats of the front and see your plate on either side of
the front of the shorts and then it's a flat waist band that you attach on
the front of of the place and the back of the waistband had elastic in it
so I thought that was a really nice de sel I have no idea with the
the elastic is the right and lengths for my niece that's the only problem without having
your model there sophister at the time safe and that my bones up and with my
sister at the moment so clear it doesn't fit my home will be there to adjust
it so yeah that's the first one I was really happy with that make and he
had my first about strict with the other make I did recently and was from the
Edward menagerie back and which is why carry law to works in partnership with soft
so in this book I basically when my first news was born I made to be
I mean Emma the bunny I had so I thought of my second these
I would make the next person along the cat so I made Alexander the washing to
pants similar to you when I make the money passion in this book it's nice and
simple the great thing about making crucial toys is it just feels a bit safer
baby because you're not relying on your own sewing up skills if that makes sense so
I was happy that he had basically you stuffers you go along and so when it
starts I'm and then you decrease the net narrows so all the sewing up bits where
my part was the face and and attaching the ears of them's until
so it just feels a little bit thing for in that respect and also I'm you
use double nets but will I think it's a three millilitre hooks so it's it's quite
tight as well so there are gaps
and obviously I bought some actual toy stuffing CDs and sometimes if I'm just making a
mask all that for someone older I just used use a low hill I won't stop
it with that but I did by Bob was toy something for this one so yeah
it was a lovely simple make and the great thing about the Edwards of the naturae
book so this is the first one that there are a few more books out up
I'm hence the other books of a bit more domestic I think that's one dedicated the
dog breeds I'm
not sure about the others
yeah it's really handy actually there's lots of advice in the back of the book about
adding the face details how this can change the personality of the animal you're making I'm
know how to stuff the animal at the end I'm as you go along as well
so with with these stories you only actually put but something in the the base of
the limbs so where the little one wider this is and and that kind of adds
to its particular charming the books really good as long as you do read those other
pages to help you I'm you know so up and stuff it appropriately and it turns
out really well to see I was happy with that and properest the not as well
and the third
project I was going to mention it is that I made some Donald clothes in my
underneath she's I'm going to get a new goal for her birthday so I said star
suggested that I could make some dholes like to go with it so I'm really hoping
the it is again without having the actual dull better hand it is a bit of
a gamble but I just followed the guidance on the back of this person and to
whether it would fit the particular does so I've gone for the medium size the small
medium and large
and I got very chatty version again I think this is from a charity shop but
I don't know when I got it so I'll try and find a better picture from
online and it shows the front cover of it as a
so with this pattern again I'm it was quite nice skill-building pattern just because you
are making everything in miniature and so that was really nice it's also brilliant stash buster
because I managed to use some quite small bits of permanent fabrics I had a mustache
to make these three sets which I probably can have even made place for my based
out of them say I was really happy with that so and yet this is the
simplicity five by by for its a sewing patterns the dummy's but I don't know I
wouldn't say it's any easier to read them a regular commercial pattern it seemed pretty much
the same so I don't know why it's the dummy's unless it came with the setting
for domino call I'm not really sure and caught the history as that I think it's
a burly old pattern I'm not sure I'm not even sure I've got the copyright
owner the city thousand Andree it was really nice to make the to mention so the
main skill I practiced on this one it was pretty straightforward overall but you
use bias finding on the
neck opening which I it was a really nice way to practice doing that it was
a tricky round and the shoulder part
Oh yeah that's another point the M the shirt was redolent Rogaland shape as well which
was quite nice but yes he used vice finding him to
cover the rural edge on the next seem so when you you know you stitch it
down so all the bison thing is on the inside and which is a good skilled
practice because of the sea and there are a lot of I don't something just making
patterns which is authentic the other skill was on the panties on the legs you used
elastic to gather it
which is something I've never done on a person before so it was quite nice to
learn that
and also it's just nice to dote because it had a quarter of an inch same
valances so I am I used the overlooker for any scenes that want you know that
wasn't hemming and that so it meant that I didn't have to cut a funny fabric
and so yeah it's a very economical pattern andia it's just a good way to practice
and so me addressed making skills really so the final project that was going to mention
is that I made a penguin towerman Teucer them for my my younger nice
so I got this from the make for baby book which I've shown you my attempts
of a trace of the templates with the sketcher grasso this pattern I really loved their
which is why I decide to make it I had she had the pattern in a
magazine but I just couldn't find where the template page was so I could I had
to get the book out the library to get the templates to make the toy a
person and I think yes just like to the facial features on the town that the
pinguin on that part
so it's a really nice make it's pretty simple the instructions are straightforward the only Christmas
and that I would mention on this person is that you have to draw out the
the hood section
so they show you how to lay out on your towel and
they tell you that two of the edges or twenty line I think twenty-nine centimeters long
I don't think they told you how wide the other
the other
length of the triangle was but he didn't actually highlight that it was a right angle
between the two equal sites
I guess they might be assuming they're your use logic that it's going to get into
the corner of this where that of how that you're going to cut out but because
they had a lying on the patterns that it wasn't in the corner of the tower
which would be the most economic way to pass it perhaps they were thinking about the
nap I'm not sure but I just found that I'm through the off a bit because
they could adjust put a little right angle was fine in there just to clarify that
it definitely was
you know ninety degree angle between those two lengths the other thing was the because you
had to draw out circles for the eyes to for both pink women's and I think
it said of one centimeter circle and a two and a half a centimeter circle or
something similar like that's that and I think they could adjust of paper that it was
a one centimeter in diameter circle because I know it probably would have made it crazily
small if it was the circumference all that but it was just a little bit misleading
and I think that would out what I ended up doing because I couldn't find I'm
I can find my confess I used a one pound coin I found an old man
point that we haven't had taken to the bank and to get one of the new
talk cided ones and I used a two-pound point to make the bigger set of penguin
eyes so it works out okay in the end and they were probably the right size
I think the smaller eyes ended up being slightly bigger and the bigger eyes was likely
Saul over there were only you know a couple of in meters in it is that
and but yeah was really happy without ended up handsewing the bison with the bias finding
I machine says I'm the best slide on but then I had stitched the other side
over and just because I do have a vise finding foot but I find with town
and fabric it's the times to think just it just does incorporates that works so I
just thought it would have a nice to finish anyway by hands to show on that
okay so and that's it for now also oversee I'm if you are looking for only
six are interesting fastens to make for a baby or toppler these are some and I
probably recommend all of them to be honest they will fairly straightforward and there are some
good such basters there and yeah I really enjoyed making more actually and the other been
posted off and ready to be given as give thanks for watching