today I'm going to discuss my hundred-day project have a better reflect on how the hundred
days went possibly what I do differently next time and which ones were my favorites as
always if you like this video would like sea-wall please don't forget to like unsubscribe if
you haven't already I think it's quite important when you've done a project like this to
reflect on how it went to see what works what didn't what you might do to
for the next time and whether you would do us again for what went well I
think planning of preparation went fairly well I did well in the sense that I picked
my hundred animals before the project started so I had to think I drew up a
list and I wrote down on a sat for a piece of paper each animal that
I decided on wanted to pick a decent range so I didn't end up having my
all bird so I don't know a particular
type of animal the advantage of then putting on a piece of paper and putting them
in a box so that I then didn't know the order of these animals was also
important though because it added a bit of spontaneity to the project so although it was
nice knowing that I had a hundred animals by groups to complete projects I didn't have
to go each day Oh gosh which and am I going to do which one of
I already done I found it very useful to have that element of surprise as well
because it didn't make me curious the next day to go or I wonder which animal
I'm going to be searching today so that definitely help and I would recommend adding the
element this price of you can something I didn't do quite as well as was planning
the supplies but had no idea what type of colors I was going to get through
which in hindsight was a bit line because it was quite obvious that of the animals
were graze Brown's so really I should have preplanned the things colors I also almost ran
out of fabric it turned how I did actually have some more white caligo and research
that was the right wait I did end up ordering a couple of I'm different fabrics
online and I couldn't quite get the same type so it was really lucky I did
find smore my stash I'm but it would have helped if I just grated on my
stash from the start cast out all hundred squares I think the reason I didn't cut
out all the hundred twins was because I was worried that I might not finished project
so I don't want to cut how a hundred put that expectation for myself and the
pressure to succeed and then find out that a cart you know
seventy-odd squares that I never ended up using all the project to be very probably what
it used them to make cuts wouldn't have been a complete right off but anyway I
can affect that head and of calico even if it wasn't cut out obviously locked down
and the pandemic did make it a bit more challenging to replenish these supplies so I
was quite lucky because of the craft had to say or they keep having sold so
I did manage to replenish some of the columns but it was quite hard to select
them because sometimes they don't always look quite the same in person as they do own
mind so we did find side selected the future of the brown but actually I had
a huge gap still in my color palettes so to speak and which I probably wouldn't
have missed I want if I'd gone into a store likewise with the fabric I could
have just popped down into a local shop and chosen a meeting white beach calico but
I was really
I had no idea on the fabric Piper gone on what weights that was so even
the GSM that they shed on Patrick's online had no idea what wait the one I
had was perhaps I should have looked this up to see if I could have worked
out myself but I didn't do that they think I have learnt from this challenge I
have learned that if you shall walk every day and do something for his estimate of
time that you would have any get results I was slow it the start however I
was using lower quality threat and in the end I started using it less and less
and pretty crutch the latter ones aren't using the lower quality throughout it all I did
the odd time just because I didn't have the right color in the high quality shapes
but I tried to avoid it because I mean if if you've seen any of the
time lapses I just kept having to rethread it it would break it would you know
get tangled up and then I'd spent a lot of time rectifying that so and that's
something else that I don't use it levelly start up with better quality resources another point
of reflection is that some days are harder than others I did get into a routine
I found that the morning was best for me some days I just wasn't in the
mean to do in the morning in which he could be quickly scrambling around doing it
before beds which is fine you just have days like that and I had to learn
to accept that I found this a really useful exercise in learning to paste myself having
a chronic illness I really do need to learn that lesson I know that I can't
just spend a couple of days solid sewing a lot of the time because it just
exhausts me pretty much for the rest to the week having to fix myself and not
knowing which animals on the next day so I couldn't plan for it I found that
quite challenging at the start but I did get into a rhythm and I did have
to face that and accept it so in a way it worked really well that had
unresearched one of the animals and what's that template straight away it would be a lot
quicker if I Donald out but to be honest I didn't have time before the challenge
at the start of the project I found that I was a lot more hesitant I
was really worried about choosing wrong color not stitching the outline correctly I found that these
worries dissipated by the further down the line so probably the first two weeks were the
only couple of weeks where I was really like or grush is the story color for
this animal I'm not sure ocean I've added that shading by the time I got to
be and it is like yeah okay let's do that that really helped and it to
show that exposure to it there helps you overcome it boundary day product also showed me
that it is essentially a habit it's a great way to build a habit if you
do end up doing hundred-day project but to be honest I think this particular project wasn't
that sustainable for a long time habit I have taken a nice few days' rest since
finishing the hundred animal and I'm quite enjoying having that bit of respite however I really
do appreciate that it did make me set up my sewing machine every day which is
something I don't want me to do I do have periods of time when I don't
use my so machine at all sometimes are going months without doing three machine embroidery so
it was really nice to get back on board with that and get some results moving
forward I'm not really sure what goes to to squares I'm thinking either equipped for a
wall hanging probably a wall-hanging but I keep coming and iring about it I was considering
making individual cups or framing them but I mean framing them would take up a lot
more room than a wall hanging and would be a lot more expensive and for cards
I think some of the animals might not work as well for that and it also
seems a shame in a way to split up the set moving on to my favorite
one's got spinous I think my favorite one and I think it was from day to
is the evening I'm not sure what it is about it but I really like that
one the great second is the sea Tasso which was quite challenging one to make it
looks like from the college which will see shortly it was the longest make as am
I really enjoyed that one and I quite like the peacock as well actually so on
of names three for the favorite but I think the human was definitely my whole round
favorite out of the whole project which yet ironically was dating you can say that's a
wrap up from me but what I will do is leave you with the college of
all of the videos running at the same time so my partner was getting to a
bit of video-editing so he has kindly edited this for me and it just shows which
ones take the longest as well which is quite interesting thanks to everyone who has come
along for the right and thanks for watching