hello so today's video is a nice simple quick make which you can make for yourself
or as a gift for others the project today is a dishcloth recently my mom got
into making her own dishcloths to be a bit more sustainable also their great for using
up scraps of fabric if you have some left over from other projects this dish cloth
is simple to make it uses a bit of hessian or burlap for one side for
when you need a more abrasive surface for cleaning which won't damage any nonstick surfaces the
soft decide is simply cotton and can be made from any of your favorite remnants there's
also a bit of plain cotton in the middle to make them as sustainable as possible
you need to use a hundred percent natural fiber fabrics and thread this will ensure that
the dishcloth can buy the degrade here I have used a cotton fabric as I have
loads of remnants of this and the one I'm using in this video is a remnant
from making fill some pajamas but another natural fibers such as linen would work just as
well if you'd like to make a few dishcloths either for yourself or to give to
others I'd recommend making a cardboard template to make it easier to cut out a batch
particularly if you're using a rotary cutter so moving on to what you'll need you'll need
the following to make a nine centimeter by fourteen centimeters dishcloth but obviously you can make
it whatever size you'd like you need to cut out and eleven by sixteen sense me
so remnant of he-she and or ballot fabric for the non scratch scourer aside and eleven
by sixteen centimeter remnant of a hundred sent plain cotton or another natural fiber for the
middle of the cloth and finally an eleven by sixteen sent me to remnant of another
a hundred percent natural fiber fabric which you want to be on show on the outside
on the soft side of the dish class you'll also need a hundred sent cotton threads
so the first step is with your he-she and fabric in front of you place the
fabric you wish to have as the soft side of your dishcloth so the bit that
you want to show on the outside place this right side down onto the piece of
passion next place the plane piece of fabric you wish to use for the middle of
the dishcloth on top so that the main cotton peace is now sandwiched between the plain
cotton fabric and the hessian pin or peg the pieces together
leaving a large enough gap for turning right side out so all three layers together using
a one centimeter seam allowance I've given it a generous seam allowance of one centimeters considering
how small it is but the hessian phrase quite a bit and arguably is the most
challenging aspect of this project one thing I would recommend is to use a large enough
stitch length because I found that if I used a to Titus stitch length it would
all bunch up and crinkle a lot more clips the corners to reduce seem bulk and
then turn right side out ensuring the corners or pushed out as you'll notice from this
I probably should have left a slightly bigger gap to turn it right side out
once I turned it right side out I gave it oppressed with the iron as well
just to help for the next stage so the next step is to so two lines
of topstitching so the first line is sown close to the edge this will just mean
that you won't have to slip stitch the opening chats the second line of stitching is
parallel to this line and just a bit further ends for the one I'm doing here
I just used the edge of my press of it as a guide and use that
to sew a bit further and finally to keep the three layers secure in the middle
so a couple of lines of stitching in whatever pattern you like or you can do
what I've done in this video which is just do a random pattern it just stops
it crinkling up too much in the middle and yeah you can do whatever pattern you
like you could free machine I guess so there you have it a completed dish class
the great thing about this make is that you can get it done in a spare
half hour it's really handy its great because you can just recycle it when it's no
longer usable and their great gift that you could make up really quickly another great thing
about this project is that you don't need to worry too much about accuracy or what
it looks like because at the end of the day you're going to clean your dishes
with it or wipe down your worked up that's it for this time thanks for watching