hello in this video I will show you how Phil and I made a light up
bookmark for my niece the bookmark has a simple castle design on the spur of a
hill with the moon overhead the castle windows light up if you press down on the
moon so first I will show you the tools I used for this project I have
a print out of my bookmark design I ended up during a final version on the
computer but I began with a sketch and if you plan to do this yourself you
could certainly just create it from a drawing
next we have a lilypad a sewing prototype this has a battery section a button a
separate switch and three led lights we ended up using all three ladies the button and
the battery section we did not use the separate switch I have a small piece of
lutra door you can get different thicknesses of leech door but I went for the thick
of variety you can see that I have already traced the design phase next there is
a glow in the dark paint for the mean not essential but I thought it would
add a nice extra touch I've got to a range of paint brushes and fabric paints
for creating the footpath grass and sky a jar which I will fill with water to
clean my brushes when required a set of intense blocks which can be used on textiles
just because these provide a worried a variety of colors than the dialogue paints I've got
there there's a small piece of warding to pad out the inside of the bookmark a
piece of black felt for the back of the bookmark and the bobbin of conductive thread
silicon stitch a circuit as well as scissors and a needle
other items I used included the sewing machine the embroidery foot on the sewing machine because
I did some free machine and broidery for this and relevant sewing threads for the design
I used a snap faster as well from my set and a green one in this
case so that it matched the grass section as it was at the base of the
bookmark first I began painting the little I started to mix the dialogue paints to create
a shade for the footpath but ended up using the color blocks to create it with
these color blocks you can use waters to spread and blend the color
the great thing about them is that you can mix the different shapes and in the
set and it just adds a bit more texture and depth like I'm doing here for
the grass area again you can use some water to blend the shades together
I use the dialogue paint for the sky
you could of course lay of fabrics using a plicae for achieving the different elements of
the scenery if you don't have any lutra door fabric paints and but I just decide
to sit this way because I did have the tools
you could wait until the colors of dried before adding the clone the dark paint and
I probably would recommend doing that but I was quite eager to carry on so I
started adding the glow in the dark paint to the moon straight away and just that
it could all dry at the same time
once try I headed over to the sewing machine to machine and broader the castle silhouette
onto the lutra door
again this is another case where you could have plica the castle design but I went
for machine embroidery to ensure that there was a thick enough layer in place so that
the lead is only shone through the windows and the design
also due to the size it might be quite tricky to a plicae however you probably
could use something like black felt and just glue it in place
leech star is great for machine embroidery as it's such a stable material so if you
did want to go down the free machine embroidery roots I deadly recommend picking up some
later it off
I decided that the footpath moon and top of the held needed a bit more definition
so I just added a simple bit of stitching to add a bit more definition using
appropriate colors
next I had to work out where to place the battery section you can see on
my design that I've added a square for the battery location towards the bottom of the
bookmark I wanted to leave the boss image open at which would be sold by a
snap fastener in order to allow the coin battery to be changed
once I decided on the position I removed the warding from this section as well as
the section below so that the battery was accessible
I tried to the front peace down to its final size
and then worked out where the three led's and the buttons which would go
now here's failed to explain the circuit used for the bookmark thanks go this is a
simple parallel circuit the battery is Peredur three Elodie's to complete the circuit the button is
pushed when it's pressed down the Elodie's light up to create the circuit I stitched the
conductive thread to the positive section on the battery board and then did a simple running
stitch through the warding and black felt up to where the first lead would be situated
in the middle
I secured the plus section on the first led into place by stitching it down a
few times and then cussing the thread once knotted
I then went back to secure the battery side with the not
next I stitched the positive side of the next lead
for this one it needed to connect up to the original line of thread which connected
my original line of stitching that linked back to the battery positive light
you can see her that I secured it and then cut the thread but I could
have continued stitching to secure the third lead on the other side which would have saved
a bit of contractive threads as well as time
to ensure the allies have been connected correctly feel used a wire to test the circuit
to complete the other section as you can see by the sped up blinking lights this
test proof that the statue was fine however it's a good test to do at this
stage to save you time having to unpick your work at a later point if it's
not working correctly
to connect the top of the led's together you can see that I have done it
the way that I described earlier I've created a running stitch between the right and left
led's and then created a new line of running stitch from the center lead which I
secured to the other line of stitching to connect them together
the side of the led's are all negative connections on this end
next I worked out the location of the push button which would be placed under the
moon I continued that line of running stitch right up to one of the connectors on
the push button and knotted it led to secure the pushbutton doesn't have positive or negative
connections on either side so you can connect which I decide you want first
I then start a new piece of conducted thread secured it to the other connection on
the other side of the push button then I made a running stitch that went all
the way from this point right back down to one of the negative connections on the
battery section making sure that I avoided any of my earlier stitching to avoid short-circuiting the
circuits and ensuring that the stitching remained within the constraints of the bookmark size
once again I secured it with the not
I popped the front of the book mark over the top and tested the light layout
and that the pushbutton white
next I used my rotary caster's to trim down the warding and the felt backing
I pin three sections together ready for sewing
I took some fairly neutrals red and began to stitch around one side the top and
then the other side leaving the base of the bookmark paper
then did a further trim with some scissors to nice enough the bookmark at the fort
I tested it once more to check that and accidentally cut the circuit threads and then
moved on to securing the base
I used to snap fastener kiss but you could use a regular proper if preferred
the kick came with an all which is great for marking the two sides of the
fastener on both sides so that it matches up nicely
and there you have it one completed light up castle bookmark