in today's video I'm going to going through using a sketch agraffes so I haven't actually
used this properly before I think I got a couple of years ago after having a
chat with my dad I was talking about and how in some Patton books you don't
they don't give you the pattern pieces to scale and while it's okay to an extent
for certain project to know you might be able to use a scholar or photocopier I'm
at home or you might have someone locally I'm in your town that you can use
this isn't always the case so
anyway he mentioned this because he remembered it from when he was younger so
so at one of these and I thought that my next project would be the perfect
of gentes trys out I'm making the cozy bathtime penguin hair just make that people it
involves there are too many passing pieces
but in the back of the book you have to
enlarge by two hundred percent
and you've put the section at the top for the I'm eyes and there's an say
the beak and then you've got the bath time penguin toy so you've got the body
and then the detail on the front of the pink with so I'm gonna test out
using the sketch graph to enlarge this by so Indra percent so on the sketcher up
all of the instructions on the box on this one
so you can either in large reduce or reproduce the original size because the pattern pieces
were in the book and from the the diagram it looks like you need to have
it on a flat surface I have actually traced cells
the original design so I've got that to hand now the soul traceur onto an able
newspaper
the books to do that anymore and I've got a bit of a three paper to
trace that one too so I've added a bit a blu-tack just add an extra bit
do all the corners of
the April peace paper just so it won't leave just going to check the position so
too in large you have the original on the left-hand side and the peace Pieper you
want to copy onto on the right-hand side so
let's like it's on an angle but I don't know that matters
were ship might put further out just so
I'm not affected by I've got joined on the table here seston
so this is the actual skeptical
it's got
to movable parts to it
it's got this I'm it looks like a base I've added a bit about blu-tacked the
bottom so that I can use it in a moment to stick it to the table
there's also this point as well
at one end so you've got a point to this end this some point dozen
you can't remain that one
but you also have
these three white foam tears so they are emphasized so
so this one's a this one's being in this Wednesday and depending on whether your enlarging
reducing or reproducing you need to and put the
the spike all the and flat face into one of these so
okay this once called the pivot I think and it is called the guide pointer so
you'll end up guiding it along the lines on your original
if I put so many to put the pencil both in what
just going to grab a pencil you say I'm going to try out a mechanical pencil
so the person needs to go in
see
the tracing pointer goes into
the which is this middle one
and the pivot in a
so I'm just going to lose that over that and stick down
piece of paper
state now I need to put the pillar I might not left enough for that the
side
some just testing whether I can get this onto the peace paper
whether there's enough for room so it's going to go off
the peace paper about there so I don't know if I leave this
long slightly
can get it went to meet the table and
I'm gonna stick it down there for now and then I should be a plucky at
the two
shapes
on the left hand side and maybe the beach
and then I might need to reposition when this is so in order to enlarge what
you do it you hold on to the pencil
but you focus on where the point is moving and you guys it around your shape
run out of room
after reading
I didn't get this one of the
but what it's a real test on your coordination
okay so I admonished to trace out the
body part of the toy it's a bit shaky
I thought I get its kind of test in your coordination and spit with colossally you're
holding down the pencil but you're facing on points to be rather than see so a
little bit and challenging
are you
okay the second piece is not come out quite so well
actually the first attempt was better
and that little wobbly line really wasn't much to worry about after trying to do the
beak I didn't if it's just you far away from me here so
maybe if I
try again I might cut out the pieces so that I can get the peace paper
a bit closer that way it's not stretching out too far and self really my next
magic
get some scissors with more paper and write
some fairly happy his body peace second me that out when I cut out with that
of these
against the table wait for herbal
go so costing the template into smaller pieces has really helped so
we see having these two points closer together seem to in my experience anyway made it
a bit easier to you
okay so I'm going to carry on enlarging the other pieces for this template and so
my initial thought there's a bit of an adjustment period to using the sketch raft it
definitely is a useful tool but you have to have quite a study hand to
I guess a steady hand and the coordination to carefully go over your template line and
so that it doesn't end up to wobbly on the other one you were making did
I know how accurate it is I mean it looks barely actress
and as you can say on the other
when I did with the fake I got completely confused and I was quite wobbly going
up on the curved line but it might because I was stretching quite far the tunnel
by that point to definitely trying to keep it a bit plaisir and seemed to help
with I'm controlling it and for me anyway so yes why useful tool to basic enlarging
and producing I don't know what the you can
age the percentage I'm guessing it's just doubling it inside or I hope that this because
I need us two hundred percent
I don't know if you can move these
is a talk so are other little points on that so I don't know whether you
can make it you know
your fifty percent or anything like only like fifty percent
okay they returned starting by enlarging the map such as a weapon from an
and I'd say this is a much simpler
starting point antheia there really are obviously it's a lot greater just I'm going to a
vertical be a bit as scapegraces an option of you if you want to be around
with that I think that make Austin all four up so
you know and obviously then you don't have to go out and pay the cost for
it and it's just the goods you have in your own resources you know using some
you'll paper and pencil and but yeah I mean it seems right I think you'd get
better as a adat as you went along so
yeah that's pretty much my assessment of the skeptical and I receive you've had during experience
with the sketch grand were locked and Erica got any tips for advice on using hat
that our boys yeah all my steps are just try and cut out your
your original as smooth as possible so that you can then get your peace pick that
you're tracing on to them as face as possible and hear it just think it's a
matter of practice really funny
and that's the first today and fact for watching