this week I thought I'd do a bit of an update so what a few projects
on the go I've also completed quite a lot stuff that haven't yet I'm reviewed it
all showed it in the video so I'm gonna do better preview on those although I
will probably still do review one most of them if I haven't made them previously
also once to a couple projects that I'm currently working on and what I've got planned
for the future
supporting off with the makes that I haven't yet shown and I made quite a few
thing and since the start of the year I started off with making another so over
at Molly dress and in the chevron fabric
see
when I reviewed this person I said that I wouldn't do the long-sleeved version because and
because it's quite my old and home all that I wouldn't wear at that much by
have actually got against that and made a long sleep version
I think main because I wanted to see what
and the contrast would look like and however in this chevron for briquets not that obvious
and that you have got views out there do wonder whether I should have made a
cocoa dress instead potentially and but yeah no it's fine I didn't have trouble with the
sleeves which was a disclaimer but on my previous review but I'm you have no happy
with that
is also one on my make line so and that's one of the list
the next one I made was
frankly t-shirt and from Dylan the button stretch book so
I've already reviewed this well as well so probably won't show it and
I won't review it again and I've done it short sleeved as before I did adult
pattern top previously I've used this fabric before and to make and I think it's a
mega Nilsson briar tea
and I had quite a lot leftover so I have just enough to make this short
sleeve version and it goes really well under got quite a lot of the pinafores I
have so I'm really happy with this and I warn it late
now part of my motivation to make another Frankie t-shirt was that I wanted to make
the baby pinafore out of the stretch book as well which is another my property so
far the ship
so
I've actually got the Jennifer Lauren gable top under on the hangar at the moment
lock on it
only a little better price but this is
the pinafore
I decided to make this because I was going to make dress up this fabric and
then I accidentally caught my nans Christmas gift in this fabric instead of another quite similar
rebred fabric so I didn't have enough to make the dress anymore however I had
a sufficient amount left over to make this pitiful which is what I wanted to make
anyway and and I really like the shape of this pitiful it's really nice I wasn't
sure about making the baby Scott on its own whereas I think I probably will get
a lot more use out of that is a plentiful with a saying that allies made
it and I really do like the shapes it's a nice visit skirts it's this time
Peter
and it's just in that pays your hips that I find is the main struggle with
this and so could make sure that your and stitchings good carrying on with the stretch
book basically I'm going through it I made the
fray address so as soon as I saw this pattern I feel I've got this hour
fabric from fabric lands which I've had for a while I can't actually remember why was
it for it was for a project but I think I just decided to scrap that
I wanted to make the konak version of the progress and again really happy with how
it turned out
I haven't reviewed it yet but I plan to
I really like the konak vergine actually I might try one of the other versions I
am equally I just be happy to make another qanat version
I did find it it's quite short and me and there I guess normally I would
lengthen it a bit but I mean it's fine with type
this is
the from Wendy woods book
when they would book
the beginners guide to you saying with knitted fabric so and my part I got me
this book I got me the stretch book as well but all me and Wendy woods
book first I'm basically a year on I'm finally getting around to doing through these books
and as soon as I saw the kinda cardigan I wanted to make a yellow version
so and before I stopped buying fabric
in December I think this was my last fabric purchase I bought this yellow fabric for
the sole purpose of making the skin the cart kinda card again
and Prue can't see it that well here and as you might native I've just come
back from the gym so I don't really want to put it over and this top
yeah so I made one for my Nan so Christmas and which probably got a photo
that I can share when I do the review and I really liked the design I
was always tempted to go for and I did the midlength so it kind of ampoules
just blew hips so I was tempted to make that one after seeing it but my
gut reaction when I first saw the passing was to make the long version am and
I'm really peace but from that
I'm see I'm really happy with this make think I'll get quite a lot you said
it over spring when you get to that in between the weather when it sells to
warm up
and and their final make
I have made recently
is this the over it cold dress
and so I got this person I think the first time we did the PDF when
you get and the one included
I believe that when I acquired it and yes so um it's very straightforward person again
the whole do were a review later and do you find that it looks better if
you put a house on
and although
I have found that I do have a rubberless way back so that might be why
it
doesn't necessarily shake them well on me and particular at the back but
yeah so that's another make and using up a bit more by Sasha's again I've had
this fabric and there's quite a long time right do that
whistle-stop tour of the mix I've made recently and so I've got a few things in
progress as well I'm making the journey dress out the sketchbook the base like day working
my way through the persons in that book I've got
this fabric
it's this paper it to which I'm using for the journey dress
which again is for my stash
so I do have a stroke fabric I'd like to make it in as well but
I'd like to do a trial run on a
less completed fabric before I go for the stripes
what
I have had this I'm
unfinished for ages and in some also making the Bridgetown dress I think I saw to
that
nearly a year ago
being on my I'm dressed for most of the year
so
basically again I think I got this and fabric from a charity shop actually but it's
been my stash for a bit so essentially I have
some pretty much all but together I think I'm currently on I'm going down the bottom
packet and the neckline
but at the time
I found it didn't fit that right round my bust
all day when I tried it on near a Christmas it was fine so I don't
know whether it's just that and we had a really hot somewhere in the UK last
year so maybe it was to do that because I won't say necessarily my weight fluctuated
but
I think that there's not much of am given the person already
so I thought the heads up really just make sure you really good with your measurements
when you see the straps and and
their minds that there's lessees than other patterns see yeah I think it does fig and
now I'll probably have to try again before
and put it back on the same machine but um yeah I would like to get
this done since I think we're starting to get to the weather where it will be
really nice to wear be nice to where with the kids the card again so and
you see if I can get that done before Nimi thing
I'm also during a fruit slk
well I've got four to make some I've got a custom order on Etsy so and
anyone he doesn't know I have a small etsi shop so I just do a few
things I do I'm like string backs croche it once and knitted fruit socks and and
tote bags and I do have a bath but a bath hat PDF pattern as well
and yet so this is the first
this is the first
this is the first fruit sock them out of the former I'm making so making all
in this sort of royal blue color and essentially belted on the round
and its in rib stitch
some currently fixing on that so that I can get it sent out on times and
bow also and raced to the have actually been focusing on making this pattern which is
a copy cardigan this is from my month missing collections and so she made this when
she was younger and she's also making one of the name is actually in a I'm
in a blue
and so I got better copy he'd just because I find it easier to highlight the
hussam size of using I was a didn't like rolling the original I'm so it is
by and you know I can be a bit or careless with the unpotable Pete version
so on that I'm quite slow progress they have for me started in January and I've
listed the back
I'm also using black so it's quite challenging and when the light levels below and to
see it clearly
and at the moment
I am on one of the first side front so
this is it so far I am so there's an option to listen pockets at the
front and which of course I've added
always had it have a pocket it is one on each front side so what you
do is you let the
back part of the pocket one separate need also must think of so got one for
the other side
so I dismiss it these on different needles rather than I am putting them on to
you
I am a spare he do after without so that's how I started with the
pocket back so I've inserted one on this side
and as you can see scene and attach it and there is a pocket for
and in the end will do they'll pick up these stitches which are currently held by
this Bojan and I'll do a low and it's like a few years of rip stitch
and then that some sewn-on I decide to secure it
so I'm just currently going up and getting to the part where it's gonna get that
complicated and you have to start shaping firstly for the and sleeve but you've also got
to shape for the front opening as well and you should notice it's a Ragland
sleeved cardigan's it means the fits really nice at the end but it does mean that
you've got to be extra vigilant and happening concentration and so
I've already made one of these before it was the best ever of a garment that
made
nesting
that was quite a few years ago
but I've had this and wall for quite a long time I think it's just king
Cole haze and by there would be really nice to have a best tall black version
of the cards again am and that basically where the house come from so I'm hoping
I can get this done this year is part of my neckline
so yet on pause while I get the fruit socks done but I will be back
nesting it soon I've got a few plans on the gap the moment I
there a couple birthdays coming up in my family so I got really say much about
that in case they do watch but I need to fix on those next and as
I mentioned before I'm gonna make the journey dress
I'm gonna have to check about the fitting because I'm not now that I know what
but this way back I'm not sure whether you can make much of an adjustment for
that in it that broke so I'm going to do but research now before I cut
it out I started making a passion for an apron so I've got it all digitized
I just need to add some markings on to that and write out the instructions
so hopefully I'll get that done as well
so the reason I'm doing this video of this week is I'm also to mention that
I'm doing the hundred-day project so my challenge I think the hashtag is a hundred days
of developing content so
like a mentioned I've made fire few things but I haven't actually got around to showering
them so I'm fixing on developing content so it does also include I'm making item so
that can be I'm the achievement of the day but it's also with the driver of
consistently pasting videos and blocks
also I've been doing some passing casting so I've been going to a local workshop and
over the last few weeks which has been really interesting so just them learning a bit
more up fit which is why I now know that I will be this way back
and also here just looking at the fit in general also looking at how patterns are
constructed from the platform so been looking at that manipulation think we're going to look at
this set and arm homes and that so I am that's been taking up a bit
of my time also been looking at some of the old books that I required from
charity shops and second hand bookshop's and to reinforce what I've been learning their and yeah
so basically and I want to do past cutting for a while but being based in
call was a bit of a challenge though I think the closest place I could find
somewhere was plumber and before a local workshop became available
yeah the ways it's Bristol in London so am really fortunate that that did come up
when it did and it was one of my goals this year is that I would
like to be able to create Oakley at least one and design of my own
I'm which yeah I feel like I'm now gaining the knowledge to do that I mean
you can look just look at vexes well but I quite I find that going to
a class helps you and helps
helps get the full rolling so you're dedicating that specified amount of time you've got someone
there to ask questions
and yeah then you can kind of take it from this so I think after that
I'll have the motivation to carry on with it Oh another make that I'd like to
do soon so I'm also be doing for just making that but I'm I got a
I don't I'm happy that my mom got I think from a charity job so
it's just
so she got this before night five
and it's just my small um it's quite a small puffy
and I want to cut the less so I think basically my mum went I haven't
I haven't unrecovered it yet do you want to do it and keep it so I
probably get rid of this land around it I might just make a cover to go
over this rather than unpicking and getting rid of the original cover and as I didn't
know what it looks like on the inside it might be fine
but it might be worth keeping and the original cover
so for this
she would believe me this bit of course which and she will pick up from the
shed shop
for seventy five p for about three meters according to the tack
she also
this I'm very gently fabric which instantly I don't think you can see
not quite I'm basically she made a room divider I'm using this fabric which again is
from a charity shop so I was thinking to playing this around the edges of it
using that I like I'm using the cords like this better quartz being used currently
using this remnant from address that made last summer
tundras
and to go on the top section
and finally
I'm going to come out this cat from another remnant which this used to be a
casten that my mom had I'm hanging up to years ago one of the kids in
our house and and I've used most of the fabric to covered the privy that we
currently is in our lunch and which I'm keeping and by thought then it will tie
in nicely with the other professor hoping for that's gone top so not completely sure the
fabrics don't clash but hopefully and it will look fine
so I would like to get on with that
but I just have to see I'm the final thing to mention is I'm working with
the next sex solution so phoenix text Aleutians and currently host my website and they also
redesigned it and if you've seen it I am but also I am I've got a
sewing related app
idea which I was interested in pursuing so currently got them having look at how to
make for our reality and so actually if you have a look at that Instagram account
you'll see that that's the hundred day projects a thing it's a hundred Dave hundred days
of app development so there looking at my up but also
practicing by designing a couple of other apps at the same time and so if you
want to have a look at that I'm a link in the description below that's it
for now I'm Sophia hopefully I'll get on with reviewing some of these mix I'm in
a bit more detail and but until next time thank for watching