hello today I am going to show you how to sew your own wheat warmer so
I had some lovely leftover fleece from making one of my niece's a leopard print cape
last Christmas and I decided that it would be a great opportunity to make some lavender
wheat warmers for myself and others I find wheat warmers are really useful when you feel
a bit sorrel stiff and I had been using a very old shop-bought one for years
to manage my chronic health symptoms before getting around to making this one once you've made
it all you need to do is pop it in the Mike wave for about a
hundred twenty seconds or less if it's eight hundred what's or to a hundred seconds if
your microwave is more than that it can help to put a small mug filled with
water of the microwave at the same time just to provide a bit of moisture so
what you need I used a forty five by twenty nine centimeter piece of fleece so
that's roughly eighteen by eleven and a half inches to make this week warmer and that's
for a traditional next style one I used seven hundred fifty grams of dried wheat and
a couple of tablespoons of dried lavender in addition to the usual sewing items you will
need a funnel or something similar to fill the warmer with wheat in this case I
actually used a cardboard tube from a toilet roll because I can find a fun him
as well as using a bowl and scales to mix the dry ingredients so the first
step is to fold your fabric in half lengthways right sides together so that the long
ends meet with a one centimeter or half-inch seam allowance stitch around the three open sides
leaving a gap at one of the shore ends the turning right side out and stuffing
trim the corners slightly and turned right side out
with a few pins mark a line in the middle of the wheat warmer which is
parallel to the long side of the warmer you may find it's easier to take this
as well just because it can leave a bit warrior stitching stitch along the mark line
starting and ending about seven and a half centimeters or three inches from the short ends
of the warmer
next mix around seven hundred fifty grams of weight with two tablespoons of dried lavender in
a bowl
using a funnel in spoon or in my case the chief in a toilet rock gradually
filled the warmer with the mix
let's stitch the opening closed
and there you have it a completed wheat warmer so there's lots of variations you could
do you could bury the size and shape depending on how you wish to use the
warmer you might want to make a circular or thinner just remember that you'll need to
scale the amount of dry ingredients and you don't want to overstuff it these instructions include
a line of static in the middle for the length of the warmer but you could
leave this step out or otherwise you could go the other way and add a couple
more lines to help shape it further ultimately it just depends how you want to use
the wheat warmer and again you just need to make sure that you adjust the amount
of filling that you require that's it for this time thanks for watching