hello I'm walking back to my channel as always if you like this video and like
to see more please don't forget to like unsubscribe if you haven't already I just wanted
to do a quick shout at the least a from and so on to thank her
for featuring my channel in one of her recent videos and she featured this channel along
with I think it was about eleven others so if you do want to find some
more sewing video channels to watch a deckman having a look at that the day so
it's gonna be a bit of a strange one today I'm basically it's been quite a
long week which I can imagine I'm is the same for a lot of people at
the moment I started a new drop on Monday and things have progressed quite a lot
and in the UK our governments and finally filling in some measures to do with covert
nineteen their very fortunate that in my new role I can't work from him the locks
the past week has been trying to learn this of mining roll and the meanwhile everyone
gradually dropping off as they started to work remotely it was always going to be a
straight week started and you roll anyway but obviously and with what's going on at the
moment it meant that immediately I had to make preparations to be able to work remotely
and it's going to be interesting moving forward as I'm going to have to learn a
new role remotely but I mean at least I can work as a result I don't
get to get any sewing done during the week so I'm going to do a nice
quick suffering project from the make it simple book I am going for the quickest one
possible which is a do you know sleep mask so I
got my templates already to go
I've just found a scrap of fabric it literally at the scrap of fabric which I
must have brought in a random bag at some point
I've got and I spared for a lining
and I've got
a regular bit of elastic I don't have any nice judgy metallic elastic and such as
isn't the one in the book but I'm not too fast but that I just want
to make something which be nice quick and ossifying I've also got a bit of left
over warding here to use to
have some putting other mentioned in the birthday card again I thought would be interesting to
compare my speed of sewing with the ones in the book so with the best card
again I was quite a lot slower as this is a much quicker smoother project I
don't expect the difference to be quite as big but I'm still interested to find out
so operators very quick time lapse of me making the item and then I'm going to
me one to just give an outline of the other makes I plan to make from
this book because there are a few others I want to do again I'm going to
look at comparing how long it takes me to make it versus the book that is
if the variation I'm doing is one where the outlined a time when in the book
will know when set myself of a time scale and went to complete all the makes
from the book but it's just that forward-thinking things to look forward to well we spend
a lot more time I right I'm going to get on with this now it's so
let me see to get nearly twenty five past seven so just to give you a
quick I do it all the timing's
the I must so for casting climate has ten minutes and setting time for twenty five
minutes so theoretically I should be done by eight o'clock right if I do
okay so I've just cut out the pieces and that took me roughly five minutes so
it's looking good so far
okay so I'm gonna start going through the instructions
thank you so that take me just over half an hour to make so on here
I think it was twenty five in it gets too close by but it's so early
took me an extra five minutes and it I saved the time by causing out quicker
so it did only take me so to five in its in total which its great
and I think needs a slight depressed so just thought I do a quick review so
I'm obviously I am a fan of the cat shape so does say you could turn
this into a uniform Seamus' if you want to do which is another good Ida I
think I probably should use slightly think awarding this isn't very thick I don't think it'll
be a problem that society I think it was to be comfortable however it does seem
like there's a lot of wiggle room sitting a bit back you so and it looks
like you could put a thinker wanting in that if you want it it's one trying
to day I do need to give it a little bit of practice to make it
look a bit better but I think it
only moved at a smidgen tighter than the pattern said however thing that I do have
quite a large head so if you do have as many as you definitely need to
adjust the elastic but from that it's a nice quicks that's why make and it's something
that you could make for anyone reasonably easy and although obviously would be better if you
knew how think that headed for the elastic I think you could make different sizes are
you go to drink or enlarge this person template if you wanted to so you could
make one for a kid if you wanted to I'm sure that love a unicorn one
so a rule I'm glad I make this it's nice to have done something sewing related
after quite a long week so it's good to get back to the sewing machine and
with this I don't really have to think too much oversee the only bit I really
had to adapt was the elastic and that was pretty painless so the second part of
my video is just my plans for the rest of the make it simple book so
I have mentioned in I catch up previously but I wanted to make
the majority of these patterns or at least the variation of each pattern so
I've had to think since then about the materials that I want to use for this
and I just thought I share that with you now they're hopefully I'll be able to
make one in the next week so I can share a pattern review so the first
person in the book is the Scythia trousers and I quite like to make the dungaree
version I'm not sure if I want to make the trouser virgin of them or Nick
the shorts in the place it so I may possibly do that this is the fabric
I intend to use it looks like it is an old person you thought I'd use
this because it seems quite substantial but think it will still gather enough with the Thai
that's on the dungarees and making I won't look too much like a curtain and I
think what's going to help me decide whether to make the short all the trials of
version is probably how much of it I've got here so I'm thinking probably the shortest
Persian just out preference anyway because I think this fabric might look too much having too
much of the fabric if that makes sense to the shorts might be a bit less
in your facts anyway and also I think you look quite fun doing a short done
reversion so that for I find with that one I would love to you make this
rock from places as well however and
essentially want to switch around the dungarees and the place it so for the playsuit out
quite like to the trousers on this one day for this happen I would like to
use list fabric which is in my samish it's a nice it's got a bit great
I'm assuming
it's either a custom blend or its synthetic I feel like I got this from fabric
land but it's been my social world which is why I can't guarantee the fabric content
but anyway I think it will look quite nice as a longer playsuits so if I
do the trials of version and would probably be fairly suitable for work although saying suitable
for work and works going to be at home for quite well now so friendly what
will be comfortable to wear at him in the market home office now for the CQ
dressed I think I'm going to make the short keep version I mentioned many times on
this channel with that because I live in gone with quite mild so my preference is
short to see stuff in general though I'm saying that wearing a long-sleeved tops today a
pro manic in fact so I am shifted my preferences slightly but seeing as we are
moving towards the summer I think it would be nice to make the secret rest of
which has the sash and bent leaps so for this one I will make it out
of this fabric initially this is one that I got and I think it was a
charity shop fabric I did over the summer just a nice it was a really nice
soft material but I think it will be substantial enough we need to line up and
would be nice to wear and some mentioned I've already done the birth kind again you
can see my past a review of this on the channel I may possibly make a
second one and leads but it probably won't be for myself for the pajama lokshen I'm
going to go for the shorty pj's rather than the original Juno pajamas again just because
we get moving towards the summer and the gate and I really like the look of
the shorts so this actually I may possibly make the longer version it is I do
have this
chevron fabric which I think might be from Charlie better it's quite a nice design so
it will we make the t-shirt in a plain white to go with it because I
do have a little voice to my Satish and which is just from try to go
locally so I do think this would look quite nice in the actual Juno pajamas that
are longer seemed and longer like actual trousers or perhaps I will just go for the
t-shirts of and make the trouser to John's the back of an option so I've just
make the sleepers and finally for the honor pinafore I've got a couple of options to
this so I'm going to for the first time I'm going to make it out with
this their color felt like sooting proper it's quite substantial and to say definitely synthetic an
initial gut reaction it might be a blend but I think it's probably symplastic I just
thought this would be quite good because it was
probably hope the shape fairly well more I took it well anyway and I'm not sure
I'm gonna do that snap fasten it I might see if I can get some
more appropriate that passes for this I do have some at home but there are like
really bright multicolored ones where is this might benefit from having a you know being brought
a little something like that and I have a brand in there are not sure brown
might be suitable otherwise there are quite like to make it this initially I may then
make a more colorful one but I'd like to see what it looks like that and
again this is one from my summer charity shop pool so at least I haven't spent
too much on the fabric I can see how it goes and then if I really
like pattern I can make it in something else but again this would be quite a
good one for work and whenever
I go back to work the case that's my plans for the rest of the book
so I'm wondering between making the olive pinnacle or the done berries first not sure which
one I'm going to go for yet but I'm hoping to do that within the next
week I'm also happen to do a couple of quick tutorials and that you can make
out the remnants in your homework so quickly they'll be up soon as well I'm forging