hello today I'm going to show you how I made this graduation sloth so when I
say made a graduation slope I just mean I made the attire I did not make
the actual slope that was from Alster thank you
so basically I'm gonna show you a time lapse of me creating it and give about
or voice over to explain what I'm doing and when I'm going your long and then
after it I'll do a bit of a conclusion just to explain what would is an
differently next time anything that's not very clear on the time lapse so I made this
for my part when he graduated just over a year ago he got his doctorate in
philosophy
and the reason I haven't and put it up on the channel yet is just because
I hadn't got around to editing all of the footage and but I have now so
enjoy
hello its clothing from proper creations and I've just quickly set up the camera it is
my partner's finally left the flat
basically my granters finish a cage de his graduating in two weeks so it's very exciting
and but I do need to get his gift sorted out
so
basically he's starting a business and he's lacking from home is only there's really difficult for
me to make anything without him like to think especially but what I want to record
the progress as well so he'd finally gone out to see his business mentor which I
jumped to the opportunity to just quickly work the camaron and do the short introduction so
the plan is I'm going to make a graduation soft
anyone who knows my partner and I see is quite chilled-out relax and his Perry animal
probably is the slot so when it was father's day as I have these and sloth
poison and which were any of either it doesn't mean that it's good chilled dad on
the bottom
so I'm going to be I'm picking up
and going to rage my cupboard stash I don't really want to buy any new fabric
for this project firstly because I won't leave that much to make this lost its graduation
ropes but also where so inundated in the fabric because of all my boarding we don't
need anyone so I'm gonna see my to be a bit creative with by options but
I'm gonna try and replicate the once he's going to be wearing in two weeks
but yeah basically make a replica set for this loss so that's my brief introduction and
I'm going to try and record the abyss as I go along without him noticing what
I'm doing so if you might be in the background but hopefully he won't twig or
won't ask any questions and what I'm doing or I can pass the others another project
which we like
okay so here I've got the graduation stuff some red fabric some black fabric
some great red brick and some blue fabric so these are all the different colors that
appear on the PhD graduation ropes for the university's graduating from
so to begin with I started trying to unpick the chilled dad embroidery off the bottom
of the sloth on its feet this proved to be completely impossible so at this stage
I decided I needed to leave it for now but I did end up going back
and fixing that which I'll explain later on right so to start with I decided to
make the actual Gowon element as that would use the most fabric so here I am
just I'm squaring off a bit I folded it over at the top the side places
to the bottom
right so I just am cut a hole roughly in the middle from the neck you
see I'm just lining up and in the center front I've caught an opening
which fits the sloth which is great so then I tried to neaten up but
neckline a little bit better
after doing that I overlooked all the way around that front
so the empty front sides and the neck opening
and then after that I held it down just using a straight stitch on my machine
so their own just I'm cutting some snipped into the neckline so that when I
press it to make the him it was
fold over easier
there I am just sitting around that neckline with the sewing machine
and cotton of the loose ends
doing it with this loss and here I'm picking the side wits' end so as she
can see I needed to so down these sides seems
now I've used a bit of Taylor's chalk to
mark where I wanted to undo the stitching line
and then I use some dress-making pins to hold it in place and then I repeated
on the other side
I checked the measurement I did on on the first side so that it would match
up with the other side
case the next day overlocked those side seams
and then I put it back on the slope and for another hit
so I folded it the other way round and so the scenes on the inside now
I will say marked that him now because it was waiting long for the sloth and
so just shortened it there
I did ever look on and the website to see how low and academic robes are
meant to go and use that as a rough guide to the where to him Hemet
on the slope
see after I cut the him I overlooked the raw edge
and then I set about and Heming it on the machine once more with a straight
stitch
case at once all of that was set up I then put the ropes on once
again for a fit
and to check it still
went round okay and as you can see it it looks fine at the stage
a case in the next step was to work out how to do
the
hood that comes with
the gown
right so this is me trying to
draw I think I'm looking at my phone at an example of what
the hood looks like when it's not attached to the gown
some roughly sketching this out to work out how to construct it
now I'm just marking
what colors
which are colored fabrics I'm using so and saying the graves on the outside bit in
this instance and then I'd need to line it with red so
and yeah I'm just working out how big I want the pieces so
okay so I roughly tried to work out the measurements for the hoods and as you
can see I amended it but as I went along after that I drew it out
on a bit of I had a bit of tracing paper to spare so I used
that
then I cut this piece out
right so I got out to pieces in the gray
and as you can see here I'm cutting out to pieces in the red fabric as
well it was quite nice using this red fabric just because that's
similar to the fabric that they actually used for the hood
actually to be fair even the gray was quite similar sort of I did you call
at nylon
anyway this was more of like a satiny and failed to say after that I then
and moved over to the machine and started stitching
first the to gray pieces together
and then the to read pieces together
that I did I'm I trained these pieces cause they were so small used pinking cheers
and to help
and then I picked the gray and red pieces together so that I could sew them
in place
a case the once I attached the gray and red vibrate pieces together
then use the pinking shears and as these would be enclosed scenes anyway and I wanted
to reduce the bulk and then I turned it right side out so I left the
gap in the scene
said it could then
be pulled the right way round
as you can see nice and sickly
struggling to get at the right way round
turned out to be a really narrow opening
so in the end I got of the wife right way round and and then I
slip stitch the opening toast
I said to leave the other edge open just because it would not
come out the right way
unless had left the narrow opening
at the neck see I'm just joining together at the top
okay for them I tried it on to the sloth to check it would fit and
there we had it
slots now but
the next part was to add a band of blue so this just go on the
front edge so where the gown opens it it lays there and comes up
I think behind the
hut and then comes down the other side so for this I just wanted a straight
rectangular tube
and so that's what I'm doing here and cut out of peace and I'm just gonna
simply make the same at the sides so also up one top shore and the long
edge and then turn it around the other way and stitch the other side in place
in hindsight I think I did make it slightly shorter
and then it probably should have been and belly can see I prompted to leave it
right to the last minute so I didn't go back and make anyone
right so once I'd made that I
tested it out on the slope
also started spinning
the gown that on to the slope
because they don't want it to move
can also see I'm just I correct in what the back of the hook looks like
one side pinned all the pieces and place I started unstitching them down so that they
wouldn't move
and just doing some simple hand stitches they're trying to make them not to notice bull
I'm just so that it won't move out place too much just catching it where it
needs to not having any unnecessary stitching
decency I'm changing color where necessary
I will say using the bobbins that I've used in the same machine just because I
know
that I might as well use those up
as I'm not sure that I'll need them in the same machine again necessarily so I
might as well use the bit that I wound on to the bobbin rather than using
the actual school
you see I'm being very precarious with the pins by just leaving them on the surface
Oh no I've just tidied the month
right so next I needed to look at making the
main part of the hat so and you might be aware when you get your doctor
it you get to where the floppy hat
which I think was one of his main ambitions on getting a PhD which sounds very
cheeking so to make the circle I've used a circle cutter which I found in the
works
for anyone who's based in the UK and I think it's about three pounds it's really
useful you can either use the blade on the edge or you can use a pencil
to market so I use the pencil because I'm not I'm not sure how sharp the
leaders to be fair so anyway so I traced that one tracing paper and then cut
it out
so did that I did a gathering stitch so I just did a running stitch all
the way around the circumference of that circle
and then tested it on the slope
okay someone today to so that was one day's adventures on it as you can see
I'm wearing a different playsuit on this day although interestingly enough it's the exact same playsuit
which is the so over at poppy playsuit which I seem to where all the time
especially in videos right so I've just used the
better fabric I've got for the the puffy part of the hat to create the brim
I'm not really sure why I made a hole in the middle of this so as
you can see I'm I'm costing two layers for the brim and just to give it
a bit more integrity and structure
and yeah for some reason I cut the whole out in the middle even though with
hindsight I probably could have left it in because I was going to say the hat
on anyway
so yeah if you ever make this and perhaps leave the hole in the print because
it's not the dust
but obviously you know if you were trying to make one that you could detach I
guess you can keep it
with a to be fair I'm not sure how well it would stay on the slots
head anyway
right there any way
of stitched it together and then I turned it right side out and then pressed it
the right way and as you can see here I'm just stitching the
close to the folded edge on the machine I've done two rows of stitching one at
a slightly further and than the other and just again help with the
structure of that room to be honest I probably could use some interfacing to make it
and better
there as it was a small hat I didn't feel like it was necessarily for this
particular project so here I am struggling to
to make a realistic looking hat even though I could have left the hole in the
room so see I'm just stitching the
top of the hat to the brim
in this section and which was fairly fiddly that anyway so I managed to do that
and then I tried it on
once tried it on I put some pins and just to put it roughly in place
and then I had to get on with making the tassel so
you can see here I used the hangar to help me with this
so you twist it round tight
so that it makes a nice cord
then once I had it at the required length I put a not in it and
unwound the
on that I was using so I've just used some some
cheap my long on that I was already had a mustache and which looked roughly the
bright color
and then here so I then pinned it on the top and stitched it on and
which actually turned out to be the wrong thing to do for this it turns out
you're meant to have the tassel going round the room for the doctorate not going from
the top which is more undergraduate masters level and but I probably explain that more at
the end of the vitiate then I stitched it onto the slots heads
which is why I didn't need to add a home in the hat
and that's it pretty much done all ready to go for graduation
okay so I hope you enjoyed the time lapse of me making the graduation sloth so
I'm here with my partner will not the graduation solution
what did you people laugh
yes well I actually saw my original introduction that I choose a slots because felt very
it's very chilled-out and likes to take things slowly saying the slot seemed a very appropriate
so when there was one in stir the father's day I thought that's brilliant I can
adapt out for the graduation or
very much to the yeah well you didn't get to keep the actual
down and that not that you'd really where it not anywhere else but we can't all
the time I can't get to your office driven up
trench
might get more like an outcast
so were the things I do differently next time
and the main thing that's really bothering me is that I've done the castle room
it really annoys me but it obviously doesn't annoy me enough to actually go back and
amende it so
it is because
it's fine for a bore an Emmy like so an undergraduate or a master's because on
a mortarboard it comes from the center that one the floppy hat you had to feel
PhD yeah it's meant to go around this part way around and then it ties up
and then the tussle comes out from there she will come from the top middle I
see what you mean
I don't mind
every time I look at it though I do think it's wrong so maybe one day
I will
I will adjust to the saying that I've got quite a lot of them close that
I need to fix unaffectionate
separately I go around to her just look at every time go wrong
and another thing that might not be clear in the video I think resolute discover later
is that I could not get the machine embroidered
chilled-out of the feet so I had to think of another solution and this was casting
out some felt souls for the sloth so what I've done is I've used blanket stitch
to attach the felt on to and the feet and then I've used chainstitch to embroider
my father's title
on one foot and then I put the date that he graduated on the other foot
man who has been a hatchet only just been a month to month a year
if you say so
yeah I think that's pretty much effect
it was quite did actually on the day because you could tell people were looking at
the sloth and wondering why he could buy it
Mr
they had those like traditional bears that the multiple its progress they don't stop because most
people don't make
and don't go the way to a PhD and the crazy people what it was from
the four years who lived in one joint project for a title yeah so you can't
get many like souvenir beds which have the air floppy hat version so at least I'm
you know this was more accurate for the title he was caught racing with
much
else good point then only quite general aren't they just you know have the black robes
and the worst board and fear it's just a bit more of a personal touch so
yeah it's a good way to use up some scraps as well I didn't have to
buy anything extra for even the thought I had to hand and they yeah yeah you
can you got a musket
until
you're very chair
I get all that it for this time I hope you enjoyed there and we'll see
you soon