hello and welcome to the time lapse of me making the market tote from the cold
stitch and save easy range
is past a number and six for nine three and I'm making version a witch's the
top one on the envelope
for this tote version you need a base and doubts for the handles I made the
base from the back of a cheap picture frame which no longer had the glass although
the patterns suggest using the cardboard the dolls were cut to size as well
I use medium-weight caudex style fabrics are both the main and lining fabrics the main fabric
has foxes bowels and head trucks on and the lining is a colorful simple flower-shaped design
the pattern says that interfacing is an optional extra I decided to use some for this
project to give it more structure
right the speed of this video will go up to one thousand two hundred and fifteen
percent now I've had to speed it up so much because I've included all of this
make from cutting out the pieces from the pattern sheet to sewing it up on the
machine of use carbon paper to transfer the patterns onto the fabric as well which I'm
not used to say this took a while as well
April it took seven and a half hours in real time
to
the
ability
to produce