hello today I'm going to finally get on with my tooth and t-shirts if you like
this video and what might seem or please don't forget to like unsubscribe if you haven't
already a case so the story is that every so often I made up with one
my friends to and doesn't live in the UK any more but she comes back a
resultant and we meet at a midpoint between our two locations I think it was in
twenty eighteen it was a really hot summer her in the UK and yeah it's just
really hot and there was a lighter and we thought yeah let's go swimming we didn't
have any stof force women to we grabbed a swimsuit from from bark and a towel
which obviously isn't the best idea and not most the same boy there anyway we did
try the one in the fitting room with the idea that we can then keep these
items they will find in the changing room but augustly we need them again we got
into lido and it just we just found they weren't that appropriate yeah it's just the
way it's cut isn't great yeah it's not one that I've ever won again this women
my local pool the takes video I am going to just show you the part where
I attach this to a t-shirt so I'm going to make the teacher from scratch because
I don't have many plain tops anyway I've got a bit I had a bit of
remnant fabric which I could make a teacher from and I thought I had tried any
Paston as well that's mine using for this is from a beginner's guide to serving with
nutted fabrics by Wendy was so here is the book here and I'm going to make
their peak t-shirt from it so the Pete teacher is quite a nice simple belly I
rise have got neckband I'm doing the short flute version I've already cut it out in
advance so I'm to add the two can I will need to use the front peace
so here is my front passin peace already to go and here is the swimsuit so
as you can see it's a very jazzy sequence to come on that what I'm going
to do fast is I'm going to cut roughly round the two can because I figure
that I can and attach it to the front PSF or two layers some descended to
pinch the back layer away because I don't want to cut into that one yet
case the next I think I'm going to add some underwear to the back just because
I'm not sure how will it really works with net fabric and that's the main thing
was been put
to me making this talk but I think
if I can get it to roughly stick and it just attaches to start with hopefully
then it should be okay
okay so to attach the wonder where to the first slide I'm going to still put
it up to unassessed while setting to on my iron but hopefully that will work and
I'm also going to protect it with a bit of fabric over the top hopefully that
this will mean it white damage or burn the fabric
in case so it seems to have stuck for okay I think and but a rule
and quite surprised at how well it has stuck on I think now I'm going to
trim the edges so that there's not quite so much blew around it I guess I
could have just done actually I'm an oval shape on it so if you are doing
this yourself think about that before you cut it out but I think I'm just going
to have to live with that now and and do very close to stick back around
all the corners
okay so I've now got my two-gun
cut out readies I now need to position it which is probably
one of the trickier parts so actually it might help this side in the front and
the back pieces together first
just going to line up the
shoulder things with the dress on currently wearing
and I'm going to roughly work out where to place it
on my top so I guess to be a bit more accurate you could in the
sides of your top as well I'm just going to go to a mirror and in
that one
actually but or I do that I am going to remove the paper backing
okay so I've decided on the rough placement of the top so I just and went
in front of the mirror placed it roughly in them put a pen at the top
of the bottom just to get a rough idea reclines posset I'm now going to do
a couple of quick measurements actually just in case it is really going off to one
side or not
okay I'm pretty happy with my place for hunting I'm not going to adjust it at
all and I'm going to carefully press it on income going to do it from the
riverside they want a tarnish or melt the sequence
so see today of last Pinson which isn't ideal but I just don't want it to
me and I'm going to put my
bed protecting fabric over the top
little progress they actually it's not that bad at all
most of it has attached
okay so I was touched it you can't probably get away with doing a straight stitch
on this because this to can so
solid that I don't think the fabric would be able to stretch their anyway but I'm
not sure I want to risk it I might do a really small six background and
see what that looks like I've got a whole point nido in because then it favoured
I'm just gonna really take my time unless
it is also I don't know I could damage my Nina if I do hit the
sequence I'm not really liking the effect
this looks a bit very just
lock on you can which obviously it is that
I might win it with a straight stitch I'm gonna test out one a different section
of the bed
and I end up I'm thinking what I'd just done
if it works okay
okay so I'm much preparing how it's turning out with the straight stitch and to be
honest I think the stitches popping won't be in issues because of the old backing that
the chickens on
some now going to unpick the bit as exact I did do I'm gonna sit or
lie across and then I'm going to really carefully trim away the excess blue border
is another I've gone all the way around in the streets it I've had a bit
of a play around talking it but I don't think it's going to pop any of
the stitches so I'm really happy with that a lot easier to do street stesse also
way I'm going to trim it is using these duckbill scissors and go we were really
carefully that cuts
your threads all the fabrics so be caught a bit still a bit caught by the
wonder I get it it's feeling we really easily
most people have used underwear knows that
doesn't stay stuck forever
okay so I've got the
to come on the front of the t-shirts so I'm now going to get on and
stitch the rest of the top up I do think it is worth
attaching if you can your embellishment or if you do want to do something like just
on the front during it at the start when all your pieces are flat you could
do it all do you join the shoulder seams I guess that would be to inconvenient
for the just and makes it a lot easier for you to just go around the
shape okay so I just go I'll show you the final results so as you can
see it's attached to the t-shirts nicely I've left a really been boarded though I guess
of course you could make a wider border if you wanted I think it's what really
well with this particular pattern because it's a nice plain basic t-shirt and so adamantly recommend
passion for in banishing and making it a bit more individual but yeah I'm really happy
with it they just a recap on what worked best for me in this particular situation
although obviously it does depend on your embellishment because it was backed on a really solid
nonmoving backing it did mean that I could do a straight stitch all the way around
and it turned out to look the best obviously if you do have an embellishment that
stretches like the fight broke you may want to put it on a backing to make
it started I did find on this one that the sigs like stitch didn't look brilliant
and I really relieved that straight stitch work because I don't think I would have wanted
because the original swimsuit was in a fabric as well I was able to just leave
a raw edge around the in punishment which was really handy so I've caught really close
with those duckbill senses and I think it's come out really well I don't really need
to worry about it frame it is net fabrics tradition do right and finally I think
if you are positioning an embellishment on it off like this it is worth either pinning
attacking all of your things including the side seams because I think you'll just get them
much more accurate idea of the final possession of your evanishment on the front in case
it for this week thanks as always for watching next week I'll be back with a
pattern review or to speak t-shirt by Wendy woods so I'll see you then