hello today I'm going to talk to you about my telling of the buttons clear dress
so I decided to make this and as part of the great British throwing the challenge
hosted by satisfaction and I was hoping to make this anyway and but I was planning
to make it towards the end of the year that kind of love between Christmas and
new year
which I know sounds very organized that I've had that plan in place for so long
that anyway when I saw although I think one of the weeks challenges was to upcycle
and so I thought great let's get this project
brought forward and get it done for the serving a challenge
so I've made this out of two pounds that's why sixteen jeans
so what I'm going to do so they'll be dupont's to this video the first part
I'm just going to really briefly review the pattern because length of people make the clean
agraffes I'm and that's not much else really to say on that subject and just so
you asked me how I found the pattern and second I'm going to show you how
I managed to cut out the pieces from two pairs of jeans I'm just in case
someone intrusted I would say that the key address is a really good one and for
up so I think just because the pattern pieces a very simple and quite nice shapes
so
it's a good I'm jumping point to giving some confidence in upcycling and but yeah that's
why I chose of this beautiful person in particular the one too many fits and I
know it's nice like campus to be during mark on so calmly show you the thing
address on the moment I only have it on my dusable when I reviewed happen but
I was wearing it today anyway so I go I just review it while I'm iring
it so
okay so as you can see I'm late the new life version
which in the new x version it does have a I'm as less at the front
but I'm actually I saw people of illness I reversed and visit in the back so
we can see it but yes it's a Ansalon instead of a frontlet
and see it open with the hip pockets as well and about more to do with
the fact that I'm upcycle to from the genes so I've taken to it back pockets
from one of the sets jeans and stitch them where I would have
the patch book it's for the hip points
and I've come with I'm doing some visible topstitching cochair they can
just what sea
and I'm currently wearing it with the Frankie teacher from the stretch but also by Tilly
once so in times of difficulty it's a really simple make and because you're making it
out with a nice stable woven fabric and such in this case of denim I would
say the main challenge is that you got most players of then refugees to and make
it in down but if you choose a it's like you like to wait fabric might
it will be a lot easier and all the books say I do like this that
denim desiccant it's really substantial I find it doesn't really crease the awful lot and it
just some it's really nice to wear and so I would say about cycling if if
there's by a lot of the fabric that still I'm not bad quality or it is
a nice quality that unlike seems to up then I'd really recommend using that I'm just
because you might get a good value wife summat of it instead of spending lots of
money order I'm any piece of fabric
I forgot to mention as well at least I thought one of the stacks of jeans
I've made up front that and I'm Morrissey's the packaging his pockets from the other pair
of jeans because they look with different and but on the back of used that set
of
the other set of genes to cut some of the pieces will though we do combat
of the other and jeans on the I could work with them quite got it out
in one piece from the other surgency it's a really simple make I made a science
for which of what I normally do footing on the pasty and the Boston and of
patterns terms of other variations about from obviously adapting the fabric over the same all the
James I was using and to make some fit I didn't make any adjustments to the
pattern apart from and moving the front slit run to the back
I didn't actually lengthen it even watches and something I'm normally tempted to do on a
person time taken and to sew up the actual person it's a really quick make you
can definitely do in a day of keeping my to it
I say even a beginner it's just some of the topstitching that might be a bit
of an issue that you could see matching topstitching and not have to worry as much
you'd say the longest part for me was having to a pixie from the jeep the
original sense of jeans as you can imagine they're really well made so and equally see
how lucky they get
yes what than people who seems first which is the one reason why spend this project
of work as I had started to dismantle these genes and then it was taking so
long that I gave up probably took the most time on top sketching just because I
wanted it to look nice and even yes my overall impression of this person is I
definitely like this make it's interesting I was that you sure about the to address to
start with just because it is quite a basic passed in I wasn't sure if it
would be that plaster regal good of raw choir's
has no rectangular figure I'd say anyway so I was unsure but is going to extend
to wait that up and down look but I'm actually now made it I'm wearing it
it's so comfortable and I don't think it looks about that all so that the little
round really nice first pretty easy and I make and yes about that on the review
so next I'll show you how exactly I
made this primitive as a gene Celexa with pockets from one set of James
the front peace is made from
one set of genes as you can Texas in the same color and then the back
peace I have to stitch together from a few bits of the fabric left yeah so
it made the straps out of one of the
bricks I think it's been so I got the pockets from
as you can tell it like
and some facing probably worth noting that was also made from the other fabric I did
have to make out two pieces so
I added the seam allowance unstitch that together to in order to have enough fabric to
make a matching face in peace anyway that's not for me I'll show you the lips
now
okay sir and as you can see I've already unpicked the most of the scenes on
the two pairs of jeans so I'm just turning them I'm meeting them up a bit
here
right so this is when I was making the back pieces it didn't have enough
with on the trials of legs to fit the whole backpiece all as you can see
there so what I thought was all keep
and because this pair of jeans had a same the front I believe had an additional
seem so I thought I'd utilize that and
square them off and then add a bit of the other pair of pair of jeans
to make it a bit wider so you can see her I'm just I'm picking the
hem of the other
bit of the jeans
off again so I've taken off the top part which I might use in the future
project
yes this fiscals
guillotines really handy actually for doing life street cuts such as this so this day of
the pair of jeans so and you can see I'm just again I'm gonna square off
a bit so that I can join it
one to that the other perogies
just get rid of the cab edge
you can see the color difference where the scenes were as well
Yep and then that's all the other side as well
right so once I had them there you can see I'm now
making sure that they appear the same way
I'm also you know so
when it was stitched up it would it would mirror each side of the back pieces
so the right back peace would match up with the left back peace so here I
am just unpegging it together
so here I am just
check in my seen lance and I'm just stitching
these two pieces together
okay so that's one side done so I moved on to the other back he spied
there are essentially creative two additional seems
then I got my overlooker out and I believe have just overlocked on one side
and then so I
tried to mimic the other team in the genes so
menisci caught turns the seam allowance on the edge there I'm not going to a block
so then I could press him trimming the seam allowance of both
pieces on the bit that on the edge that I haven't overlocked so that then I
can press it and then do a bit of topstitching
and it looks like here I have used contrast thread to empty this top statue
looks like I'm just doing it some poor then
his family make sure the attention is correct on you topstitching and yet so we've done
to do one of the pieces now
I will see using
a walking but second see so I'm just to help it feed through a bit more
consistently than a regular but
then I moved on to the other side
he so with that done
I then decided and which parts I wanted to be at the center back
I lined the two layers up together so that they would look symmetrical
so that new seem I just created I ensured that they brace
on both pieces they laid on top of each other I'm here I'm just
I'm marking the notches I think on the other side or me just making it a
bit clearer so that you can see
okay Salena was trying my best to match up with the grain on the fabric
then I started off with a rotary castor but actually it was quite challenging because
you so you can see here that I then decided to pin it because
the jeans were made of such a thick denim it was moving around as I tried
to use either the rotary cutter all this is is so I have decided it was
best to pin
and then I used my dress-making scissors to cut around it
is the reason I
cut out the back peace first was just because I was making it out of the
offcuts the other so I'd already had a look at the pattern and
the
person dunes I had and figured that I could make I think it was out of
the back pieces of one pair of jeans I could I knew that I could cut
out the front pieces of the clear out of it so I wasn't concerned about that
I was just concerned about and the back pieces which as you can see
cut out them so I just wanted to be sure about those pieces out before I
cut any of the smaller bits because worse comes to work especially the and facing I
could have done in a different fabric okay so in sequel I'm pretty sure it's the
back piece of two of the genes so when I got to this stage I then
realized that actually it was only just enough for him
and I've got to be honest I'm not completely sure that I did cut it exactly
on the grain line
because it was such a narrow margin to get it to fit on that peace because
of the shape of the front of the clear
and as you can see her I'm deliberating and awful lot trying to work out how
to
fix it
to the fabric
anyway looks like I came to a decision like I say I think it is slightly
off the green line but because it's not just early fabric it hasn't made it hasn't
made too much of a different but
I mean if I did again I'd prepay a bit more attention to this
and this point or just reduced the seam allowance on one side because I could have
gone off slightly because you do get a one and half son tweeter
and seam allowance on this pattern
I wish I could cut as quick as this time LaHaye so here and I think
the bottom layer I knew wasn't quite as wide as the top but if that broke
so you can see that I just used the tailor's talk to line up exactly where
the stitch line should be on that piece so I'd follow that when I am stitched
out together and then I am marked where the pockets roughly needed to be although like
I say I was using the back pocket so I didn't need to cut out those
pieces
okay so with the remaining bit of the genes so I'm cutting out the final pieces
so these of the straps on the clear
the bits I think I worked out that this was the best place and the best
placement
utilize the fabric I had so
I think I could only get those
the curved parts I had to do it at the top of the end is it
from at face value it looks like I'm cutting out really uneconomically and if you can
see the piece of the talks that I've just finished cutting up I've added a seam
allowance and that cause you do cut it on the fold for this passion but because
I couldn't caught it on the fold I didn't have a wide enough peace I was
going to stitch it together and create a seem to make the full peace
again it looks like I did it with the other curved peace as well
as at the back facing it looks like
you so I've added that
seamounts there as well so the next step would be to stitch those
there I am off on the machine and setting it again
and in the correct color to friends
I'm assuming I readjusted the tension from after the topstitching but I don't know the area
like the effect because you can see where the pockets have been on those pieces
okay looks like here I'm made about to add some notchers
Yep there I think I'll just realized that there are more notches on the
the facings than I actually had on that piece so I'm just correcting at that okay
and then here I'm just overlooking those and raw edges from the two seems that I
created on the facing
I hope you enjoyed seeing how I cut this pattern out of to his jeans thanks
for watching and seizing