hi it's clearly from prefer creations and welcome to my YouTube channel I'm a cellar on
Etsy where I had made a range of questi items you can also find me of
various social media platforms which are linked below in the description I also write a blog
on WordPress which I publish weekly
I'm inspired by the beautiful scenery living in Cornwall and also from a childhood living by
the seaside
previously on this channel I have experimented with time lapses of my three machine embroidery and
I plan to do more of this and but I'm also looking at creating tutorials as
well as potentially reviewing patterns in the future
I plan to post a video fortnightly
thanks for watching and see you soon